Our guys so we have our listings view all set.
But of course it's just static HDMI markup.
We want this.
We want these listings to come from the database and we want to be able to add them through the admin
area.
But before we do that we need to set up a database.
OK so we're going to use post-grads which is a very powerful relational database.
It pairs very well with Django.
If he used my ascii well or even like Microsoft SU all server very similar there they're all SU or relational
databases that use structured query language although with Gengel we don't have to write raw Eskew all
queries we have a higher level Aurum to deal with fetching data inserting data and so on.
All right so it makes it much much easier.
Now as far as installing post-grads locally it's a little different on Windows and Mac.
What I would suggest if you're on Windows is to go to post grad school dot or go to download click on
Windows and download the graphical installer.
OK and just go through that.
I'm using version 10 so that's what I would suggest if you want to use 9.6 That's fine if there's a
later version later stable version.
You can probably get away with that as well.
So it's up to you.
And if you've installed post-grads before you know how to do it.
If you have a different way of doing it by all means you know as long as you have postscripts on your
system then that's that's all we need.
OK so on a Mac I would suggest using post-grads app at post-grads app dot com.
This just makes things a little bit easier or gives you a little interface to work with.
So we're going to go ahead and click download here and this is post-grads app dot com.
And before I actually install this I just want to also mention another tool called PGE admin and this
gives you a graphical user interface to deal with your databases and can be very helpful especially
if you're not that comfortable with the terminal.
If you want to look at your tables and your data stuff like that.
So we'll also get that installed and this is available on Windows and Mac.
OK.
So we're going to go ahead and let's actually download this to.
I'm going to go to download OK if you're on Windows you want to click here but on a Mac so I'm going
to click here.
Latest Version it was.
Yeah that's the latest version.
I'm going to get the DMD on Windows it'll be in Ex-Sea.
All right so now it's let's install postgrads apps so I'm going to open up that file that I downloaded.
All right so I'm just going to break drag this post-grads over to my applications folder.
And I have had this installed on this machine before so there might be some very subtle differences
than what you see but I'll explain that.
All right.
So once that's in the Applications folder if nothing happens just open it up from within the Applications
folder or so ago and DoubleClick postgrads can close this up and it should just ask us if we want to
open it.
So I'll go ahead and click open and there we go.
Now you probably if you haven't installed this before you probably won't see these three databases here
and you'll probably see something that says initialize.
So just go ahead and click that initialize and then you should see these.
OK and this is your server settings which includes your port number the default post-grads port data
directory config file if you want to you know edit any of those or whatever you can go into there.
So what I'm going to do now is double click on postgrads and it's going to open up a terminal with you
know inside of our post-crash show.
So we need to create a new database.
Now as far as users I'm going to use this the post-grads user.
OK you always have this route post-grads user.
And I wouldn't use this in deployment but on development I think it's fine to use so we're just going
to use that but we want to give the post-grad user a password.
So what we want to do is backslash password and then the user name which is post-grads OK and then we
just want to enter a password.
Now we want to create a new database so we're going to say create a database and I'm going to call this
a b t r d d and I'm just going to do owner.
I'm going to specify that the owner should be the post-grads user.
OK and then we want to put a semi-colon at the end and run that and we get create the database.
OK now if we do a backslash L which is a list database's you'll see VTR DBI and the owner of post-grads.
OK so we should be good with that.
Now we can exit this by doing a backslash Q And now for PGE admen let's let's take care of that so we're
going to go ahead and close this up.
So just remember we have a database of Beati Ari D.B and the owners postgrads.
So now we're going to just keep this running.
We can close this up but it's still running you should actually see a little elephant icon in your top
right if you're on a Mac.
So for PGE admen see where is it.
Let's open that up
and we'll just agree OK so what we want to do is we want to move this.
I mean we can run it from here but I'm going to move it to my Applications folder.
So I'm going to just open a new Finder and go to my applications which is right here.
OK I'll bring that over
because if you run up from here and then you add in you ejected.
It's not going to run anymore it's going to be it's not going to be available.
All right so now that is in our applications it's close this up and let's run P.G. for RPG Augen for
you and we'll get this message you just want to say open.
It's going to start the program this should also create a little icon up in the top right.
And now this is going to run in the browser.
OK it's a browser based tool.
And over here on the left under servers you see that there's nothing here.
Now I believe on Windows if you if you install postgrads and then you install PGE admin and you open
it up you'll see your it'll just kind of create a server with your current databases and if you want
you can create the database that we just created the Tiare D-B from here.
OK because you can create databases from here if nothing is here then just simply say create server
and give it a name I'm going to call mine DBI server and go to a connection and you want to specify
that this is local your local hose connection and then your username postgrads and whatever password
you used for post-grads which we just did in the terminal.
So let's say save now for go to D-B server on our databases you'll see our BT are the D-B database along
with the other two.
The default database is but this is the one that we're going to be using.
Ok so I think everything should be configured correctly.
Let me just check out the properties here so why is that.
Given this just a spellcheck thing.
I'm the owner of postgrads so definition security
now.
I think we might have to add privileges here let's say
when we use say post-grads privileges.
OK so we probably want to do this or we might get some restrictions so we're going to choose the post-grads
user and say all and that should be good Granter postgrads.
I'm not sure if we need to do this since we're using the post-grads user but I'm just going to do it
anyways and just say save.
All right so we should be all set.
Now guys in the next video we're going to start to configure Django to use postgrads because right now
it's configured to use Eskew light.
So we're going to do that and then we'll move on to migrations and we'll start really getting into like
our models and stuff like that.
All right so see you in the next video.