All right guys.
Now that we have post-grads installed we're going to start to implement it with our Django app.
OK.
Now to use post-grads we need to define the parameters in the settings file but we also need to install
a couple of packages using Pipp so that it can basically like basically like drivers to connect to post-grads
so make sure you're in your V or whatever you call your virtual environment and let's do a pip install
and we're going to do it's.
P.S. Why CEO PGE to say we want to install that.
And then we also want to do that same thing but Dasch binary.
OK so we want to install those two back.
Is it clear the up.
And then we're going to go to settings up high and go down to look.
So let me make this smaller.
We're going to go down to where it says database our databases.
And this is where we want to set up all of our parameters including the driver including the username
password.
Things like that.
So first of all we want to change this Eskdale life 3 to postgrads.
Q Well
and then for the name we're going to get rid of this and we just want to put what we called our database
which was B T R E D V K.
And we also want to add the user which in my case uses postgrads and then we want the password OK.
So my password.
I just use 1 through 6 and then we also want to add the host which is going to be our local host OK.
So let's save that.
And by the way my my my jingoes server is still running if I go to my other tab here you know see my
jingoes service still running.
Now as far as this message right here and you guys saw this a long time ago when we first started the
server basically we have some on applied migrations and a migration is a file that that tells the database
what to do.
Basically as far as setting up tables and data columns and data types of each each for each column and
stuff like that.
And Django has default migrations for things like the admin area for authentication.
There's going to be users that have to do with the admin area that that stuff is all set up.
Those migration files are set up.
They just haven't been run and put into the database.
So what we want to do now is basically run those migrations.
And once we do that we won't see this error anymore so let's go ahead and just I'm going to just stop
the server here I'll stop this and clear it up now to basically to migrate.
We're going to create our own migrations for like the listings and the realtors and stuff like that.
But to run the current migrations that are already ready like those 15 that were in that message we
just want to say Python manage dot PI and then migrate.
OK now something isn't right with our database we're going to see an error here.
So let's just try it out.
OK it looks like everything went OK.
OK.
So now we can I mean you could jump into your terminal if you want or you can jump into PGE admin and
reload.
And let's take a look under servers D-B server.
When you look under databases BTR VDB schemas public tables and look at that.
Look at all these tables that have been created.
So we have our off user table.
We have user groups even our migrations get tracked in the database they have their own table groups
permissions.
All of this Django stuff is now in the tables.
Ok that's exactly what we want.
So so we know that post-grads is now is now interacting with our Gengel application which is perfect.
All right so let's hop back into this code and let's start our server back up.
So I'm going to do Python managed up-I run server and now notice we don't see those red arrows anymore.
OK because those migrations have now been applied.
So we're now in a great place because we can now start to create our models.
Our database is connected and we can start to create our own migration so that we can create tables
for listings and realtors and stuff like that.
All right.
So we'll get started on that in the next video.