All right guys so before we actually jump in to code it's always a good idea to map out your your database
schema OK before you do that because you want to know exactly what you're doing exactly what fields
you're putting into your models.
So usually the way that you figure this out is by looking at the requirements what what needs to be
displayed on this in this application and this Web site.
So I have the initial requirements here and then they have a text file called schemas dot taxed and
we're just going to map out our scheme and now if you want to use more advanced software where you can
have a little diagram with boxes that are connected and stuff like that you can do that.
I just want to keep it simple.
So in this file it's a model slash D.B fields.
OK.
So basically we're going to have three separate tables for what we need and one table is going to be
listings or I'll just call it listing because the model name will be singular so I'll say listing let's
say realtor and let's say contact.
OK so basically listings are the property listings of the realtors and then contact is any inquiry that's
made to the application should be saved in the database in a table and a contact table.
So let's start off by figuring out what fields the listing listings will have.
OK now if we go down to the bottom here we have a listing page field so this is basically what they
want displayed on the single listing page.
So let's start off with just putting in an ID because of course every every table needs to have an ID
column.
And with postgrads the way that things are set up.
It's that ID will get put in automatically and it will also be auto increment.
So we don't have to worry about putting in the ID when we insert data.
So an ID is going to be of the data type of event.
All right.
Now we also want to connect connect realtors to listings.
OK because each realtor is assigned a group of listings.
So when we go to like let's say 45 main street there should be a realtor that's in charge of 45 Main
Street.
So that means that we have to have a realtor field OK and it's going to be an integer but it's going
to be a foreign key fields.
And when I say foreign key from the realtor table the realtor model.
All right.
That way we can associate an entire realtor and all of their fields with a listing.
So that way like if we wanted to display in their image or their name or their contact info in a listing
page we could do that because we have an entire realtor connected to the listing.
So next thing we'll need is a title as you can see in the document so let's say title titles are going
to be a string.
Put a call in here.
OK.
So we have title we have address.
In most cases the title will be the address but they'll have the option for it not to be.
Also you can see where they want the whole address so will also need a city to be a string will need
a state string and do zip code
OK.
So that's the address.
We also want a description which is actually not here is it.
It's actually not in the.
The initial requirements I may add it so you may see it but it's not here.
But we know that we do need a description OK and that's going to be a string actually that's going to
be a text field which is a little different because it's going to be longer so we also want price.
OK.
Price is going to be in and.
It's not going to be a float because there's not going to be any like there's not going be any decimal
points.
I can do sense on prices of homes.
So an inch is just fine.
Let's see.
We also want bedrooms in bathrooms so bedroom bedrooms is going to be in it's just a number of bedrooms
same thing with bathrooms
OK so let's see what else we want at garage.
Garage is going to be an inside number a garage.
It will do zero as the default.
Let's see we also want a list.
So instead of a list underscore a date that's going to be of the type of day.
So real her name and image this is going to come from this foreign key right here.
So we'll be able to get anything about the realtor by use by forming that relationship.
We also need the square feet in lot size.
What about that so it's here we'll say Eskew.
That's going to be in and out and then a lot size.
So lot size is actually going to be a float because I want to be able to do say like 1.2 acres or 2.3
acres or something like that.
So we'll save float for a lot size.
It would seem so for images.
We basically want to have one main image and then it says five other images but I want to do six.
So we're going to do.
We're going to do a photo underscore main which will be strong and just to be clear we're not actually
storing images in a database.
We're storing the location of the image.
That way we can fetch that location and we can simply put it into an image source so that it displays
on the page.
OK so we'll have the main image and then we'll have photo underscore one.
And then we'll have one through six so I'm just going to copy that two three four five six and we'll
just go ahead and change these up.
So 1:36 and that should do it for our listings case.
These are all the fields that we're going to need in the listing model and these will all get created
as rows in the listings table in the database.
So now let's let's do the realtor.
So for realtor we're going to have an ID.
OK all all tables will have an ID that will be in and we're also going to want the realtor's name so
it's do string and for name it's just it's going to be first and last name I don't want to have them
separate fields.
Also photo there should be one photo of the Realtor also a description.
So just like a short description let's say text for that.
And let's see we're going to want a and email a phone
now remember that number they want the option to do a seller of the month.
So we need a field for that which will be a boolean.
That reminds me of something I've forgotten the listings as well which I'll get to but I'm going to
call this is MVP something short list is MVP and then that will be a boolean.
All right.
Now what I forgot up here in the listings is remember they also want the option to publish an unpublished
listings.
So we need to add that as a field as well.
So let's go Ray here and say is underscore published.
OK.
And that's going to be a boolean.
And then in brackets here let's put the default so we want the default to be true which should be published
by default.
All right.
Also garage.
I want to have a default of 0 and then for the MVP of course you want a default of 0
and the last thing we want for realtor is the higher date.
OK so that's going to be a day.
So it's just the date they were hired.
All right.
So I'm going to just save this so far.
And now we just have the contacts came in contacts are just like the inquiries that are sent in.
So each one will have an ID when we just move this up.
So we will have an ID.
Also we want to know which user are sent in that inquiry if the users are registered and logged in.
So let's say a user underscore ID and that will be an event.
And we also want to know the listing.
And and I'm also going to do the listing I.D. So the listing is actually going to be connected to the
title or the name of the listing and then the ID will obviously be the ID.
OK we also want a name should be string will be the name of the person that's sending in the inquiry
we want their email phone
and a message
and then we also want a contact date which should be a date and that's it.
That's our entire schema.
So when we create our models and Django we want to model it after this file and after all these fields.
OK.
So that's all I want to do in this video guys in the next one will start to actually create the models.
All right so I'll see that.