Art guys so in the last video we mapped out our schemas for listings realtors and contacts or inquiries.
Now we're going to actually create some models.
I want to create our listing model and then we'll create our realtor model and then we'll run a migration
that will create the tables in our database based on those models.
So this is actually a Jingo documentation link where you can see up here and this is from model field
reference so when we set up our fields we need to basically give them certain types OK as you can see
over here on the right have field types and there's a whole bunch.
We're definitely not going to use all of these but just notice we have like a date field char field
is for like just that's that's going to be the most common one we use for like the title The address
the city the those will be char fields.
OK.
Date date time field email field file field for files and then you also have Image image fields for
files that are specifically images integer fields.
We have text fields for longer text you are el fields so if you want to check out the documentation
and actually look into this it's there's a lot of information here.
OK so let's jump in to vs code and we're going to go into our listings app OK so our listings folder
and let's open up models dot PI every time you create an app.
It's going to create a model's dot PI file.
So I'm going to just get rid of this and the way that we define a model is with a class.
So we want to call it class and it should be the singular version of the app.
So in this case listing and then we want to pass in here models with one m models Daut and then upper
case M model.
So basically we're extending the core model which gives us a whole bunch of stuff to work with.
OK and then we just want to define that class.
And then within that we create all of our properties.
So the first one we're going to create is the realtor.
And this is going to be the I guess the most difficult one because this is going to be part of another
table so it's going to be the foreign key of another table so that we can form a relationship between
realtors and listings.
So we're going to set this to models Daut foreign key and this is going to take in the name of the other
model that we're relating which is going to be realtor.
Okay.
And then it takes a second parameter of what to do when you delete because if you think about it if
you have a realtor attached to a listing and you delete the realtor What do you want to happen to the
listing should the listing delete too.
In some cases you may want it to.
I don't so I'm going to actually set this equal to models Daut do nothing.
OK so that will just that that we'll just leave it and leave the listing alone even if I delete the
realtor that's associated with it.
All right so next thing is going to be the title and this is going to be said to models dot.
And remember I showed you all the different fields that are available.
We're going to use char fields for this which is just a basic text.
Excuse me basic textfield.
And this takes in a max length and this can be whatever you want.
I'm just going to say 200 days should be longer than 200.
And then let's copy this down.
Let's actually just copy a bunch down.
OK.
So after title let's do the address.
And most of the most of the time the address and title are going to be the same just because that's
the way that I want to format it.
But you could have a different title than the address for the I guess I'll leave that at 200 as well.
OK.
So the next field is going to be the city because the address is just the the is just the street address
it doesn't include the city or anything.
So we want city we also want state and we want zip code and zip code.
I'm actually going to set to just 20 state state to 100 city to 100.
And then after zip code we're gonna do description
and description is going to be a little longer.
So or can be a little longer so we want to do textfield.
OK we don't need a max length with textfield.
Also I want to pass in blank blank equals.
True.
And what this means is that this field is optional.
OK so it's not if we're in the admin area we're creating a listing and we don't put a description and
we won't get an error if we don't put this in here then it's going to look at it as required and it's
going to give us an error.
OK.
I want all this other stuff to be required.
So next thing is going to be price and price.
As far as the type is going to be in integer field guys who want to do in your field for the price we
don't need any the parameters you don't need a max length or anything.
Actually you know what I'm going to just get rid of these because then I don't want to just keep like
deleting max length.
Next thing is going to be bedrooms
so bedrooms is also going to be an integer field.
So models dot
integer field.
Let's see if we also one bathroom's.
Now this is something that I haven't mentioned yet.
Firms actually want this to be a decimal field.
And the reason for that is because you can have you know one and a half bathrooms or two and a half
bathrooms and I want to be able to do like 1.5 2.5 and so on.
So we're actually going to set this two models dot decimal field and then we can pat we can format this
a little bit we can pass in Max digits and I want it to be two.
OK so the the actual first number should be no longer than 2 digits.
I mean I don't think we have any houses with 100 bathrooms and then decimal places.
We can also assign and I just want one decimal place so like 1.5 2.5 and so on we don't want 1.5 0 or
anything like that.
OK so that's the bathrooms.
Next is the garage.
OK so garage is going to be models Daut integer field as well except we want we want this to have a
default value of 0.
OK so the way that we can do that is just say default equals zero.
So you can see how easy it is to set up our database using a model rather than going into like the post-grads
shell or even something like PGE admen and doing all this you know manually.
So next thing is square feet we're going to do Eskew F for that and Lynsay models.
Square feet is just going to be a regular integer field and we want lot size.
So a lot underscore size lot size is going to be a decimal field as well for that for Max digits let's
do lots as well do 5 max digits and then decimal places.
Is going to be one K because it's just going to be Acre's like we'll do whatever 2.4 acres and stuff
like that.
All right so now we want to get we wondering do the photos now in the schema that we created in the
last video I said it was a string.
But that's that's in the actual database with with Django.
We have different types of fields like we have an image field so that's what we want to use for the
photos or the images.
But in the database itself it'll be a string.
So let's say photo underscore main and let's see a photo underscore main and then we want to do models
Daut image field.
OK.
Now here is where we wanted to we want to define where the where are these get uploaded to.
Now there's something called a media folder in Django and we're going to set that up in anything that
we upload as far as images or files in the admin area is going to go into that media folder.
But what we want to do here is define the folder that we want inside of that media folder so we want
to say upload underscore too and you'll see all this in the documentation if you want to look further
into this stuff.
We're going to say upload to and let's call the full photos.
Now we could leave it like that but I want each photo to go into a folder structure of the date.
So basically like the year the month in the day and you'll see what I mean once we actually upload a
file but the way that we do this is we use the date format of percent uppercase y for year.
Percent lower case M for the month and then percent lower case D for the day and then slash.
So that's the this is the location inside the media folder that this this field should go to this image
should go to.
All right.
We want to do the same for the rest of the images.
Remember this should be 6 6 other images and those will be the little thumbnails that have that open
with the light box.
So I'm actually going to say one two three four five six and we're going to just change the name of
these two.
This will be photo one photo to three for five and six.
All right.
And then I want the same file structure here but I want all six of these images to be optional.
OK the main one is the only one that you actually need you don't have to have six other images.
So what we need to do is just add another parameter here of just like we did above.
Blank equals true.
OK.
That will make it optional so I'm just going to copy this and then we'll put that for all of these.
That way it's not going to complain if we don't upload all six photos.
OK so now the photos are taken care of what's put on is published OK so we want is published and this
is going to be a boolean.
So we want models Daut Boolean field and then we can set a default.
OK we want that default to be true.
We also want a list.
OK so list day are in the same models Daut and this we're going to use a date time field and then we're
going to set a default.
OK now the default.
I want to be the current date and time.
So in order to do this we need to bring in the date time package from Python so we're going to say from
date time import date time and then the default will actually take that date time and we'll say it now
which is a property that will give us the current date and time.
OK.
But this I'm also going to set two blank rules.
True.
All right.
And then that should be it.
As far as fields.
Now with arm with our admin area when we have I mean I haven't even showed you the admin area because
we have no models yet to really show you anything but we're going to have a table that's going to display
each listing.
And we need to pick a field to be kind of the main field to be displayed.
And what I would suggest here is the title to be the main field to display.
So what we need to do is we need to go down here on the same level no tab here just do a def and then
we want to do a double underscore.
TR double underscore and then self ok and one indent here and then we just want to return self Daut.
Whatever.
Whatever the main field we want to display and that's going to be the title.
OK so make sure you do that and that's it will save this file.
And that's our model.
Now we're getting in error right here because this realtor actually needs to be brought in from the
realtor model.
So up here the top let's say from realtors.
OK we can just access any other app we want by just saying the name of it and then we can get its models
by saying realtors dot models and then we want to import the name of the model which is realtor.
K we haven't created it yet but we will.
So let's save that and you can see it's giving us an error because there is no real term yet.
We have to create that.
And that's what we're going to do in the next video.