All right guys.
The last video we created our listing model inside models got pie in the listings.
Now we need to create our realtor model K because these are going to go hand in hand we have a foreign
key of Realtor that's going to be linked to that that realtor models so let's go into the folder of
Realtors and then open that model's pie and we're going to same thing create a class and we're going
to call it realtor.
And we also want to extend models our models Daut model.
And then we want to create our properties member ID we don't have to do that's going to be automatic.
Let's do a name.
We're going to set that two models Daut.
It's going to be a character field.
We'll give it a max length of let's say 200 K let's do a photo.
OK so each realtor should have one photo.
So models dot image field and just like we did before in the last video we're going to do upload underscore
to and let's set this to the same things it's going to go into photos slash.
And we want to do.
Percent.
Why slash percent.
Lower case and slash percent.
Lower case D.
Slash.
OK.
Next thing is the description description is going to be models dot textfield and I want this to be
optional so we're going to say blank equals true.
Next thing is the phone
so phone is going to be a char field will do max length.
He calls say 20.
OK.
Next is going to be the email I'm going to do 50 for the e-mail
Next is going to be is MVP.
So this is this will be checked off if they're going to be the seller of the month.
This is going to be a boolean field case a Boolean field.
And we also want to set a default OK.
Default is going to be false.
All right let's see let's do hire date.
So hire date models dot date time field.
And just like we did in the other model I want the current date and time so we need to actually bring
in.
We'll say from the time imports date time and then we can simply say default equals date time Daut now.
And I'm also going to do a blank equals true here.
All right.
And then just like we did with the listings we want to have like a main field for the realtor and I'm
going to use their name so let's say I define double underscore as to your double underscore pasand
self.
And we're going to say return
self Daut and then whatever field we want which is going to be name.
All right so let's save that.
So we now created our realtor model now this error we have here if I just resave this that now goes
away because realtor now exists in the realtors models.
OK.
So we just created so now that we have the realtors and the listings models done.
Now we want to get the stuff into the database right now it's not in the database if we if we look even
though we've saved the model it's go ahead and reload and it's kind of a pain because you get to navigate
back down but I just want to prove to you that just because we created the models it doesn't mean that
those tables are created you'll see there's no new tables for listings or realtors so we need to create
a migration or make a migration and then run it.
OK.
So let's head over to vs code and I'm just going to make this make this a little bigger here and let's
see say we want to run Python
manage dot PI and there's a command called Make migrations.
All right.
Now this make migrations is going to actually create a file.
This this itself is not going to do anything in the database.
It's simply good to create the file that we can run to then update the database and notice that in the
listings folder there's a migration folder which is empty aside from cache pie cache.
Same thing with realtors has migrations.
So what this will do is create a file that will get set that will get put in there based on the model.
So if I run this OK.
So the reason that we're getting this error is because in order to use image field which we've used
plenty of times here we need to have a dependency called pillow case that we need to install with Pip.
So to fix this we simply run make sure you're in your virtual environment and run Pipp install pelo.
All right so now that we've done that let's do the make migrations again and notice that it's not only
did it do listings.
Now we could have done.
And I actually meant to do make migrations listings but it doesn't matter is since Realtors is a foreign
key on listings they both would have ran.
OK but if we do make migrations it'll just run all of them.
OK both of them.
And it's created a file called 0 0 1 underscore initial dot pi.
Inside both migrations folders.
OK.
Now if we take a look at these files this is what migrations look like.
And they include this.
This operations lists with migrations daquiri model has a name and then it has all the fields OK.
So this is basically what's going to be read into the database.
Now there's actually a command that we can run to check out what the query would look like.
So if we do or what it will look like we'll say Python managed dot PI and we can actually do this isn't
something you have to do.
I'm just showing you it's an option we can say Eskew Well migrates listings.
So we'll say listings and then the number of the file which is 0 0 0 or 1 and it will actually show
us the rescue well so create table and soon to be called listings underscore listings because it's the
name of the app underscore the name of the model.
And then you can see it gives it an ID serial which means it's going to be auto increment in postgrads
we have something called serial titles going to be var char char as did the actual post-grads type.
OK we have char field which is the model type.
The Django modeled type of the field.
But this is the actual database field.
OK.
So you can see the actual rescue Allen didn't run this it didn't do anything it's just simply showing
us what it will what it will do.
OK so don't think that you have to run that command.
So let's clear this up and now it's actually do the migrate.
So whenever we have migrations up and up and ready we can simply do Python manage dot PI and then migrate
when we get to OK's from realtors enlisting.
So now that that specific command actually changed the database added the table so let's take a look
let's go to PGE admin or you can open your terminal you or you'll have to reload this and then just
navigate back down to it.
So be Tiare the scheme is public tables and there are listings underscore listing and realtors underscore
realtor.
OK so our tables are now there and if we look at it I mean we can look at the we could look at the data.
There is no data but we can say like all rows and it would show us all the data that's in there.
OK but you can see we have the ID which is the primary key title address city all the different fields.
So pretty cool.
All right.
So our database is all set.
The next thing we're going to do is work on our admin area.
Now that we have the database tables in place we want to make it so that we can actually add data you
know Update Delete whatever so that's what we're going to get into in the next section.