All right you guys know that we have our we have a models created we did our migrations our database
tables are created for the listings and for the realtors.
Now we're going to start to work with the admin area which in my opinion is one of the greatest features
of Django especially if you're a freelancer or someone that works by itself or just maybe maybe with
just a couple other people you don't have this big giant team where they can create a custom admin area.
It just gives you that right off the bat.
OK and you can customize it as you see fit.
So if you make sure you have your server running and if you just go to local host 8000 thousand slash
admin it'll bring you right there.
Hey it's been here all along.
Now we don't currently have a way to log in so what we need to do is head over to our terminal and I
am using my via's code terminal and we need to create a super user if we do Python manage Daut PI health
and take a look at let's see up at the top here I believe under.
Off you see we have a create super user command.
OK so that's what we want to use.
So let's go ahead and run that it will say Python managed or pi create super user.
So for a user name I'm going to use one.
When am I going to use this.
I'll just use Bradd but you could use whatever you want.
So email address.
I'm going to say Brad at gmail dot com which isn't a real email address but I'm going to use it.
And then your password.
So for my password I'm just going to use 1 2 3 4 5 6 1 2 3 4 5 6 OK so it gives me just a message saying
that my password sucks should it.
Should we bypass the validation anyway.
And I'm just going to say yes.
All right so now we have a super user so it's clear this out.
And let's go back to the Adwan area and I'm going to put in Brad.
And of course use whatever you put whatever you used and put in my sucky password and log in.
And there we go so now we are actually in the the administrator area now from here without doing anything
at all we can manage our users in groups we can assign groups and Django case we can add groups with
different permissions.
We can also create and manage users So here's our Bradd user and notice that there is a staff status.
So this is basically this just means that this user is an admin and they can actually log into this
area because a lot of times you'll have users that can log in to the front end of your web site.
But you obviously don't want them to have access to this area.
This is for staff only.
OK so that's that's where is it right here.
So Staff Status.
So you check if I uncheck this this user will not be able to log in here.
OK.
So that's that.
Now obviously we want to be able to to to add listings.
We want to be able to add realtors and stuff like that.
So in order for that to happen we need to go to our code and let's go to listings.
OK first we'll go to the listings folder and we want to go to admen pi.
OK so this is basically where we can customize admin stuff for the for the listings app.
And I want to register register the listing for the admin areas so we need to do that here.
Is register your models.
So I'm going to say first of all bring in my model so from dog models I want to inport listing gay and
amusing listing because in my models that's what I call it.
So whatever you have here is what you want to have here.
And then let's see to register it we can say admin Daut site dot register and then we want to pass in
the name of the model which is listing.
And we also want to pass in than actually let's just do that for now.
I think that that will actually work.
Let's save it.
Let's go back to our admen area and reload and there we go we get listings.
OK.
So if I click on listings we don't have any at the moment but they would be listed here and we can add
them notice that we have all of the fields that we added.
Even realtor so we can choose a realtor title address city state zip.
These are all text.
What was it were they called Char fields.
This is a text field.
The price is is an ENT.
So we can also use these arrows just in h t Moul number field and then bedrooms bathrooms can be decimal.
Garage isn't into square feet in lot size is also a decimal.
For some reason the decimal places they give you a longer input.
Well I guess that would make sense because you may have a lot of decimal points that we have photo main.
Notice that these are dark and these are not that's because the required fields are dark.
And remember we made these optional.
So that's why they're not dark or bold like that.
And then is published is a checkbox and by default it's going to be checked because we set the default
to true in the listing date is going to be the current date and time but you can easily change it with
the date picker.
OK and then the time picker.
So this is just amazing functionality to have right out of the box like for us to create this interface
would have would have taken just oh I don't know how long but a long time.
So that's why Django is just an incredible framework especially for freelancers.
So I think what I want to do now before we start adding data is also add the realtors in the in the
admin area.
So to do that we're going to do the same thing we're going to go back to the US Code and let's just
copy these two lines here and go to realtors admin dot tie in pieces and Except we're going to change
this to a realtor and we want to register the model of Realtor.
So I save that we go back and we reload.
Now we can see realtors if I say add realtor we get the name the photo description phone.
Email is MVP.
So that's for the seller of the month.
And it's not checked by default because we set false to be the default value.
And then the higher date which of course we can change if we want.
All right so now we have realtors and listings as part of our admin area and another thing you can do
is over here you can view the site you can change your password so whatever user you logged in as you
can change password you can log out and we're going to customize this pretty nicely like we're going
to obviously Gengel administration we don't want that you're not going to want to give this to a client
with that.
We're going to actually put their logo here and we're going to change the colors to their branding colors
so it matches the front end and then we have a lot of customization to do for how the data is displayed.
Right now you can't really see it because we haven't added anything.
But once we add a listing you'll see it's going to look a little funny.
We're going to want to really specify what we want to show like in the table and so on.
All right.
So we're going to do all that.
But before we get into customisation I just want to add some data.
OK so in the next video we're going to go ahead and add at our realtor's upload the images all that
stuff and also add our listings.
All right and then we can work on customizing this admin area.