All right guys so we're going to be adding some data here just to work with.
I and I would suggest that you follow along and you add these realtors and these listings and stuff
just so we're all on the same page.
But before we do that we just need to define some stuff for the media folder where the photos will get
uploaded.
So I'm going to go into VS code closes up and I want to open up my settings files so be Tiare settings.
PI.
We're gonna go down to the very bottom here and we need to set some stuff just like we did with the
static files.
So I'm going to go right here and I'm going to say put a comment and say media or media folder settings
and we want to define a media underscore route.
OK so I want this to be just in the root folder called media.
So we're just like we did before OS stock path dot join.
OK we want to pass in our base underscore Diyar base directory and then a folder called media.
All right and then we just want to set our media underscore you are l and set that to media K or slash
media slash just like we did with the static.
All right let's save that now.
One other thing we have to do in order for our images to show up is we have to go to our core BT houri
folder here you are housed up high.
So the main you are Elle's dot pie and we just want to add onto this.
We want to say plus static.
And then we want to pass in here settings Daut and then media underscore you Arel which we just defined.
And then a second parameter of document is that right you document underscore Roueche and we want to
set that to settings so our settings file and then media underscore route.
Okay so these are things that we just defined if we don't do that.
The that's not that things aren't going to show up correctly.
Now we're getting an error here because it doesn't know what static is.
We actually have to bring that in.
We also have to bring in settings.
So right above here is we'll go right here we'll say from Django.
It's going to be Django dot com.
We want to in port settings.
Okay.
And then we also want to bring in I want to say from jingo dot com dot.
You are Elle's dot static.
We want to import static.
All right so if I save that now those errors go away.
Okay.
So just a little something that you need to do for the media files to show up in the front end but you
know we're not we're not even dealing with looking at the front end yet are showing listings or anything
we're just dealing with the admin area.
But I wanted to get this over with.
All right.
So make sure we do that let's close that up and let's go back to our admen area.
All right now first thing I want to do is add some realtors So let's go to realtors ad realtor and we're
going to add Kayal Brown and we're going to go ahead and choose his image which is going to be on my
desktop.
It's going to be in your resources images realtors and Kayal.
OK.
For a description I'm just going to go to Lipps some lips some dot com and just generate some dummy
text here.
So I will say generate larm some mental just grab like like up to here.
OK we'll go back paste that in.
And then phone I'm going to say let's do 5 5 5 5 5 5 5 5 and then e-mail.
Let's do Kayal at the T.
Real estate dot co.
And then hire day.
I'm just going to say this is a fairly new company.
Well so he was hired in like 2017 and then we'll save.
OK so now we have Kyle Brown.
Now one thing I want to mention is the reason we're seeing his name like this under realtor is because
of when we were creating the model for realtor we added this right here.
OK.
Otherwise he would say like realtor object 1 or something weird like that.
So that's why this is this is pretty important to have here and it's like that in other places as well
like on the listings page when we choose a realtor.
Let me just show you real quick if you go to listings and we add a listing it has his name it wouldn't
be like that if we didn't have if we didn't add that that function.
So just keep that in mind.
So let's go back to realtors and let's add the other two.
So let's say who else did we have we have Mark.
So I think it was Mark
what was his name.
It was his last name.
You know what.
Let's I'm just going to open up the theme real quick.
So desktop that's the theme.
And Destino Let's go to the About page.
OK.
So this is just the static aged him out.
Mark Hudson That's right.
All right.
So go back here and say Mark Hudson description I'm just going to grab that same block of text and phone
number let's 2 4 4 4
and IMAO will saying Mark say Mark at P-T real estate dot co.
And as for hire date let's say and say Mark is fairly new and will save.
OK.
So the last one is going to be Jenny Johnson.
Grab her picture.
OK paste in the same text to get a copy.
Again and then phone number will be off threes and e-mails is going to be Jenee at BT real estate CO.
That's it.
Let's let's make her hired a
say she's been there for a while since it started so now we want to add some listings so let's go to
listings.
We can actually just click add right here OK we'll choose.
Let's take a look at the theme.
These are just the theme files and let's add 45.
Dr would circle k and Norwood's.
So let's choose Kayal Kyle I'll say 45.
Dr. words circle.
So that's going to be the title.
It's also going to be the address.
All right.
And that's going to be in Norwood mass and zip code.
So actually put like the real zip code 0 2 0 6 2 0 6 2.
Just want to make it look like as legit as possible you know the description doesn't really matter.
We'll just grab the first paragraph here and put that in the price.
Let's see the price will say four ninety four ninety one two three four and 90000 bedrooms.
Let's do three bathrooms will say two garage C C two and kind of a double garage so we'll do two square
feet.
Say like 3 2 9 8 doesn't have to be exact to the theme.
Lot size it say it's like two point three acres.
We'll choose a main photo.
So I'm going to go to see images homes.
I'm going to choose home one.
All right so that's the main image for the next photo one.
I'm going to choose home inside one.
OK.
This particular listing.
I'll I'll have all six images but they're not.
You don't need to that should be home inside too.
I mean just see home inside to see home inside.
Three four.
And just imagine if you had to program this all yourself it would just take so so much more time
on our go.
6 So is published we want that checked list date is good and that should do it.
Let's save.
OK so we have our listing now later on I'm going to show you how to customize it so we can show other
fields here as well not just the one list not just the name but yeah again this is this is showing because
of that that little function we added at the end in the model if it was in it would just say like listing
object 1 or something.
So let's add some other stuff some other listings.
So we have 18 Jefferson lane by Mark a Jefferson lane and we use that as the address.
I know this is kind of tedious and boring but I want this to look like a legit site.
So it's the Woburn Mass 0 1 8 0 1 0 1 8 0 0 1 that's a Newburn.
And if you guys want to do different information you can
grab description.
OK so price on this one and these prices might not be.
I mean this is Massachusetts this would be way higher but it doesn't matter.
It's a five fifty one two three.
So bedroom's let's say four bedrooms and two point five bathrooms garage.
There is a little garage so say 1 square feet I'm going to do 3 1 0 0.
What size will say 1.5.
And then let's choose our photos.
So I want home to for this one.
And let's just let's choose a couple of the SAW do home one
ups here.
These should be inside home inside one home inside too.
And let's do home inside three so we'll pretend we only have three for this and then everything else
is good so let's save that good let's add another one.
So this one let's see we have 187 Woodrow street.
So say this is by Jenny Johnson
K title address same let's say Salem Mass.
It is on line 1 5 1 9 1 5 let's grab the text for the description price say 580
these are very low these areas and let's see we'll do square feet what bedrooms three bathrooms three
garage one square feet thirty four lot size.
We'll just do one Agere photo let's do home three let's do photo.
And if you want to just eat them you have to watch the rest of this video if you just want to add the
rest of these homes.
That's fine.
Let's see if we get home inside one let's do home inside to home.
Inside three will do for home inside for OK save.
And another one we have see 28 Giffard street in Bedford New Hampshire.
So this will be Mark's
different street.
It's bad for Stu and H.
New Hampshire and zip code
0 3 1 0 3.
A price is 380.
So a little cheaper in New Hampshire and bedroom's let's do three.
I know this is an exact to the theme but that's ok.
Garage.
It's a two garages square feet.
Let's do a little smaller mostly twenty nine hundred lot size bigger lot size we'll do like 4.5.
And then the photo is going to be what home for I believe right before it's due home inside one.
Let's just say that this one has two images.
OK so we'll save that good almost there.
I know this is really tedious.
So next one is 12 United road in Southampton.
We'll give this one to Kyle.
12 road
and it's going to be so 10
Hampshire and 0 0 3 2 7 3 2 7 description
you can see prices to 30
say let's do three bedrooms and let's do one point five one and half bathrooms garage is one square
feet let's do 1980.
Lot size three point two this is going to be home of home five is right here.
Photo on and two and three.
All right one more which is 33 circle in Lexington will do will do.
Kyle again he's going to be cellar of the month.
So what was it 3 3 6 circle
Lexington and state is mass zip code 0 1 7 3 1.
And then let's see let's get the description
and then the price is.
This is going to be the most expensive one this is 780 bedrooms let's say five bathrooms will say for
garage.
One square feet let's do 5 0 2 3.
Lot size do 1.7.
And this is going to be home six
just choose the insides and you don't you don't have to match exactly what I do.
Five and six.
All right.
And we'll save.
There he goes.
Now we have to change this.
And just to show you we can update this very easily.
Just a circle
and go out and save.
Also when we choose a realtor here if we wanted to add one we could do that from here too which just
opens up.
If you guys can't see that it just opens up another little window here and we can add a realtor which
is pretty cool.
We can also delete realtors.
We can change the selected realtors So it's it's pretty cool.
It's pretty intuitive for just a standard built in system.
All right.
Now that we have all all of these listings in the next video I want to look at customizing this a little
bit because I want some more information in the table here.
Also I want to add some filtering options so we could for instance filter by realtor or whatever other
fields that we want just customize it a little bit.
Also notice over here we have recent actions so every time we add like a realtor or a listing or whatever
it shows right here which is kind of cool.
Now one more quick thing I know this video is getting really long but when we uploaded those images
let's take a look at our file structure now when to close everything out.
And we now have a media folder that wasn't there before it was created on its own because we sat in
the settings media route to this folder and if we look inside we have a folder called photos because
that's where we said the uploaded to photos and then remember the date format we did.
So what it does is it creates a year and it creates a month OK whatever month it is that that image
is uploaded and then the day and all these images are put inside here.
OK.
So if we upload a listing tomorrow it will get put into 0 9 to 5.
So it just keeps a nice structure to your photos.
OK.
So that's that.
I just want to show you that that's how the media files are being stored.
All right so that's it in the next video will do some customization to the admin area.