All right guys so in the last video we went ahead and added all of our data here to the back end.
But now I want to customize the admin area says a few things I want to do.
I want to add some more fields to these tables.
I want to have some filters and stuff like that.
But before we do that let's change this up here.
Just Django administration.
I don't think anyone is ever going to want that.
There you go.
At least you want your company name or something.
So we're going to add the logo here the logo that they sent us and the resources that we have in our
stack assets.
I also want to change up the colors.
I want the colors to match the front end.
OK so if we go see a view site we want to use this blue this dark blue and this green instead of the
default Jango blue colors.
So that's what we're going to do in this video so let's head over to vs code and first thing we want
to do is go to templates and we want to create a folder called admin OK.
And then inside admin we're going to create a new file called base underscore site HMO.
OK very important that you call it that.
And what we're going to do is extend the admin template and then we can actually change blocks we can
add certain blocks including the branding blocks so at the top here let's do
extends and then we want to do admin slash based on each team.
OK so that's the that's the template we want to extend.
And then we're going to want to use an image we're going to want to use our our logo.
So we want to bring that in from our static assets so we also have to load static and cry now for the
branding or that where it as Django administration we have to put whatever we want to put in there inside
of a block.
And this is going to be called block branding.
OK and then of course you want to end that block
and inside here we're going to put in H-1 with an ID of head and we're going to put in here for now
let's just do Beati
relist real estate.
So if we were to do that let's save and let's take a look reload.
There we go so that it's as easy as that to change the text up here.
But I actually want the logo and I wanted to be the logo and then just say admin area.
So inside this H-1 I'm going to do an image and give it a class of brand underscore I am g.
And for the source it's going to be it's in the static folder.
So we want to put our tags and we want to say static.
It's going to be in the I Am G and it's going to be logo dot P and G.
OK.
All right I'll just put the company name
BT real estate.
OK let's see what else we want to put.
We're going to specify a height width so to say height equals 50 in with equals 80 k that way no matter
how big the image is it will still just format it to look right.
And then after the image of say admin area.
OK so save that let's go back and reload and there we go.
So now we have our little logo and it says addling area said a Gengel administration.
Now for the CSSA if we want to edit that we actually have to add another block down here and we're going
to say block and then it's called Extra style.
OK so an extra style and that has to end.
And then in here we can put a link it's a link.
It's going to go to static
so static and then CSSA slash admin dot CSSA we're going to have to create that file and then I think
that should do it so it's save that.
And let's go to we want to go to be Tiare
and see
radio static success and this create a new file called admin Dotsie.
SS So the first thing I'm going to mess with is the header.
Ok so it has an idea of header.
And the reason that I know that is because I just use the chrome tools here and use the elements selector
and select this and you see it has an idea of header and you can see the the styles down here.
So I want to increase the height a little bit to 50.
And then also change the background to are blue are branding blue and also change the colors to white.
I don't want this yellow color also for the link.
This right here.
These are links in they're yellow I want to change that.
This branding H-1 as well.
So let's head over to our CSSA and let's change the height.
So say height 50 pixels.
Let's change the background to the value of 1 0 2 8 for E which is the dark blue.
And let's change the color to white and then we also want to take the branding ID and then the h one.
And we want to set that color to white as well.
All right so save that and check it out.
So reload.
There we go.
Now there's a little more space under the logo because we increase the height this background color
changed and that yellow is now gone.
All right so see the next thing I want to do is all the links I want to be using me this dark blue color.
So will do that also if we go back to the home.
These are still this.
This actually now before we get to that let's handle this.
If we take a look at what this actually is it's the div with the class of breadcrumbs.
And if we look in our styling here you'll see div dot breadcrumbs.
So we want to override that.
So let's first of all just do a we're going to do all a link and a visited and we're going to say color
and we're going to set it to this bloke here.
OK.
And then the breadcrumbs will say give Dot
breadcrumbs.
Let's set that background to the green so the green is going to be 3 0.
See a zero save that.
Let's go back reload and now we have that green color.
All right.
See I think that's good.
Actually I don't like the color of these.
This right here this line I could see with that is
that in the brain.
Yeah that's the breadcrumbs link.
So you know what we'll do let's just make that black so we'll say Divx breadcrumbs
links say color then we'll do 3 3 3 and see if that works.
OK but what about this this also these are just these are not the links for those.
Let's do the blue.
So we would just do color in the breadcrumbs.
So like color
like that.
Let's see go and if you mean you can do what you want if you want to experiment if you want to make
them a little lighter.
That's fine.
So now if we go back to home I want to take care of these these blocks right here.
And if we take a look at what these are there are caption tags and if we look at the styling we want
this right here because you can see this is where that background color is.
So we basically want all of these classes.
So I'm going to go ahead and copy these and paste that in.
OK.
And we want the background to be green so I'm going to just copy that and paste that in.
And let's take a look.
There we go.
So now it's starting to look more branded more like are our clients branding colors or company colors.
So I just think that's pretty much it.
Let's see if we go to the ad page or let's go to like the listings.
Let's go here.
I guess we can change these buttons if we want see
yeah.
Let's grab this right here.
And let's do
let's do a background of the blue
and then color white.
Screen load.
And there we go.
I don't have a problem with that.
The Save button looking like that.
I mean that's fine.
So I think we're good for the SS in the next video.
What I want to do is customize the tables a little bit.
So like I want to have some other stuff here like the let's see what can we put here.
We could do some location info like the city we could put the price the realtor things like that.
OK so we'll start to customize a little more in the next video.