All right guys so in the last video we added the logo here in the admin area.
We changed up the colors to match the company branding.
Now I want to just mess with the this this a little bit.
I don't want just the name of the listing here.
I want to have some other data like the price and the list date stuff like that.
So to edit this we need to go into VS code and we need to go to our let's see you want to go to our
listings app and then admin dot pi k where we registered the model and we want to go right here and
create a class called the listing admin and this we want to pass in here admin Daut model admin and
then we can actually add certain variables here are certain properties that relate to how things are
displayed.
But before I forget this listing admin class we just defined what we need to do is pass it in here.
OK.
Or it won't work.
So I want to define what I want in the table or in the list.
So we say list display and you can see if you have a whole bunch of pop ups here of different things
we can do by let's do list display and we want to just set a set of parentheses and then the fields
we want so I actually want to show the ID.
I want to show the title which already is showing but I want to show that still I want to do is published
and what's really cool when you do a boolean value it actually shows like a little checkbox or like
an X if it's not published.
So I think that's pretty cool.
Does that automatically shows a little icon.
We could do like those.
The city and state and stuff like that but I'm not going to I'm going to do price and I'm going to do
list today.
And I'm going to do.
Realtor.
So let's save that.
I forgot I a pretty or enabled so let's save that let's go back and reload and there we go and see the
will is published.
You actually have these little checkboxes which is pretty cool.
And I'm going to show you how we can make it so that we can click these here and actually publish an
unpublished them without having to go in.
But first notice that I can't click on the title to get to the page I can click on the ID and the reason
for that is because it's the first one.
But I also want to be able to click on the titles so the way that we fix that is by adding right under
this we can say list display links right here so lists play links and then pass in any fields that we
want to actually link.
And for me what I want to choose is ID so will keep the ID and then also title OK so I'll save that.
Now let's go back and reload and now we can click on the title OK and you can make any of these go to
the page if you wanted to.
So let's see we can also filter.
I want to be able to filter by realtor.
I mean we could do like like this.
That I'll just kind of order it by the realtor or by any of these rather.
And that's that's that's some functionality that's included that we take for granted.
I mean it would take quite a bit of code to be able to do that.
So if we want to have like a little filter box we could just simply say list filter.
And I just want realtor
OK realtor and when we use parentheses like this we just want if it's only one value we want to have
a comma at the end or we or we'll probably get an error.
So we want to do that and reload.
And now over here we can filter by realtors say Kyle Brown and only show me Mikhail's properties which
is really cool.
And you can do this for any any field you want.
But I'm just going to leave it at realtor.
Now I'm going to do is make it so that I can click on the is published icon and it will publish.
And then of course I could publish it again if I click again.
So to do that we can add in the list underscore editable and we're going to set that to is published
with put a comma because there's only one value.
So now if I go back and reload they're actually going to check.
I forgot they they changed the check boxes so if I go ahead like that it's now unpublished if we go
in here and we look at the value actually because it's not oh you know what we have to save it we go.
Forgot all about that.
So we can publish it again.
So it's up to you if you want to have the check boxes here with the save button you can do that or you
can just display the X's and the checks.
OK.
Now what about searching.
OK so we have a ton of listings here we want to be able to search by certain fields.
We can do that so we can just say in here search fields and let's be let's make search by title so I'll
say title description
address
city
state
zip code and price.
OK so will be able to search by that.
So let's save this.
And if we go back and reload now we have a little search field up here so you can see we can kind of
build like we can really customize this without having to go into the actual Django admen code you never
want to do that.
We just have these extra methods that we can add to be able to do this stuff.
OK so if I search for let's say Essex and here it is so we can search.
All right.
So let's see just clear this up.
So the next thing I want to do is just define the amount of listings per page because I believe by default
it'll just keep going without pagination so I'm going to define right here list underscore per page
and I'm going to set it to 25 and save and that's it.
So now that we've done the listings Let's go to the realtors and let's go to admen dot PI here.
And let's let's change some things here to customize this so first of all we need to create our function.
So this is going to be I'm sorry not our function our class and this is going to be realtor admin and
this is going to take an admin Daut model admin and let's not forget to pass it in here.
So we want to also pass in the second parameter of Realtor admin.
And let's set our list display.
So this is what fields we want to display in the table will do same thing Id let's say name let's do
email and let's do hire date.
All right.
And then let's do the links so list display lengths we're going to set to just ID in name search fields
let's just do.
Well just to name
and with do lists per page and we'll set that to 25 as well.
So we'll save let's go back and check out realtors.
There we go.
So we have our name email higher date a search field up here.
Good.
All right.
So I think that we're pretty good with the admin area.
We can easily add realtors and listings now.
So in the next section we're going to start on the front end web site.
OK so for featured listings we want to be able to fetch into the database grab the listings that we've
added in the admin area and display them here.
Okay so that's what we're going to work on in the next video and in the next section.