All right guys in this video we're going to install Python 3 on a Mac and I already have it installed
but I'm going to go through the process anyway.
So if you open up your terminal and you type in Python dash dash version unless you've already installed
Python and you have a Python 3 and you've set up your environment variables and stuff you're probably
going to see Version 2 k 2.0 something probably 7.10 we don't want to use version to you you don't want
to use version 2 anymore for anything unless there's a specific reason.
So let's go ahead and say Python 3 dash dash version and you'll see that I have version 3.7 0 which
is the latest version.
If you see like not found or something like that that means that Python 3 is not installed on your system.
If you see an earlier version of three then you should go ahead and follow these instructions to upgrade.
So we're going to go to Python dot org and go to downloads click on 3.7 point zero or whatever the latest
version is at the time.
And let's open up the package that it downloads and it's just going to be just a simple installer that
we click through.
So let's click continue.
Continue and we're going to agree.
And here you can click install but I just want to show you if you click customize you can pick and choose
to and to disable like the Unix command line tools and stuff like that you want to make sure all of
this is checked especially this you want to make sure that Pip is installed which is the Python package
manager.
It's used to install third party packages including Django.
So we definitely need that.
And now we're just going to click install and you just put in your password
and it's going to go ahead and install Python 3.
All right so once it's installed you'll see something like this and we can go ahead and close it and
we'll move the installer to the trash.
So now what I want you to do is open your terminal up and do a Python 3 dash dash version and you should
see that you have the latest version installed.
All right.
So if we do just Python 3 it's going to bring us into the REPL or into the python console where we can
actually type out Python code and get a response.
So for instance we can do the print command and let's just say print hello and we'll run it and we get
hello as our output.
All right we can even do things like create variables so I could say name equals Brad and then we could
do print name and we get Brad.
OK but we're not going to do too much in here.
Well we want to do is create python files which are files with a dot PI extension and then we're going
to learn how to you know learn the basics of Python within the files and then we'll jump into Django.
All right so if we do a control d we can get out of the Python console here and in the next video I'm
going to show you how to install Python on Windows.
Obviously if you're not using Windows you don't really have to watch that video.
But after that we'll start to learn the basic syntax and then like I said move on to Django.