All right guys in this video we're going to install Python 3 on a Windows machine.
So we want to go to Python dot org and go to downloads and whatever the latest version is at this time
it's three point seven point zero.
Download the X-C file and open that up.
OK it's just going to just click run and it's going to be a simple install.
Now really important that you check this off right here this is going to add 3.7 to your path so that
when you type in Python it's going to be it's going to use 3.7 by default.
So make sure you check that off and then click Install now.
OK so it's going to go and go through with the installation.
All right.
So now we see set up is successful so we can go ahead and close this up.
And now we're going to do is open up a Windows command prompt and from here let's say Python dash dash
version and you can see we have 3.7 point zero.
And if I do just Python enter it's going to bring us into the python shell here where we can type any
kind of Python commands such as print.
So I will say print hello.
We can assign variables like name same name equals Brad.
And then let's say print name and we get Brad OK and if we want to get out of here we can do control
Z or we can do X it like that and that will x it out.
All right so that's how you can install Python 3 on Windows.
So when the next video we're going to start to set up our text editor which is going to be vs code and
we're going to install the python extension along with some other extensions that I'm going to show
you.
All right so I'll see you in the next video.