All right guys in this video we're going to do two things we're going to set up our text editor which
is vs code and we're going to set up the python sandbox which is basically just a set of files that
we're going to use in the next section when we look at Python fundamentals.
OK.
Now the next section if you're already if you're already comfortable with Python and things like functions
and conditionals in dictionaries and different data types and structures and stuff like that then you
can completely skip that section and move on to Django.
But if you're not that comfortable with Python or if you've never used Python I would definitely recommend
watching the whole next section in using the sandbox.
OK now as far as your text editor Of course you don't have to use VS code if you want to use atom or
Sublime Text or an idea like pi chalmer eclipse or something like that.
That's absolutely fine.
But we'll be using Visual Studio code so we're just going to do some some basic setup here.
So if you want to download it you can go to cocotte Visual Studio dot com it's cross-platform Mac Windows
Linux.
I already have it installed so I'm not going to go through the install process.
It's very very self-explanatory.
So let's jump into VS code.
So if you just downloaded it and install it you'll see a welcome screen you can just go ahead and close
that up.
And with this code you have a whole host of extensions you can install if you click on this icon here.
You can see these are the extensions that I have on this machine.
We actually want to install the python extension.
So if you search for Python it's going to be the first one you can see.
There's almost 15 million downloads.
So we're going to go ahead and install that.
OK once it installs you just click reload and now it's installed and that will give us things like lending
Intellisense and highlighting all types of stuff if you want to read more about it you can just click
on here and you can go through all of this stuff if you want.
All right.
So now what I want to do is open up the sandbox files in vs code and if you're using a different text
editor just go ahead and open the files up in whatever you're using.
So on my desktop I have the python sandbox Stoddard's zip file which you should have in this lecture.
I'm going to go ahead and extract that.
And this is what I want to open up but I'm just going to rename it to Python sandbox rather than just
you know Python sandbox starter.
And if I go to this code I'm just going to go to open file or open folder.
I'm going to go to my where it's my desktop which I'm on and Python sandbox.
OK so in here you see all the different files we just want to click open and we should get all of those
on the side here.
OK so I'm just going to open up one of these files variable's dot pi is the first one we're actually
going to be working with.
These are just comments.
Nothing is going to come of this.
We'll be adding on to this later but I just wanted to open up a python file.
Now if you type something in here and then just delete it and save control or command as you may get
a pop up that asks about Python lending.
It's up to you if you want to use that Linter or not.
We're going to use Lanting later on when we get into Django but I'm not going to use it for the the
for the next section so you can disable it if you want.
Or whatever.
So to run these files there's there's a few ways we can do it in vs code.
We're going to take the symbols out and just run Python 3.
And then whatever the file is like variables dot PI and that will run it.
We don't have any output here because there's nothing to output to output.
If I said like print 1 here and then we ran it we'd get one.
OK.
Now it's important to run it with Python 3 and it depends on how your system set up if you're using
Windows and you install Python.
Chances are if you just do Python that's version 3 and you can easily check by doing a dash dash version.
You can see on my system it's too.
But if I do Python 3 dash dash version that's version 3.
OK and when we start to use virtual environments and stuff we work on that will no longer have to use
Python 3 we'll just be able to use Python but we'll get into that later.
So that's how we're going to run our files for now.
Another thing you could do is go to your debugger in vs code which is this right here.
And if you want to set this up you want to do a command shift p.
In fact you should do this anyway.
And then just search for Python and go to a select interpreter.
OK.
Now later on when we work in virtual environments our virtual environment will actually show up here
and that's what we'll have to choose.
But for now we just want to make sure we choose 3.7 or three point whatever whatever version you're
using as long as it's Python Python 3.
All right then down here you can see that it actually now says Python 3.7.
So I could run this file and put the print back here so I could run this file now by simply clicking
the play button.
And choosing Python and now you can see that it ran.
It's going to give us like the whole path and all that stuff.
But you can see it ran because it printed out one if I want to change is to say print a string hello
world and we'll get into strings and all that stuff later.
But if I go ahead and press play and it runs so if you want to do it that way you can but I think just
putting in the file name is is an easier way to do it.
So it's up to you guys how you want to do it and of course if you're using a different terminal I'm
sorry a different text editor.
You know you can do it however you want.
I'm sure there's different ways to run a file.
All right so now we're set up in the next section we're going to start off talking about variables and
data types how variables are constructed things like that and we'll go through pretty much all the basics
of python and then we'll jump into our Django application.