Hurry guys so our application is finished at least for now up to this point.
You know we add more features later on in the course.
But now we want to deploy our Django app which is no easy task deploying any kind of Django app or even
like a flask application anything to do with Python is usually a little more difficult and let's say
something like ph P where you have a lot of pre-made scripts that are included with shared hosts and
stuff like that.
So Django is a bit more difficult.
So what we're going to be doing we're going to be using something called Digital Ocean which I'm sure
many of you have heard of they offer virtual private servers they call them droplets but they're basically
just instances of Linux distributions so we'll be using a buntu and we're going to pretty much have
to recreate most of the stuff that we've done on our local machine meaning set up Django.
We're going to set up post-grads on our remote machine but of course we're not going to recreate all
the files and stuff.
We're going to use it to transfer all of our files to the server.
All right so before we get into Digital Ocean we want to push our project to either get Hobb or you
can use bitbucket or get lab whatever you want to use.
I would definitely suggest get Haab especially if you're you know you're not really familiar with this
kind of stuff and you want to follow along.
So I'm logged in to get hub now and I'm going to create a new repository and I'm going to call it BTR
the underscore project and then let's just say Django real estate Web site.
Now I'm actually going to make this private so because I don't want anyone to see this for now I do
have about 7000 followers or so on get how and I don't want them seeing this just yet.
But I will make this public afterwards if you want to use a private repository you have to pay a fee.
I think it's like 8 bucks a month or something like that.
So you probably just choose public and then I'm going to do create repository.
OK so now we're going to do is push our project to our repository so I'm going to go grab my terminal
here and you can see inside my BTR project I do an ls will see all of our stuff here.
One thing I do want to do is just take a look at our Get ignore so I'm going to do cat Daut get ignore
and just see what's in there just to make sure that this is correct.
So have Slash media slash static V and V.
OK.
So just make sure that you're get ignore looks like this.
All right so let's let's I have now just to let you guys know I've been making commits all along.
I don't know if you have if you have not then you need to at least make one commit now so that you can
push it if you haven't even initialized the repository just go ahead and say get in it and run that.
All right.
Then you want to do get ad Daut So that will add everything to the staging area.
Once you do that you want to do get commit dash em and then whatever comment you could say like initial
commit or something like that.
OK once you have that you have it all loaded in your local repository and you want to now add get help
as a remote repository.
OK so I'm going to go ahead and grab this now.
I have my S-sh keys set up with a good hub going to go through that here.
I am going to show you how to set up S-sh keys for Digital Ocean.
But if you don't have your S-sh set up with get Hobb just go ahead and change this to HTP apps and then
grab this link and you just have to put your get have a username and password but I'm going to choose
S-sh because I should be all set for that.
So I'm going to copy that and go back to my terminal and let's add that as a remote pausa story and
then we just want to push to the master branch so we want this next command.
And we'll run that and hopefully I didn't forget anything.
And it should go ahead and push our project.
All right and if I go back here and reload There we go and I'll add a read me here later on it's going
to leave it for now.
So our whole project is now on get Haab Oh you know what I should have put the VS code in in the get
ignored but that's fine.
I'm just going to leave it for now.
So now that we have everything pushed to get hub we're going to go to this link right here.
I'll probably create a document in the course so that you don't have to type all this and you can follow.
And this is a just.
Ok get objects which is like kind of like a just a text file.
This is actually a markdown file so it's formatted nicely and this is going to take us from start to
finish for deployment so everything from creating a digital ocean droplet to creating S-sh keys to access
it to security provisions like disabling the user setting up a firewall.
We're going to use post-grads of course you've just set that up our virtual environment.
We're going to upload using.
Get going to have a local settings file for sensitive data and then unicorn.
We're going to use to serve our project on port 8000 thousand and then we're going to use engine X to
serve it on port 80 case we use engine X as basically as our proxy and then set up our domain.
Now this document may be different.
What you're seeing may be different from what you're seeing right here because I'm probably going to
have to update it in a couple of places but just follow along with the course do what I do.
And you know we'll get through it.
Deployment can be a real pain in the ass sometimes but we'll do it.
We'll get through it.
And as far as digital ocean there's a link here if you click this link and sign up using this link you'll
get $10 free and we'll be using the five dollar plans you get two months free hosting and then if you
want you can you can add more funds and continue with it or just you know not pay anything.
So yeah.
So let's get started here in the next video we're going to go through create our droplet.
I don't know if we'll do the S-sh keys in that video or the next one but we'll go ahead and we'll get
set up to start deployment.