All right guys so now that we're going to start our deployment we're you're going to want to do is go
to this just file here and I'll put the link in the course if you don't.
If you can't find it just go ahead and google Brad Travers see just Brad Travis get have just in your
find this jingle deploy file.
All right in this link here is going to give you $10 free so if you don't want to pay anything at all
to do this just go ahead and use this link.
It'll take you to Digital Ocean and you just want to sign up.
OK just sign up like you would any other site validate your e-mail and then just go ahead and log in
and you'll see an interface like this.
OK.
So what we need to do now is create what's called the droplet.
OK so we go up here we can say create droplet and a droplet is basically just a VPN a virtual private
server.
It's it's basically just an instance of a buntu or whatever Linux distribution that you choose.
So right here you want to choose your distribution we're going to use a buntu 18.00 for now if you're
watching this later on there's a newer version 19 20 whatever.
I would suggest using 18.00 for just so that you don't run into any issues and it's absolutely fine
to use an older version.
It'd be fine for me to use 16 right now so choose that and then I just want to show you that under one
click apps there is an option for Django but it's Django one right now.
By the time you're watching this it may be Django too but I still wouldn't suggest using this.
We're going to do we're going to do everything from scratch.
OK.
So let's go down here let's choose the first option here which is the $5 per month.
So if you use that link I give you you'll get two months of this.
With this package that will go down.
Who's going to leave all this.
New York is fine for me for the data center.
Now here you can choose to add an S-sh key and then I'm not going to go this isn't going to be S-sh
keys 101.
I am going to show you how to do it.
But I do have a core.
A crash course on YouTube under the Traverse City media YouTube channel if you want to learn more about
S-sh.
But basically you have the option to have a key so that you don't have to enter a password from your
from your computer or it'll just automatically go into the server.
Or if you skip this and just create your droplet you'll get what will happen is you get an email with
your with a temporary password and you'll log in that way.
But we're actually going to create an S-sh key which is highly recommended it makes it more secure and
just easier in general so easier to log in.
So what we want to do is open up your terminal now with Mac Linux Windows 10 you have an S-sh command.
OK so you can do S-sh and you can you can run the you can log in using that command you can create keys
and so on.
If you're on Windows 8 or less like Windows 7 or something like that which I'm sure isn't too much to
many of you but if you are you're going to have to use something called Poddy and poddy gen which allows
you to S-sh into servers.
I think you might be able to use get Bash in earlier versions of Windows and have access to the S-sh
command but I'm not positive on that it's been so long since I've used something you know less than
Windows 10.
So we're going to go ahead and get started here now I'm in my virtual environment inside my project.
I actually want to do all this from my home directory so I'm going to open up a new tab in my terminal.
OK so now I'm just in my home directory.
OK.
No I'm not.
I'm still in my project.
I want a CD that will bring me into my home directory.
OK.
So don't we just explain how this works when you create an S-sh key.
It's going to go into a folder in your home directory called Daut S-sh.
Now you didn't see that when I didn't ask because it's hidden by default.
Anything with a dot in front of it usually means that it's a hidden file.
So if I do it and last and then dash a which shows all file all files and folders.
You'll see it right here.
S-sh.
All right.
And even if you don't have it for some reason when you create your key it will create it automatically.
So let's just see what's in my dot S-sh is going to say current directory and then dot S-sh and you
can see I have I.D. RSA and Id say pub.
I also have some good hobbies.
Now when we generate our key it's going to automatically want to name it.
This ID underscore RSA and that's fine and you can do that.
I'm actually going to call mine ID RSA underscored diod for Digital Ocean because I already have these
here for something else and I could use these if I wanted to but I want separate keys for Digital Ocean.
So to generate a key if we look at our deployments file right here we want to run S-sh Ki-Jana.
Okay.
And then it says hit your all the way through.
It's going to want to create these files like I said but you can rename them as I'm going to if you
want.
And then you want to copy the public key file.
So let's do that.
So it's an S-sh dash co-gen.
All right so enter file where you want to save it.
So like I said it's going to put it here by default in your home directory S-sh folder.
I'm actually going to change this to the same location so users
Brad Traviss slash dot S-sh slash.
Except I'm going to call it.
Id underscore as a underscore d o k so for Digital Ocean I'm going to hit enter and what it'll do with
it will create that in the dot pub case of the public and private key Do I want a passphrase.
No I'm just going to hit enter.
And now that should have created it.
So now if we do an ls in our S-sh folder you'll see I have the DEO and then the Deodhar PABX.
OK.
Now the public key is what goes on the server the private should always always stay secret stay private
and stay on your local machine.
OK.
So what we want to do is we want to get that private that public key and put it in Digital Ocean.
So if you look right here we have a command called Cat and this will basically display whatever is in
this file.
The public key it will display it in the terminal and then we can simply copy it and we can add it to
digital ocean.
OK so we're going to clear this up and I'm going to do cat current folder Daut S-sh and then I want
the ID underscore PABX underscore D.O. dot dot I'm sorry Id say underscore D.O. dot pop.
OK.
So only put the D.O. if that's what you used if you use the standard IDR say and do that.
So this is our key.
So what we want to grab it from where it starts at S-sh and then it ends where it says locals are going
to copy that whole thing go back to digital ocean say new S-sh key pass that you see we get a little
green checkmark letting us know what's the proper format and just going to call this iMac because this
is from my Mac machine that I'm on now and I'm going to add that key.
OK.
So that's it.
Now for your hostname you can name this whatever you want.
I'll just call it a buntu say a bunch to one and create
OK.
So now it's going to go through and create our server.
It should be pretty quick once it does that we'll have a remote IP address to access it.
I mean this is not going to be anything on it by default but we're going to we're going to put our Django
app on it.
I mean as you can see it goes pretty damn fast.
So it's now set up and this is our IP address.
OK now if I copy this and I go to it
should just say it should just be like like there's nothing here like there's no web site here yet so
it can't be reached because we have no web server on it.
No.
No server software no engine X or Apache.
There's nothing on this.
So we're just going to get this page.
OK.
So the next step is I just want to show you if we go to if we click on our droplet you'll see a bunch
of options over here.
You can see or you can monitor your CPQ your disk input output all that stuff but it's not going to
show up just yet because we just created the server.
But you will see this later on.
Also access you can launch a console from the browser if you want power or if you want to power it off
in three volumes you can resize if you want to scale your application and you need more memory or Sipa
you can easily upgrade it which is great networking gives you your IP address and Gateway and all that
stuff your backups.
So you can make backups you can take snapshots you can destroy it so you have full control of this droplet
or of this V-P Yes.
All right.
Well let's go back to the deployment here.
This markdown file and we want to just try to log in now.
OK so we want the IP address which is right here we can just click copy and we're going to go back to
our terminal and let's do S-sh and then we want the user name which is going to be route.
OK that's the only user on it for now for now.
And then we want to do at and then paste in the IP.
OK.
So the first time you try to log in you're going to get this message you just want to say yes and then
enter.
And we got permission denied.
OK.
So if you get this this right here you might get this if you renamed your key to underscore D.O. like
I did.
If so then just try to do this S-sh dash add and then you want to do current folder dot S-sh slash and
then the name of your key which in my case was ID underscore iris a underscore d'Eau.
OK.
No dot pub just just like this.
Now it's his identity added.
So now I'm going to try to log in again.
And there we go.
So now we're in.
OK so if if you got that public key denied.
Go ahead and try to run that S-sh ad and hopefully that works for you.
If not you may have to go back and recreate the key maybe you didn't copy it right.
Or something like that.
Maybe there was this because it has to be exact when you put it in that little box and digital ocean
there can't be any spaces or anything like that.
No no line breaks.
You get to make sure it's perfect.
So now the reason that I know I'm in is a few things.
It's giving us kind of a welcome page here and it's telling it's giving us some information like the
system load the processes that are robbing the memory usage the IP address and down here it notice it
doesn't say you know Brad traversed or whatever my my computer name is.
It says route at buntu one.
And remember buntu one is what we called our server and you see we have the little hash symbol the number
sign here.
And actually if you look at the documentation that I created in are just whenever there's a money sign
that means that we're running these commands on our local machine anything where you see the number
sign that means we're on the remote server.
Ok so I wanted to kind of make that clear so you don't run commands you know commands that you should
be running on your server on your local machine and vice versa.
All right so at least now we know we can access our server.
So the next step is to do some security provisioning.
You don't want to be using your root user like we are right now.
So in the next video we're going to create a new user and we're also going to disable log in for the
root user.
OK it's really important security steps to take and then we're also going to enable our firewall just
a very simple firewall and we'll take it from there.
All right so we'll see you in the next video.