All right guys so now that we're logged into our server we just want to do some security stuff.
OK so first thing I want to do is create a new user.
I'm actually going to clear this so.
So I'm just doing command Alpher that are my be control.
I usually switch my command and control keys when I'm using a Mac.
So if we go down here we already logged in.
So now we want to create a new user.
So I'm actually calling my user Django admin because that's really the purpose of this account.
So let's go ahead and do that.
I mean you don't have to use Django admin if you want to use something else that's fine.
I'm actually going to make this smaller so that we can see both these at the same time.
If I can.
All right.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Let's say AD user and I'm going to say Django admin actually maybe we should call it something else.
That's fine.
Whatever.
All right.
So add user now we want to give this user root privileges OK or pseudo privileges.
Well actually first we have to do a password so let's give the user a password.
It's the.
All right.
So this stuff this this will last you for like your name and stuff you can just enter through all this.
Is this correct.
Yes.
All right so now we have a new user so let's clear this up and now like I said let's give this user
root privileges so we want to do user mod dash lowercase a uppercase G pseudo K sudo is the basically
like the root group that we want to put this user in and say Django admin OK.
Now this user should have admin privileges.
So I just want to show you something real quick.
If we were to logo.
So if we say X it and we try to log in again so I say as a sage except I want to log in as Jane Gladman
we get a public key deny.
OK and the reason for this is because the S-sh he that we created is only for the root user.
So we actually have to if you look over here we have to add our S-sh key to Django adman's file an authorized
keys file.
All right.
So let's log back in as root.
All right so now I'm logged in as true and I'm going to CD into home slash and then Django admin.
OK.
Actually hold on a second.
Let's do slash like that.
All right so this is the Django admen users home directory.
And as you can see there's nothing in here.
What I want to do is create a file called authorized keys and then I want to put our S-sh key that's
on this local machine into that file and you can see how how to do that over here.
So we just seeded into it let's make a directory called Dot S-sh.
So make our DOT S-sh And if you do an ls a you'll see that folder lets CD into dot S-sh and from here
we want to create an authorized keys file.
Now there is you can use different text editors command line text editors like you can use VAM if you
want of them is a little complicated so I'm not going to use that just in case you know people are new
to this which I'm sure many of you are going to use something called Nano which is very easy to use.
Now if we do Nano and then name a file like authorized underscore keys what it's going to do is it's
going to create that file and go into it.
So I'm going to hit enter and it brings us into that file.
So what we want to do here is put in our key so I'm going to go back to see if we want to go outside
of our server.
So I guess I'll just open up a new tab or just a new terminal depending on where you are using your
software might not have tabs so just open up another terminal.
Make sure you're on your local machine and I want to grab that that key again.
I'm going to say cat and I'm in my home directory so I'm going to say Daut S-sh remember I'm on my local
machine now and I want to grab ID underscore as a underscore D.O. dot pub.
OK.
And I'm going to go ahead and grab this and copy it.
And let's go to our authorized keys and paste that in.
OK.
Make sure this has to be exact Again no spaces or anything like that and you can't see the whole thing
but you can see that it is it is added.
All right so now that's added to get out of this you want to do command.
Or I'm sorry control X or yeah control X. It's actually command X for me that's why it's a little confusing
because I switch my keys.
Like I said.
So we want to save it so we're going to say yes we're going to hit Y and then we're just going to hit
enter.
OK.
And that should save it.
So now if I were to do a cat
authorized underscore keys this would show us what's in that file and you can see that that key is in
the file.
Ok so now that we've done that we should be able to log in as Django admen.
So we're going to exit the server as root and clear this up.
And now it's to in S-sh as Django adman's and there we go.
And you can see that now actually colored now because they're not as the root and Django admin at a
buntu one so that's exactly what we want.
So now we want to actually disable the root log in because it said it's just a security measure so we
want to open up our nanotech said it or add to this file S-sh D-Conn. Feg.
So you get a pseudo Neno and it's slash see slash S-sh slash S-sh d underscore config.
OK.
Now this is a config file so we just want to find these two right here.
Permit route log in.
We want to set to know password authentication we want to set to know which I believe is already set
to know what we want to make sure.
So let's look for permit route log in just going down here right here.
So permit route log in right now is set to Yes.
So we're going to go ahead and change that to no Okay.
And then let's see what else password authentication should be around here.
So password authentication is already set to no good.
So to get out we want to do control X and then yes or Y for yes and then enter.
OK and that'll save it and then we just want to reload the S-sh service.
So to do that we can run this command here.
And if you want to type in this stuff you can just simply paste it in like that and that will reload
it.
OK so now what I want to do is just set up our firewall and I just want to mention that all of these
commands this stuff is all coming from the digital ocean documentation.
I probably should have mentioned that in the beginning if I say digital ocean Django and genetics just
do that right here.
So if you want to kind of look over this this is kind of the same thing.
It doesn't include like the S-sh keys and stuff like that.
It doesn't even actually is I don't even know if this is the thing I was looking for and this is for
16.00 for see send it.
No that's not it either.
I don't know they have they have all kinds of.
And that's not even Digital Ocean but Digital Ocean has all kinds of tutorials on this.
So if you need extra help just go ahead and search their documentation.
So next thing I want to do we want to do the firewall so we want to run this right here.
So go ahead and clear this or one pseudo.
So UFW app list.
OK.
So available applications open S-sh.
So we want to make sure that open S-sh is allowed so we do sudo UFW allow open S-sh.
OK then we want to enable the firewall.
So sudo and UFW is the firewall and we want to enable it to see command may disrupt the thing that's
fine or say yes OK.
And the reason it didn't disrupt us is because we added open S-sh open SH's the program that allows
us to do the S-sh command into the server.
All right.
And if we want to check the status of the firewall we can do UFW status and you can see that open S-sh
is allowed.
OK so it's as easy as that to a need enable just a simple firewall and.
And these are steps that should be taken for any server.
It doesn't matter if it's Django.
No J.S. and Ruby on Rails ph P if you're using just a you know a standard of buntu server.
This is stuff that that you should be doing.
All right so that's really it guys as far as like security provisioning and stuff.
For now at least I think in the next video we're going to start to install stuff like you can see we're
going to install Python 3 post-grads engine X all that stuff and then we'll start to set up our database.
OK and we'll start to deploy our application.
So I will see you in the next video.