All right guys.
Now we're going to we're going to install some software.
OK.
So you want to be logged in as Django admen into your remote droplet.
And we want to first of all update our packages.
OK so we're going to say sudo apt.
You can do app to get if you want but you're now allowed to just do apt and an app to get it.
This is our package manager for a buntu.
And we just want to update case we want to update and then we want to run upgrade which will actually
upgrade the software upgrade the package listings that we can upgrade any software that we have.
All right so now it's two
grade.
Yes.
I just want to have the most up to date stuff installed.
And the next line here is we're actually installing a bunch of stuff at once.
So we're going Stahl Python 3 Peppe Python 3 dev.
This dependency here this lib P-Q dev postgrads.
And then this post-grads contrib engine X and uncurl
unicorn are going to do that a little later.
And that's going to be used to serve up and that's installed using Pipp anyway.
But that's going to be used to serve up our application.
OK.
So upgrade always takes longer than update.
I'm going to actually just copy this line here.
I just want to grab that just for when this is done.
Go ahead and run it.
All right so if you run into this right here it's just going to ask about the Grodman the GRUB boot
menu.
So just just choose the default.
Ok keep the local version that's currently installed.
OK so hit enter again.
OK and this should be just about done.
All right.
So now that that's done I'm going to go ahead and paste in what I copied which is not pasting in scratch.
Again there we go.
I believe 18.00 for buntu comes with Python 3 the latest version.
But we're just gonna install it anyways.
And there might be a later version when when you guys are watching this
OK and then once that's done we can start to set up our database
and we have everything here that we need to add.
All right so this is done going to just clear the terminal up.
So now we want to do is go into postgrads.
OK.
Now when you install post-grads you just like with the local installation there is a default user called
postgrads.
So we want to log in is that so we're going to say pseudo dash you.
So we're just defining the user of post-grads.
OK and then we're going to do PSU Well right now.
You can see that this is changed.
We're now inside of post-grads.
So we're going to create a database and say create a database and you call this whatever you want.
I'm calling it BTR the underscore Prod. semi-colon there.
Case that you create a database.
Now we want to create a user We don't want to use the default post-grads user I know we did that the
way we do it I think we did that in local development but we don't want to do that in production so
let's say create user.
Now this needs to be fixed over here you can see I use DBI user here.
I think I just meant it as a placeholder and then down here I use the user Django DB admin.
I think that I'm just going to call the user D-B admin because I think Django D-B admin.
And then the user of the server which is Gengel admin I think that's a little confusing.
So I'm just going to call it D-B admin like that.
OK.
And then we're gonna give it a password.
So with password and I'm just going to give this I'm just going to give it a password of a b c one two
three exclamation Kies let me just make sure that's good.
Yeah.
And then we just want a semi-colon.
All right.
So now we just want to alter some roll we want to just set up like the encoding and stuff like that
the time zone.
So we're just going to copy this although I'm going to change the DB admin because that's what I use
so it's pay set in and I'll change this.
I'll change the markdown file for you guys so you won't have this you won't have to change this unless
you want to use a different name.
That's absolutely fine.
D-B admin OK let's grab this one
so you aren't D-B admen
again this is all in the Digital Ocean documentation
TV.
OK snow and all that stuff is that we want to give the D-B admin want to give them privileges to the
beat free prod database.
OK so going to copy this except I'm just going to change the user to DB admin
so granting all privileges on the database Tiare production or Prod. to DB admin.
And there we go.
So now we can get out of postgrads by just doing a backslash.
So we want to quit.
And that's it.
So now we have our database.
It's as easy as that.
So now we're ready to actually start our Django stuff and just like we did on the local machine and
we want to create a virtual environment on the on the remote server.
Ok I'm going to set the structure up a little different.
What I want to do is I want to actually this yeah we need to install that.
All right so we're going to have a folder in our home directory called pi apps because a lot of the
times you'll have one server and you'll have multiple applications you may have a p p application.
And you know you can route through engine X or whatever.
So I want to have a folder called pi apps and then have our project folder in there and the virtual
environment is going to be in the PI apps folder or not in our actual project folder like it was in
our local environment.
OK and this stuff is optional I mean you can structure things how you want but that's just just how
I prefer to do it.
All right so we'll get into this in the next video.