All right guys.
Now we're going to start to create our virtual environment now.
We have to actually install the Wii or the Vende package using our apt package manager.
OK so we want to run this command sudo apt install Python 3 dash and V
OK.
And then like I said we're going to create a directory called pi apps in the home folder.
Let's clear this out and just C.D make sure we're in the home.
If you see this little squiggly line that represents the home folder and right now there's nothing in
it nothing that's not hidden.
So let's go ahead and make directory PI apps and then CD into pi apps.
OK.
And from here we want to create our virtual environment.
So we're going to say Python 3 and this works just like we did in the local environment.
If you're using Windows and you we're using the we're going to created the same way but to activate
it you're going to use the this right here been activate not your scripts activate back.
So Python 3 Dasch am and we want to say V and V and then the directory We want to call it is going to
be V and V as well.
OK.
Now if I do an ls You see we have our V and V if we look inside of that we have our bin file and that
has our activate script.
OK so let's activate our environment by doing source.
We're going to do.
V and V slash Ben slash activate.
And now we're inside of our virtual environment.
OK and you can tell because we have this this V and V right here.
So now we want to get ready to actually clone our get repository which has our application.
Now we need the dependencies for our application now I'm going to go back into my local project.
OK so right now I'm in my local project very important to know that I'm not on the server in this in
this tab.
So I'm still in my virtual environment now if I do a pip freeze this shows shows me all of my dependencies
for this project.
Now a lot of this stuff is like lifting stuff from vs code auto pep 8.
This isn't stuff that we actually need on the server.
So you have a couple of options you could install each thing on your server separately like Pipp install
like of course Django Pipp install pillow which is needed for images.
These two are needed for postgrads and then I believe the only other thing we need is
I think this right here this is P Y Z.
We don't need pilot Django we don't need any of that but I just want to show you a command that we can
use to get all these dependencies into a text file and then we can actually push that to our server
and just install from that.
So to do that we want to do Pepp
install Dasch are I'm sorry.
So we want we want to do that on the server.
We're going to do Pipp freeze which basically takes all of our dependencies and then we want to put
it into a file called requirements dot XTi.
All right.
Now if I do an ls you'll see we have that file if I take a look at it I'll say cat requirements dot
x t and it has all of our dependencies.
So I actually want to edit this.
I want to delete the stuff that we don't want on our server.
Ok so I mean we could do a nano here.
Let's actually just go into VS code.
So it's going to be Tiare project.
And now we have the requirements dot text.
Ok so I just want to figure out what we need and we don't need so we don't need asteroid we don't need
that or that of course we need Django.
We don't need this or that we need pillow we want these two these two have to do with post-grads don't
need this.
Are these any of this pilot stuff we do want that we don't need six or wrapped.
So basically we just need these as requirements so I'm going to go ahead and save this file.
Now we want to push this to our Get repository.
So what I'll do is go down here and I'll say Get add all.
And then let's say get commit
you say added
requirements file.
OK.
And then we want to push someone to say get push.
All right.
So now if we go back to our Get repository and reload
there's are requirements dot text.
Ok so now what we need to do is on the on the server we need to actually clone this whole application
this whole repository.
So let's go back to our terminal window just closed via code up or minimize it go back to our terminal
and I'm going to go back to the tab where we're actually running our server as Gengel admin inside of
our virtual environment.
So from here we want to do a clone and then actually let's go back to our document here.
And the way that we do that is like this.
OK.
So get clone now using HDDVD here because I don't feel like setting up S-sh keys on my server forget
hub so it's up to you if you want to go through that you can.
But I'm just going to use HGP as that way I can just log in.
So let's see if we're going to go ahead and paste this in.
And you just want to change if you called it bt or a project like I did you just want to keep it like
that but you want to put your user name in here.
So clone that.
So it's going to ask for the user name
K password.
All right so now let's do an LSN PI apps and you can see we have our beat project.
So we have our entire project on our server.
We LS BT are the underscore projects and we take a look at our entire application is here so using get
to deploy to or to bring your files onto a server is just fantastic it's extremely fast and it's much
better than using something like like FGP or something like that.
All right now we need to actually install our requirements our dependencies so if I do a pip freeze
on our server now we're in the virtual environment and I do a pip freeze.
All we have is this package resources we don't have Gengel we don't have any of that stuff.
And like I said we could do Pipp install for all for Django for all of our dependencies.
But since we have that that requirements file we can use that.
So I just want a CD into our project now so BTR the underscore project and this is where I do and last
you'll see we have our requirements dot textfile.
So I'm going to clear this up and I'm going to run Pipp install dash our requirements Daut t t
came for my javascript developers this is like doing in NPM install and having it look at your packages.
JS and vile is virtually the same thing.
So now if we do a Pipp freeze
we have all that stuff installed.
All right so the next thing we need to do is we need to create a local setting's file on our server
because right now we have a setting up PI that has all of our development stuff in it as far as the
database name all that stuff.
And you don't want that to be public.
You don't want your production database credentials to be public especially if this this here is going
to be a public repository like they could easily go into Tiare and settings and they can see your secret
key which is something that you definitely don't want to be exposed.
They could see some other stuff your database which is the most important.
And then we also need to change a couple of things for production like set debug to false allowed hosts.
We need to add our allowed host so to do this.
What we do is we add we have a special settings file on the server and we just basically include it
at the bottom of this file.
So we say if if we're in deployment then add this additional settings these additional settings which
will overwrite databases and secret key and all that stuff.
So that's what we're going to do in the next video.