All right guys so now we want to take care of our settings our local settings set up and if you were
to Google and say Django or all settings is there a documentation page.
Actually I thought there was but maybe not.
Look at this stack overflow file basically.
So we want to create this local settings up pie on our server and have the correct production database
stuff as well as some of the other options as well.
And the way that we do that is in our settings pie.
We want to put this at the end.
And this is basically just saying if this file exists then then bring it in you know use it are included
I should say.
And it's not going to exist on in our repository or anything the only place it's going to exist is on
our actual server.
So that's that's when we want to use it.
And I have that same block of code right here.
So this actually needs to go in our settings and push to our pausa Tory and then pulled into our remote
app.
OK.
So what we're going to do is go into our projects settings file and via's code and go down to the bottom
here and we're going to add that block of code.
So we would just want to do try and then say from Daut local underscore settings that's what we're going
to call the file.
We want to import all.
OK.
And then we just want to put in exceptions so we want to say except on import error then we just want
to pass meaning that if it doesn't find that file just that it's fine just do nothing.
If it does then we want to import it and it's only going to work on the production server because that's
the only place this will exists.
We're not going to create it here.
We're not going to push it to our repository or anything like that.
So let's save this and then we need to actually push this to get.
So we're going to say Get add all get commit let's say added
added
Local Settings import and then get push.
OK so now that we've done that now it's now it's at a good repository we want to go to our remote server
and we want to pull that down.
So make sure you're in your Tiare project and let's do a get Paul.
All right.
So let's check it out.
I'll just do a cat and we'll go into what is it bt r e slash setting's dot PI and there it is down at
the bottom.
Good.
So now it's going to look for that local settings file so we need to actually create it.
And we're only creating it on our local server we're not creating it here on our on our it's actually
it's kind of weird because they call it local settings that's kind of the convention but it's actually
production settings.
And some people do actually call it production or prod settings instead.
But I've noticed that the the common convention is to use local settings like it's you or your local
production server I guess and it can be a little confusing.
But when we say local settings we mean the settings that are on the actual server.
Ok I know it's confusing.
So let's go ahead and CD into BTR eat because if you look that's where the settings dot py file is we
need to create long side of that so we're going to say pseudo Nano.
And let's do local underscore settings dot PI OK and then this is where we want to put any special server
stuff that we don't want in our in our local repository.
I should say our get hub repository.
Anything that anyone can access outside of the server.
So first thing let's let's let's look at the doc the docs here that I created.
We want the secret key the allowed hosts database debug email.
So I'm going to copy from our settings up high end vs code are going to go to the top and grab the secret
key exits grab all of this secret key de-bug and allowed whoas.
So when the copy that I'm going to go back to our terminal and paste that in and we want to do a few
things we want to change a secret key.
Now this can be anything you want.
I'm just going to delete a chunk of this and then just put a bunch of stuff in here like that.
That should be fine.
And then let's go down to debug.
Let's set this to false and we need an allowed hosts the allowed host is going to be our Digital Ocean
IP address which is right here.
We can just copy it.
Yours would be different.
And get a piece that in here OK.
And next thing we need is the database stuff so let's grab that.
So right here.
Copy that
paste that in and then we're going to change this to
see password.
What do they do.
I think I did ABC one to three exclamation user on the server is the admin and the name of the database
is Viti IREY underscore Prod..
Make sure you have your own your settings match and then e-mail your e-mail stuff shouldn't even be
in this file so I should have actually deleted this but I'll just copy it.
Yes I will copy this.
Delete it and save.
And then we're going to have to push and pull again so.
But I'll do that in a second.
Let's finish this up.
So I'll paste that in here.
And of course you'd put your password but Amadi of you I'm not going to do that here.
And that should be it.
So this file looks good.
I'm going to control X and hit y to save.
And then we go and if we do an ls we have our local settings file.
And just to take a quick look
and that's what it looks like.
All right.
So let's just quickly push this to get hubs and say Get add all get commit get comments
removed.
Email from setting's
and push.
All right.
And we'll go back here and we'll go see dot dot to be Tiare project and get Paul
and if if your if this was a production app I would suggest using S-sh keys.
Forget hubs you don't have to keep doing that every time.
But I'm just I'm not even going to bother.
All right so now that we have our local settings OK so we added all this to our local settings in the
next video we're going to start to do all our jingoes stuff.
OK so if we want to create a super user I want to try to run our local host or run our server now to
do that.
We're going to have to allow port eight thousand in our firewall because right now it will be closed
off.
So we need to open that up to allow 8000 thousand.
All right so we'll get to that in the next video.