All right guys so up to this point we have we created our local setting's which is just exclusive to
our server our droplet and we have all the database stuff added one thing are a couple of things I forgot
to add to this document which I just added.
Now you probably didn't see in the last video is we need to actually run our migrations because that's
what's going to create the tables and stuff inside of post-grads.
All right then we need to create a super user just like we did on the local development and then we
need to collect static because any static files that are in subfolder should be taken out and put in
a main static file in the root directory.
OK after that we can just test this out with the default Python server and then we'll move on to Unicorn
and stuff like that.
All right so let's go to our server and we're going to just go ahead and run.
Make sure you're in your BTR project.
We're going to run Python manage dot PI and let's do make migrations.
Now this should actually say that there are no migrations because we shouldn't have any that that that
haven't been ran so we go ahead and do that good.
No changes detected.
So now we actually want to do migrate which is going to create our tables.
OK.
So it's a migrate.
Awesome.
So seeing all these green OK's means that our database is connected correctly.
OK so we have arbitrary Prah database and all the stuff should have went in there and did what it was
supposed to do otherwise you'd have a bunch of read errors.
If you do have a bunch of read errors go into your local settings file that we create and then the last
video and make sure all of the parameters are exact to what you what you did on your remote server they
shouldn't match your local local settings.
All right.
And it should give you some some pretty some pretty clear errors as well.
So I want to clear this up so now that we did our migration let's create a super user so we'll say Python
managed up-I create super user.
OK.
So see I don't want to use Django admin.
I'm just going to use Brad as my super user and email address.
I'll just use Brad at GM now which is not a real email address by the way.
So password Oh do ABC 1 2 3
password is too short.
By-Passed validation is fine.
All right.
So are super users created and then the last thing I want to do here before we open our port and try
to run the server is we need to collect our static files OK so all the static files that are in subfolder
or apps should all be placed into a main static folder and that's what that's going to do.
So it's run Python managed by pie.
Collect static.
OK so 151 static files that's all CSSA all many.
You know javascript images even the admin stuff it's all it's all going to get put in the static folder
now.
In fact if we are less static you'll see even the admin folder isn't there.
All right.
Awesome.
So now let's open our port.
So sudo you have w this is our firewall we want to allow port heat thousand because that's what it runs
on by default.
Excuse me.
And let's try to run our local server.
So Python managed dot PI run server
actually you know what that's wrong.
I'm sorry.
We need to get out of that.
So if we look at the the gist here we actually want to do run server and then 0 0 0 port 8000.
So I'm just going to copy that.
Sorry about that.
Let's go and run it.
All right so now and then I realized that because it said one to 7 it should do.
It should have this 0 0 0.
So now let's take our IP address from Digital Ocean.
Let's go to a new tab and make sure we go to Kolin support eight thousand.
All right guys.
Now one thing I didn't account for is the static files because since since they said debug to false
in our local settings it's basically saying All right well engine X or whatever we use is going to take
care of static files.
So for now I'm going to go back I'm going to escape out of the server here.
And let's let's do pseudo Nano.
And we want to go into local settings which is in the B.T. are the and then local underscore settings
dot pi.
And for now let's set debug to true and hopefully that works so we'll get out of this save it.
Yes and or.
OK.
Now let's run the server again
and reload.
There we go.
OK.
And you know once once we start to implement unicorn and genetics and next will take care of our static
assets.
But for now I'm just going to leave debug to defaults.
OK.
And notice that there's nothing there's no team members there's no listings and that's exactly what
we want.
We didn't want to deploy with that data.
We want to deploy as a as a fresh application.
So that's exactly what we want.
So there's no users Let's check the admin area.
Hopes we don't want to go to listings admin We just want slash admin and let's see.
I used Brad
as our admin area if we go to like listings there's nothing here.
All right.
So that's exactly how it should be right now.
So let's actually add some data we don't have to add everything but let's make sure everything is working.
So we start by adding realtors so it's good to realtors say add new ones.
Good old Kyle Brown and say Choose file and we're going to go to the desktop.
You want to go to your resources.
Images realtors Kayal description.
I'm just going to grab some some dummy text from Lipscombe dot com.
Just generate some text here and I'll grab the loops.
Is that right.
Oh what the heck.
Oh I copied the wrong thing.
And by the way this obviously isn't going to be running on eight thousand.
This is just the default Django server.
We're going to be doing a more professional deployment using engine X and stuff like that.
But for now I just want to test out the functionality.
So phone number.
Email Kayal and we'll say is MVP and then hire date.
Just pick something back here in 2017 and let's save and hopefully this works let's go to the front
end.
So I'm just going to open the site in a new tab.
Let's go to a bow.
There is awesome.
And the picture shows up everything that's being uploaded is going to the media folder.
That's exactly what we want.
So let's add the other realtors since this is real quick so I will say Mark Hudson
piece that in two for us
Will Jenny
OK.
So now let's go back to see.
We'll go to listings
and let's to add listing
and choose Kyle this is going to be 45.
Dr. Woods circle see address.
I'm going to put the same thing
it auto filled for us.
That's cool.
So description not just page Sison price is let's see let's do 490
bedroom's is going to be three bathrooms to grudge two square feet square feet 3 2 9 8 0 and you can
put anything you want here for the mean you guys can just throw some crap in here just to test out.
But you know I just want to have have some some valid and valid looking data for the course.
So lot size to say two point three.
And then let's grab the photos so photo main is going to be in images homes home one OK.
Whoops yeah.
OK.
So photo one is going to be home inside one photo to be home inside to
re
for
five and six.
All right let's save it.
Let's go to our front end here to the home.
OK there's our feature listing.
Let's go to the listings page.
There it is.
More info.
Awesome.
Perfect.
All right.
So I'm just going to add a couple more here.
Let's see.
Let's do the next one let's do Jefferson lane which is Mark.
So it's 18 Jefferson Wayne Wilborn price on this is going to be 55
bedrooms will be four bathrooms two point five garage one square feet let's say 30 100 lot size 1.5
and then pictures let's do home to that's home inside on home too.
And this one will be home inside one home inside too.
And let's do one more.
OK.
So I'll go ahead and save that and now if we go back to the home page now we have our second listing
call.
So let's do one more for now.
So you would do an ad listing and see.
Well do Woodrow street.
So this one will be Jennies so be 1 8 7 wardrobe's tree.
I lost my text
OK so see the price for this one looks to five.
Eighty
bedrooms three bathrooms two two point five garage it's two one square feet will say thirty four hundred
and lots size will save 1.2.
And this is going to be home three for the image and I'll just describe one of the inside images cage
to kind of hurry hurry this along so let's save that reload and there we go.
All right guys so you can see we're logged in here on the front end because we're logged in as Brad
as the admin in the back end so it's going to show that.
OK.
So now what I want to do is obviously we don't want.
I mean if we left it like this we would have to always have the terminal open and you know you don't
want this is not a production way of doing things.
So this is where unicorn comes in where it will constantly serve it on port eight thousand without having
to you know just keep this caught up.
So you know we will be able to get out of this UPS.
I just do.
So we'll be able to get out of this if it lets me it's not letting me some reason.
Control-C.
There we go.
All right.
Geez.
So now you'll see if I go in I reload that's not going to work anymore.
Obviously that's not a good thing.
So that's where unicorn comes in and then we want to set up engine X so we can actually serve it on
port 80 so we don't have to go to Colon 8000.
That way the app will just be on this IP and then the final step is to connect a domain name so we can
actually go to whatever BT real estate dot co.
And it'll pull up our Python application and then we're done.
All right so we're almost there guys like I said in the next video we just check our deployment here
yeah and the next video we're going to start on the unicorn's set up so I'll see you then.