All right guys so up to this point we have our Gengel application running on and Digital Ocean droplet.
Luckily it's not running right now because I stopped the jingoes server but that's how we have it now
is not is definitely not the way that you want to keep it.
It's not it's not production ready just yet.
We need to add a couple of things here.
So we're going to use something called unicorn or green unicorn which will it's a python HGP server
if you want to read more into it you can go to Google Korn dot dot org.
And.
So it's a python w SGI HDP server for Unix.
So we're going to run this.
We're going to let this run our app on eight thousand and then we're also going to put engine X in front
of it later.
OK engine X is a very popular web server and this will allow us to run it on port 80 so we don't have
to go to port eight thousand and so on.
All right so the idea here is to install it then we can actually run it like this.
But that's still not what we're going to.
That's not going to be the end result but we can test it and run it like this.
And then after that we need to actually added some config files on the server and add this stuff to
it.
OK.
And some of this I'll have to change because as you can see I still like Django admin as the user wait
Gengel admin is the user.
What is it that I have to change here.
Actually you know what I don't think I do have to change anything.
So yeah that should be good if I do then I'll change it.
And you guys will have the fresh version.
So let's get started.
I'm going to install unicorn with the Pipp package manager so let's go back here to our server and I'm
logged in as Django admin and I'm in my virtual environment so I'm going to say Pipp install Goonan
Korn
OK.
That was quick and then I have right here we want to add it to our requirements task because that file
holds all the dependencies everything that this application needs to run is in there so we should we
should put this in there so it's WIPs.
Let's go back to our terminal and let's say Pipp freeze.
And we want this.
We want to add this to requirements Dot T x t OK.
So once we do that let's take this line here and this should actually run our server but we may not
see any static files images stuff like that.
So let's try to run it and see what we get.
And notice that this BT Arri this is whatever the name of your your inner folder is so we have BTR the
project is our main project and then BT IREY is the main the main file.
This is where the WS G-I dot PI file is OK so we're going to run that and it looks like it's working.
So let's try and go to our IP.
So it's going to copy our IP address as you will obviously be different than mine.
I still want to go to port 8000 and there we go OK.
So with all these images are showing but you can see that we're missing some some assets here.
So we have to fix that.
So if we go back to our document here we want to stop the server and then we want to deactivate the
virtual environment.
OK so let's go back let's go ahead and stop this and to deactivate we simply say de-activate case.
Now notice that the van is now gone from the front of this so we know we're not in our environment anymore.
So we need to open up this file and this is going to corncobs socket file.
So I'm just going to copy this.
I'm going to make this smaller and we're going to go ahead and paste this in.
Whoops it didn't copy correctly.
All right.
So this is actually going to create this goon corn dog socket file.
And we want to grab this right here.
I want to grab these lines and these all come from that digital lotion article.
We want to save this so I'm going to do a control x yes and then enter.
So that should be saved.
Then we want to open this file this caught guna cornets service so we'll grab that and paste that in.
We're going to copy this.
All right.
Now if you didn't use if you didn't use these paths this path right here Home Django admin if this isn't
your user name actually put your correct username if you didn't you know make sure that this path goes
to your project.
Mine is and PI aps and then Bakhtiari projects.
Same thing here.
This should actually go to your van.
So wherever your Vende folder is and then it goes into been going on it will actually create that that
folder.
And then I think that's that's it.
You want to use B.T. area whatever your folder is.
Just show you real quick so whatever this folder is OK.
If you've been following along then it's going to be Tiare.
All right.
And notice that's where the W SGI file is.
Remember I told you that that has to do with hosting.
So you know C or your application is available on the Internet.
All right.
So this should be good.
Let's go ahead and control X and you know I'll be honest with you I don't know what a lot of this stuff
actually does but I know that we have to do it.
So now we just want to start and enable the unicorn socket.
So I'm going to copy this run that command.
Copy this.
So just keep this file as a resource.
So this created the symlink.
All right.
Then we can check the status if we want
all right and you'll notice that it's active it's listening.
OK so the unicorn socket is now listening.
Check the existence of the Unicorn starts sock.
OK good so everything looks looks good.
Up to this point.
So I mean if you get any errors here.
Just make sure that you created this exact these exact files.
Make sure that your configuration looks the exact same.
I would really like to find the Digital Ocean article.
There's just so many of them like there's there's probably like 15 different Django engine acts unicorn
configuration articles.
See let's say a buntu 18 18.00 for Django and genetics.
Digital Ocean.
So is this series here.
Yes yes this is.
This is exactly the article that all of this stuff comes from.
You can see that re-installed all this stuff logged into post-grads
see where is it.
But this is for a new project you can see this is for creating a new Django project
just trying to look for the configuration
right here so this is what we just did.
We created this unicorn socket.
This is the code that we put in.
We created this service
we didn't actually oh yeah we did.
This is just part of this file.
So this is what the final thing should look like and that's what we did.
OK.
And then checking for the unicorn socket We did that everything looked good.
All right.
So now we want to work on engine X so down here you can see configure engine X to proxy pass to unicorn.
OK so basically engine X sits up front on port 80 and then it passes it off to Gounod corn which runs
on eight thousand I believe.
All right so that's we'll do in the next video is start to configure and genetics.