All right guys so now we're going to set up engine X..
And this is going to be pretty easy.
There's not too much to do here.
So we want to create a project folder.
So we want this.
And next sites available Tiare project.
So we're going to do pseudo Nano and then that OK which is actually a file.
And we want to add this stuff into it.
OK this whole server Block.
And basically what we're doing is we're listening on port 80.
We want to put our IP address in here so whatever your Digital Ocean droplet addresses you want to grab
that.
OK make sure you put your own.
So just delete this and let's paste in that IP address.
And then this is just the option to add a fab icon we want.
This is going to load our static folder.
And this is going to load our media folder and then down here we're just proxying this June Gogg unicorn
soc service.
OK so let's go ahead and save this.
Oh yes.
All right.
Now one thing I want to do is set the debug value that we have back to false because remember we set
it to true just to deal with the static assets with the regular jingoes server.
So let's go ahead and say sudo in the VTR folder we want local underscore settings dot PI forgotten
a..
OK we're going to set this debug value to false
and let's save this.
Good.
OK.
So let's go back to our document here.
So we have this all in that file.
Now we need to enable the file by linking the sites enabled directory.
So I want to take our project and link this sites and enabled.
So I'm going to just grab this and paste it in and mine.
I'm going to have a file exists because I actually already did this off camera but you shouldn't see
this message it'll just go down to the next line.
So let's save.
I mean let's clear this.
That's so I mean we can check our engine X installation or config.
And I do.
OK so everything looks OK.
Now we want to restart engine X. So I'll just say sudo system CTO and we want to restart engine X. So
now we have to set up our firewall now.
Remember earlier we allowed port 8000 and we don't want that anymore.
We don't want people to access port 8000 from the outside but we do want people to access port 80 and
we can just use this engine next fall so we want to run both of these let's say sudo.
We're going to take our firewall.
So UFW and we're going to delete the allow rule that we added for port eight thousand.
OK.
And then at the same time we want to take our firewall also UFW and we want to allow them we can put
a string in here of engine X fall and we'll know exactly what to add.
So that's that next thing.
I mean we could we could probably run the server now or the server is running but we could probably
visit the Web site and so on.
But if we try to upload an image it's too big.
We're going to get an error because we want to increase the client Max body size within the next Khant
file.
So I'm going to just copy this.
So we're going to go into that file.
We're going to go down into the H block and we're just going to add
and add that client Max body size.
So client underscore Max body size we're going to see that 20 meg.
OK.
And make sure you put a semi-colon and that should do it.
So let's go ahead and control X and save and then we're going to restart engine next.
And we should be good.
I believe so.
Let's go ahead and check it out.
So grab our IP address no port 8000 this time engine X is running on port 80 So that's the default HDP
port.
So I'm going to just go ahead and paste the IP address in and there we go.
Now you're probably going to have the listings that you added earlier.
I actually ended up deleting them earlier and I I would suggest to do the same.
So going to slash admin because you might have some issues with the media files so you know go to listings
delete go to realtors delete them all.
And also I'd suggest deleting the photos folder in the media folder in the media not.
And so if we do an ls in our projects we have a media folder and if we do an ls media we have a photos.
So what I would suggest doing is deleting the photos folder because once you upload photos they'll automatically
it will automatically create that directory.
So let's say pseudo our AM and then we want to add the dash R.F. flag.
OK since there's there's actual content in the folder and we're going to do media slash photos and cards
now for doing LS media.
There's nothing in it.
So we've cleared all the all the data all of the photos and now we'll go ahead and try to upload some
stuff.
All right so let's go to realtors first and I'm not going to add everything I'm just going to add.
You know a couple of Realtors and a listing and we'll test it out.
So it's a name Kyle Brown let's choose images.
Realtors Kyle Kyle is a great guy shoes.
Number here he male will make MVP and save.
Good.
Now let's go to the front end of the site and if we go to a bow there is
Denmark is also great.
All right cool.
So now let's do a listing.
Let's see Kyle and Stu 45 driveway jumps to 45 drive would circle
say great house with poor
the 550 bedrooms.
Negative One that's not going to work.
Three two one.
Thirty one hundred.
Doesn't matter what you put here.
OK let's grab from the homes fold there.
I'm going to grab home one
inside grab a couple and save K. let's go home.
There's our listing here.
And we have smaller images.
Awesome.
So everything seems to be working here.
So in the next video where I want to do is connect this to a domain name because obviously we don't
want this as our address.
Nobody's going to remember this.
So we want to be able to go to Beati real estate dot co.
And I actually registered that domain name for the purpose of this course.
So we're going to get into that next.