All right guys.
Now we're going to get into the domain set up and there's actually a couple of ways you could do this
you could do this through digital ocean.
You can use their name servers.
What I'm going to do is just simply add an A record in my domain panel and for the IP address for Digital
Ocean and C name record for the domain and then we need need to just add the the domain to our allowed
hosts.
We also want to add it to our BTR project file in the engine X configuration.
So this should be pretty easy.
I'm not sure how long it's going to take to propagate.
They can take up to like 24 hours sometimes.
So what I'll do is we'll do the work now and then I'll just wait a little while and then come back once
it's done.
But yeah I'm going to go to name cheap that's where I have my domain registered.
Obviously I know that there's a ton of different registers and you may use someone different but all
the interfaces are pretty similar.
So again keep in mind BT real estate dot coing going to go to advanced DNS and what you want to do is
add an A record.
OK so I'm going to say add new record a record.
And for those who want to do at the IP address is going to be our Digital Ocean droplet IP address.
We're going to grab that and going to piece that right in there and click the checkbox.
OK then I'm going to say ad See name record.
The host is going to be w w w and I want to point that to the actual domain which is going to be BT
real estate dot co.
And hit the check button.
All right.
And the stuff up here.
I'm actually going to delete on any of that.
I just want the record and see name.
All right so now let's go to our terminal and just like the the document says we want to add to the
allowed host.
So I'm going to say pseudo nano VTR e slash local underscore settings dot pi.
And we want to go down to a loud hostes
and put a comma here.
OK we want to put the non WW version first.
And then let's also put the WDW version.
All right.
And then I'm going to save this and exit and then we also want to add it to our engine Ex-Files so can
grab this right here let's do pseudo nano paste that in
and see what am I doing.
Server name.
So right after server name I put a space in to save BT real estate.
Obviously your domain will be different.
And then also the w w w version.
Right.
So let's save this and next thing we'll do is just restart and X and unicorn.
All right.
And now I'm going to go open up a new tab and go to Beati real estate dot co.
There we go.
Awesome.
Feature the listings for
you know we didn't try to register a user.
Let's do that let's check the E.W. version as well so we don't do it.
Good.
That works.
So let's register a user just to test this so we'll see.
Tom Smith Tom G-mail dot com
register
Tom
awesome.
Now I'm actually going to disable the e-mail functionality in production because we don't have each
DDP as and when you're in production you should use something like postfix or Centigrade or something
like that.
And I think that's beyond the scope of this tutorial.
So what I'm going to do.
I mean you could submit it now but you get a 500 hour and it would go through like in the back end but
the email wouldn't send.
So there's a couple extra things you need to do for that and I might create another video touching on
that later on.
But for now I'm just going to disable the e-mail so I'm going to go back to my VS code and I'm going
to go to let's see.
I want to go to contacts we used up high and I'm simply going to comment this Pardot right here the
sendmail.
All right so we'll comment that out and save and then I'm going to push this.
So do a get one and it had all say good commit
and it's say disable email and then get push and then we'll go to our server.
And let's do a get Paul.
Make sure you're in your BTR project.
All right.
So we're going to reload.
Engine X. So sudo system see T.L. restart engine X..
All right so now let's go back to our application here as Tom and let's go to a list go to our listing
and make an inquiry.
So our stuff is already in here by default because they're logged in.
We'll send it in success your request has been submitted.
And let's go to the back end.
So we want to go actually let's check our dashboard first.
OK so there it is and we'll go to the admin.
We get a log in is Brad
and contacts and there is Tom Smith.
Good.
OK so everything is working except for like I said the production e-mail.
That's something I may look into an ad later on.
But other than that we're in good shape so we can log out here and that's it.
So hopefully you guys enjoyed this course.
I know it was it was kind of long in and you know it's long for one project usually have in courses
you have a couple of small projects but I wanted to do something that's a little larger from start to
finish so I really hope you guys enjoyed it.
I hope you learned a lot about Django and how to create applications and hopefully you can start to
create some of your own.
So thanks I really truly appreciate that especially if you made it this far and hopefully I'll see you
in my next course.