All right guys so now we're moving on to the contacts part of the inquiry's part of this.
This Gengel project so we need to create an app called contacts so when we go down to my terminal here
make sure you're in your virtual environment and we're going to run Python
managed up high and we want to do start up and we're going to call this contacts.
So now over here you can see that we have a new folder called contacts all the standard stuff inside
of it.
And I think the first thing that we should do here is create our model OK because this is going to have
its own model so let's open this up and let's create a class called contact that's our model name and
we need to pass in models Daut model and Colin and then we want to put our fields so we're going to
have listing and listing is going to be a character field so we're going to say char field and let's
give it a max length.
And let's do max length 200.
OK I'm not going to do our relationship here between the contact and listing because we don't really
need to.
All I really want is just the title of the listing and also the listing ID.
So we're going to do listing ID and that's going to be an integer field so models dot integer field
K that we want to name.
So this will be the contact name UPS models dot.
This will also be char field.
And let's do max say max length and let's do 200.
All right.
And then I'm going to copy this down.
Let's do two more down.
And this one both of these are going to be max length of one hundred.
This is actually going to be the email on the phone.
So say e-mail
and phone OK so the next thing is going to be the message
and message is going to be a text field K and message is going to be optional so we're going to do blank
equals true meaning that it can be blank.
So it's optional.
And then let's do contact underscore date and we're going to set that to date.
Sorry.
Models dot let's do date time field and I want to put a default in here and I want to set the default
to date
time do it now.
And in order to use the time we have to bring that in so we're going to say from date time imports date
time.
So default now and then I'm also going to add blank true to this.
So it's a blank and set that equal to true.
And then we want also want the user ID.
Now this user ID is going to be connected to whatever registered users logged in when they make an inquiry.
So let's say models dot will do integer field and I'm actually going to set this to blank equals true
because when someone makes an inquiry they may not be logged in.
OK so we don't want inquiry forms to only be available to people that are logged in.
However if they are logged in we want to track that user ID so that we can show their inquiries on their
dashboard.
Now the last thing we're going to do here is define and we're going to say double underscore to your
double underscore.
And then we want to pass in the self.
And this is the basically the main field we want to refer to for contacts and that's going to be named
so we're going to do self-taught name and that's it.
That's our model.
Now we're going to have we we want to put a table in the database for our contacts so we need to create
a migration.
All right.
So let's go down here to our terminal and we're going to say Python
managed our pie make migrations contacts
app contacts cannot be found.
All right.
So I think I've said this a couple times throughout the course I always forget to put my new apps in
the installed apps list in the settings so let's go to our settings page or settings PI and go up to
installed apps.
I wish that they would just somehow make it so that these got added automatically because I just can't
seem to remember to put them in.
So this is going to be contacts config and we want to change this to contacts.
All right.
So let's save that and let's try this again.
So we're going to run make make migrations with on the contacts app.
I sort of look at that model and will create a migration file so you can see it's created in contacts
it's created in the migrations folders 001 dot initialled dot pi.
Now to run this we need to do Python
managed up-I because right now we just have that the migration file it has actually ran so it hasn't
created the database table.
So now we just simply say migrate and we get.
OK so if we want to double check that we can go to PGE admen and probably going to have to log back
in here because it's been a while.
And you don't have to use PGE admin if you want to log into your shell your PSU all shall That's fine
as well.
So if we go to databases and be Tiare DBI schemas public tables and there it is contact's underscore
contact.
All right good.
So we know that that worked.
So I think we're all set here and the models are going to close that up and in the next video what I
want to do is I want to register our model with our admin area so that we can actually see our contacts
in the admin and we're also going to customize the table a little bit.
All right.
So we'll do that in the next video.