All right guys so in the last video we went ahead and created our contacts app we created our model
and we ran the migration.
So now we actually have a contacts database table.
Now we're going to go to the admin dot pie here because we want to register our contact model so that
we can actually see them in the admin area.
So let's go ahead and bring in we'll say from Daut models.
Want to import contact and let's do class contact admin and pass in the admin Daut model admin and then
we can do our customisations here and then after that we want to run it through admin dot site dot
register pass in the name of the model contact and then the name of the class which is contact admin.
OK so in here as far as customisations Let's do our list display so we've done this before with other
models.
Solist display I'm going to do.
ID.
ID let's do name let's do listing.
OK so that will be the actual listing name email and contact date.
And if you want to change any of these up feel free to do that.
Snellius do list display links.
Which ones do we want to actually be links and I just want to do ID and name OK let's do search fields
so search fields I'm going to do name
email and listing
and then finally let's do list per page.
And that's going to be 25.
Just like the rest.
And that's it.
I'm not going to do anything crazy here so let's save that.
And now we go to our back end.
We're going to have to log in reload this we have to log in as Bradd or whatever your admin user is.
And let's go to our home and now we see contacts if we click on that we don't have any contacts obviously.
Now you can add them from here if you want but I really don't know why you would do this.
I guess maybe a few If like you talked to.
If the company if someone from the company talked to someone outside of the Web site like in real life
and then they wanted to add their information into the admin area I guess they could do it this way.
But for the most part the contacts that are going to be listed here they're going to come from that
inquiry form on in the application.
So that's that's really what this is for.
So I'm not going to go out I'm not going to add any contacts through here.
I just wanted to go ahead and add that those customisations for the admin area.
All right so in the next video what I want to do is prepare our inquiry form.
So this right here when I say make an inquiry I want to do a few things here we need to change this
because this is just hard coded right now or just just static each time.
Now I also want to put the name in the email of the logged in user if they're logged in I want I want
that information in there as well as some hidden fields so I want to prepare this form in the next video
and then we'll move on to actually submitting it and and getting that data into the database.
OK so I'll see you in the next video.