All right guys what I want to do in this video is prepare our inquiry form or our contact form.
So that's going to be in our templates and then in listings in listing aged him well.
OK so it's at the bottom this inquiry motile here.
And there's quite a bit that we need to do here.
First thing I'm going to start with is the form tag.
So we need to add an action to this.
Now we haven't created any or else yet for contacts but we will.
So I'm going to put in here.
Let's say you are Arel and will just say contact
OK.
We also want to make sure that this is a post form so we want to say method equals post and we have
a post form in Django we want to make sure that we secure it with our CSR token
and then this property here is just static.
So I just want to replace this with our listing name member in the listing but each team file where
we passed the listing in so we have access to all the fields of a listing.
We also have access to the user stuff.
So if the if the user is logged in I actually want to send the user id as a hidden input field because
we're going to need that.
So let's go where should we go to go right under the token right here.
And let's put an if statement.
So say if user dot is underscore authenticated and I just want to put an else here as well.
OK then we need it.
And if so if the users authenticate I'm going to put a hidden input and say input hidden the name's
going to be user underscore
ID.
And then the value is going to be user dot ID now.
Else if then the user isn't authenticated I'm still going to send this input.
OK I'm still going to send it but I'm going to set the value to zero OK.
And this is just going to make things easier for us on the other side when we handle the submission.
So I also want to send along a couple of other things I want to send the e-mails.
The e-mail of the realtor and the listing I.D. And the reason I want to send the email is because I
want to send her an e-mail when there's a new submission so we're going to go right under the def.
OK this shouldn't be in the conditional and we want to put an input case is going to be hidden again
and name for this is going to be real to her underscore.
Email in the value k so the value is going to be listing dot.
Realtor can remember since the relationship between a real turn of listing.
We can get any fields from the realtor model and we want that email so we can do that at the same time
and want to get the listing ideas as a hidden input some going to copy this down and I'm going to change
this to listing underscore ID and of course we can do listing dot ID for that.
OK so now it's Hindle the name in the e-mail.
If the users logged in I actually want the value to display as their name and their e-mail.
So let's go to I want to be in the input.
I'll go right after the class.
And right before the required here and let's put an if statement in here.
Case and say if user dot is
authenticated and I'm going to put the end
and if so if these are authenticated then I'm going to put a value attribute and that value attribute
is going to be equal to user dot.
What is this e-mail.
Does the e-mail.
No this is the name so user dot name.
OK we want to do the same thing for the e-mails I'm going to copy this whole if statement.
Go right here for the e-mail pasted in and I'm just going to change this to use your dot.
Email.
Why is this discolored.
That's weird sit like that up here to
class form control that yeah that should still work.
It's just a VS code thing.
So it is at it that's it.
So at the bottom input types have.
Good.
All right.
So let's save this.
And first thing let's see if we have any errors.
So if I reload the page we do reverse contact not found.
So basically the reason we're getting this error is because there is no u r l with the name of contacts
so what we're going to do is in our contacts app just like we've been doing with just about every other
app we want to create a you or.
Py file.
And in this file We're only actually going only going to have one u r l and that's for the submission.
So let's just quickly say from Django Daut you are Elle's we want to import path and let's bring in
our views so from all import views and then we want to do our u r l patterns
K and we just want one path here and path.
I'm going just going to make it.
Let's see what are we going to do here let's say contact
contact and that's going to go to views Daut contact.
And let's say name equals
contact.
Now just like with any other u r l file we have to basically include it in the main you or else PI and
we're getting this error because there's no contact method.
Well we'll add that in a second.
But let's go to Tiare or els and we're just going to do what we did with the rest of these it's going
to copy this down.
And this will be contacts.
It's going to go to contacts.
Elves.
All right.
So I'll save that and let's create our view method so we'll go to our contacts app and then used up
PI and let's say define
contact pass in our request and for now let's just return save that and that should get rid of the error
in the dot pi if I resave it.
There we go.
All right so now let's make sure that we have no errors 3 load and good if we make an inquiry.
So the correct listing is in here 33 x x circle.
Actually though I'm logged in.
OK so it has the email but it's not showing the name.
Why is it not showing name at all.
The reason is it's not showing the name is because the user doesn't have a name it has a first name
and a last name.
So we want to go down to where we tested right here in the input and we put user name we're actually
going to put user dot first name space
user dot last name.
Let's try that.
So now if I reload and we make an inquiry.
Hope that didn't work either
oh you know it didn't work because Brad the user Brad doesn't have a first and last name.
If we go to users and we look at Brad there's no first and last name so that's actually fine.
Let's try to log in as Cathy and see what works you with happens.
Because for the first name a last name it's not required.
So if we go to a listing and make an inquiry there we go.
Cathy Smith.
Good.
So in the next video we're going to start to handle the submission.
So I'll see you then.