All right guys so now that we have prepared our form are in Korea contact form now we need to handle
the submission or start to handle the submission.
So if we look at our contacts folder here contacts app you are Elle's of one path and that's contact.
And then that's linked to this method here.
So we just want to first of all make sure that it's a POST request.
So we're going to do if
request Daut method is equal to post.
But our colon here then for now all I want to do is let's see what we do let's just do a print and we'll
just say hello and we'll just return just so we know that the form is actually submitting.
So my server here once I submit the form we should see how.
So I'm going to just go back there and reload and make an inquiry.
Kathy's information is in there because we're logged in as her it's just send.
All right.
So the view contact's view did not return.
That's fine because we didn't all we did is return or we didn't return the HDTV HDP response.
I just want to check the console and there it is.
Hello.
So we know that this is submitting and it is in fact a post request.
All right so.
So back to the terminal here and let's continue on.
So if it is a POST request then what do we want to do.
We want to capture the fields right just like we've been doing.
So let's get the listing ID and the listing ID was that hidden field that we put But we fetch it the
same way.
Doesn't matter if it's a hidden field or textfield whatever it is we use requests dot post and then
whatever we named it which was listing ID.
All right we're going to do the same thing for the other fields.
So let's do see two three four five six seven eight fields here.
So the next one is just going to be the listing basically the listing title.
Then we have the name the contact names is going to control D and change both of these to name.
Next we have the e-mail.
So I'm going to control de-select the next one e-mail and then we need phone
message.
OK message use your ID
and then we want the realtor email
OK.
So we do have some issues here but this should have nothing to do with that error but we'll fix it anyway
so messages we didn't bring that in.
So up at the top here I'm going to do from
Django Daunt contrib.
They want to import messages.
Redirect comes in from shortcuts so we'll just add a redirect and save.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is I just want to see if that actually went through.
So I'm going to log in as Brad
and we'll go to contacts.
OK.
So that did not go through.
So let's try this again.
I mean I still think we're going to get the same error but we'll try it just send that in you're still
getting that error.
So it's on listing.
So we're getting listings listing equals post request listing.
Let's go to the template which is listing dot aged him out and go down to our form and see listing is
right here.
And you know what I think it's because we have a disabled so let's actually remove the disabled
and I'm going to go ahead and I'm actually going to log out and log in as Kathy.
OK so success.
So let's go to a listing make an inquiry.
I'll say I'm interested.
This Home Page Not Found.
All right.
OK.
So I know I know the issue here.
This should be listings slash.
So that's no problem and it looks like everything should have gone through with just the redirect that
messed up.
So if I go back and we reload we have to log in as Brad because he's a super user or admin whatever.
And we should see there she is Cathy Smith So we have the listing the email on the contact date.
If we click on that you'll see the rest of the stuff here.
So the listing I.D. the phone number her message Date user ID and so on.
Good.
So we just want to go back and change in views dot pie.
We want to change this to listings slash listing ID.
That way it will actually redirect to the correct place.
So let's actually log out of the front end and go back and log out and let's make an inquiry.
So I'll just say like Tom Smith
you know leave the message blank.
OK so success your request has been submitted and this is it just redirects us back to the correct listing
the one that we were on.
And if we go back and go to our contacts which I have to log in is Brad
there is Tom Smith.
I didn't realize he used the same last name.
All right.
So we're now able to submit inquiries whether you're logged in or not.
So in the next video I want to I want to make it so that if the user is logged in and they try to make
inquiry on proper the property that they already have it's going to tell them they've already made that
inquiry.
All right.
So Kathy logs in and does another inquiry on this home.
She's going to get a message saying there's already an inquiry.
All right so we'll do that next.