All right guys so our submission for the contact form is going through but there's a couple more things
you want to do.
I want to make it so that if the authenticated user has already sent to an inquiry that they get a message
saying they've already sent it and then I also want to add the functionality of e-mail I want to send
whoever the realtor email is I want to send them an email notifying them that there's been a submission.
So let's start off with telling the user that they've already had eight inquiries so we're going to
go right here let's say check if user has made
inquiry already.
So we're first going to just say if I request dog user dog and then we want to use that is authenticated
OK.
So if they're authenticated then we want to get.
We're going to say user ID equals request dot user dot ID.
All right.
And then after that I'm going to say has underscore contacted and said that to our contact model and
then objects dot all and then I want to filter can I want to filter I'm going to say listing underscore
ID equals listing underscore ID because I want to check for the current listing and the current user.
So user underscore ID equals user underscore ID.
OK.
And then right under that we're going to do it if we're going to check that has contacted.
So if has contacted We want to send an error message some messages dot error
and we'll just say you have already made an inquiry for this listing and then we'll redirect back to
the same listing.
So I'm just going to copy this redirect down here put that there.
Make sure it's on the same line.
OK.
So let's go ahead and save that and let's give it a shot.
So let's go back and let's reload.
So I want to log in as Kathy because she already made a list.
What is she called it 20 Giffard Street So Kathy then two three four five six.
All right Snel Let's go to that Giffard story and let's try to make an inquiry.
Guys I'm just going to send.
And there we go you've already made an inquiry for this listing.
So let's try it let's go to another one.
Make sure we can make them to make an inquiry to one we haven't actually done yet.
And that works so if we go to the admin area we're going to have to re log in as Brad
and she has one for 12 united.
But notice that she doesn't have to for 28 Giffard street so prevented that from happening.
So there's no way to prevent an unregistered user from making multiple inquiries on the same on the
same property unless you add like IP tracking and stuff like that but we're not going to get into that.
We just want to make sure that logged in users don't don't make double inquiries.
All right cool so now let's do the e-mail stuff.
So we go to Django.
So say Django email and right here the sending email documentation what we need to do is is pretty simple
we just bring in send e-mail from Gengel call our mail.
We simply run sendmail we put the subject the message from e-mail any two e-mails fail silently so that
the false will use the default.
So you have to do that.
And then in the settings we have to add some stuff as well.
I don't know if it should be on this page.
We have to add like our e-mail server and stuff like that.
And I'm just going to be using G-mail.
Yes so these are the the variables we need like e-mail host e-mail port things like that.
So I'm going to show you how to use it with G-mail.
OK.
And let's go it's got our settings.
So we're going to go to be Tiare settings up PI and go all the way down to the end and let's do e-mail
config.
So I want to say e-mail underscore host.
So our host since using Gmail is going to be s m t p dot G-mail dot com and we want the poor.
So it's a e-mail underscore poort and that's going to be 5 8 7 depending on your S-M T.P. server whoever
you are using this port may be different than you want your user.
So email underscore host underscore user.
All right.
I'm actually going to do this off camera but you want to put your Gmail user and then e-mail underscore
host underscore password and you want to put your Gmail password and then we want to set email.
The e-mail underscore use underscore last.
And we're going to set that to true.
So those should be the only options that we need here in order to use Gmail.
So I'm going to save this.
And then let's go to views dot PI and we need to figure out where we want to put this and that's going
to be I'm going to do it right after we save because I only want the email to be sent out if it's saved
if we put it up here and something goes wrong.
I don't want the email to be sent.
So we actually need to bring this in up top so let's say go right here and we'll say from Django dot
core dot mail.
We want to in poor send email OK.
So see I think you should be good here.
Let's go down here.
Let's do send underscore mail all right and this is going to get a few things so that the message or
the I'm sorry the subject I'm going to say property listing inquiry
and then we want the body which I'm just going to keep very simple I'm going to say look we want quotes
here.
I'm going to say there has been
an inquiry for and then I'm going to just concatenate the listing K which is like the listing title.
You could put this in the subject if you want as well.
So put like this to a period and then a space and we'll say sign into the admin panel for more info
and you can construct this and make this a lot more in-depth if you want but that's going to be our
body.
Next thing we need is the the from address which is going to be the the the address we set up for S-M
T.P. which is going to be our Google.
And let's just put it in here it's a junky mail anyway.
Anyway so mine is going to be traversed dot Brad at G.M. dot com.
So that that that is what would go right.
Here's the user
that OK.
Obviously you want to put your password in.
Let's see so the next thing we want is we want to put in an array or a list I should say of of e-mail
addresses that you want that you want these to get sent to.
Now what I want to do is use the realtor email right here.
So we're going to take that and put that in there and then I also I'm going to send to one of my e-mail
addresses so I can check it so I'm going to say.
Tech Guy info at G-mail dot com OK.
So just so I can check to make sure it works.
And then we're going to do our fail silently equals falls.
OK so it'll show us some error error messages if something goes wrong.
All right.
So I think I think that's it.
So I'm what I'll do is I'll save this and then let's see off screen I'll put my password in and then
we'll test it.
So I'm just going to pause for a second put my password in then we'll go and test it.
All right so I put my password into the settings and everything should be OK.
So I'm going to actually just send in a submission I'm not logged in.
That doesn't matter though and it's put something in here so I'll just say like Jack say Jack Williams
dot com.
And let's just send that
OK.
So your request has been sent.
If we go to the back end was going to log in again.
So there's Jack Williams.
Now I'm going to check my e-mail so I'm actually just going to pull a tag tab off the screen for a second
and just check it out.
OK.
So there it is.
I don't really want to show you guys like my whole inbox I'm going to click on it and then I'm going
to bring it over.
OK so we get property listing inquiry.
And this was not in my spam box it was righton G-mail and has the from e-mail address which is the the
the Gmail privacy dot.
And in here you can see it also went to Kayal at Beati real estate Daco which is not a valid email address
but that's what is in.
That's the e-mail address that Kyle has in the system.
So that's who it goes to.
So you don't it's not like it just goes to one master e-mail address.
I mean you could do that but we're actually having a go to that specific realtors e-mail address.
OK.
So like Mark or Jenny they wouldn't get the e-mail because it's not their listing.
OK makes sense and it says there has been an inquiry for 12 United road sign into the admin panel for
more so whatever the listing is will be put here and you could put that in the subject if you want as
well.
All right cool.
So that's all working so we can make inquiries.
It goes into the database and not only that an e-mail gets sent as well.
All right so that's going to be at.
That's going to be it for this video guys.
I will see you in the next one.