All right guys so we're just about there now what I want to do is make this dashboard dynamic because
right now it's just static each time out.
So we're going to head into VS code and open up the Tiare project and I'm just going to close all of
these up and where we want to go now is accounts and it's going to views up PI and then down the bottom
we have our dashboard which right now is just rendering each time all file.
Let's open up that as well.
And in our views dot pi we need to basically just reach in and get the contacts or the inquiries of
a certain user.
So and at that users obviously the logged in user which we can get by using request dot user.
OK so that's that's something that is available to us.
So right here I'm going to say user underscore contacts and going to set that to the contact model which
we bring in.
No we didn't.
So we need to bring in the contact model.
So say from the contacts app dot models we want to end poor contact.
All right.
I also want to bring in messages so it's too.
Oh we already did.
Mine.
OK so down at the bottom here we're going to use the contact model and we want to fetch.
So we're going to say objects Daut and I want to do order by OK order underscore by and we're going
to do a hyphen and then contact data because we want the most recent first and then we need to filter
because right now it's just going to give us all of the contacts we want to filter by the user.
So we want to say filter the user ID is the field we want to filter and we want we want to add here
request using that request object which includes the current logged in user.
And we want the ID perps we want to do dot ID.
So this should match.
OK so any any user ID that has the logged in users ID that's what we want.
Those are the contacts we want.
And then right here I'll go ahead and put in a context dictionary and we'll set contacts to say user
contacts and then here we just want to pass in our context.
Good.
Now let's go to our dashboard dot each team now and let's check this out.
So
I'm noticing that we have about Beati real estate.
That's not right.
So we want to change that.
Someone in chains is to use their dashboard
and for this tax rate here I'll just say manage your
BT real estate.
OK.
And if you wanted to add more dashboard functions later on you could do that.
So let's see the breadcrumb that looks good.
We do have home about.
That doesn't make much sense.
Let's let's actually make this the active I mean not the active.
This is going to be the active which is going to be dashboard.
I must not have changed this stuff.
I may change this in yours so you may not have to do this.
OK so dashboard and then home.
All right good.
That's fine.
So down here.
Let's see if we have welcomed John.
Obviously we don't want John for everybody so we're going to change this to be dynamic.
So remember we passed in well we didn't pass in user users just available to us so we'll say user Daut
first underscore name and that's the beauty of this of Django is you can use this user object anywhere.
So here are the property listings that you've inquired about.
That's good.
So right now it's just in each team all tables is a static table.
Why I'm going to do is keep just the first table row and I'm going to delete the rest of them.
OK these other two.
And then we want to wrap a for loop around this.
OK.
So actually we'll do it.
We'll do an if statement first.
We should probably do the if before we even do.
Yeah we'll put the F right under the welcome actually.
So we want to check for contacts so if contacts k then we're going to want all this.
I'm just going to Tab this all over and see where it is and just I guess just the paragraph in the table
will tab over and then right here we're going to put in the else
OK so else.
And then we want it and if
so if there are no contacts let's just say paragraph rules say you have not made any
inquiries.
Now if there are contacts who are going to do all this but we want to loop through them and output each
one is a table row.
So I'm going to wrap this in a for loop.
So let's say for contact in contacts and down here going to
and for a tab this over and change these two dynamic values.
So the soby contact dot ID.
This is going to be the listing title which is going to be under contact dot listing and then view listing.
We want to change this graph to you RL
listing and then we also it needs an ID to go to which can we can get from contact dot listing underscore
ID.
All right so that should work let's save it.
Let's go back and now we're logged in as Cathy if I reload.
Looks like I have an HMO error here on the CD somewhere right here.
OK fix that.
And now we can see all of the listings that that copy is made.
And we can view those listings as well.
All right cool.
So if we were to do another one like let's say this one here make an inquiry.
Just send it in.
All right.
And we go back to our dashboard now we can see that listing.
Awesome.
So I think that we're done guys I think that we have our application so we can manage listings we can
manage realtors.
OK realtors are shown on the About page of our Selar of the month of our search functionality should
still work.
So if we say nor would submit that still works surge for let's say whether we have Lexington.
So the search form that should work.
We have our dashboard we have our authentication latest listings everything is good.
We have our customization for our back end for admin area.
Recent actions we can manage users groups contacts listings and realtors.
All right.
So I think that now at this point we would hand the client the application for testing and what we would
do some more testing ourselves and then hand it to them they could test it out see if it fits what they
want.
Obviously if they wanted some changes they could come back and we can make some revisions and stuff
like that.
But I think that we're good to go.
All right so now what we're going to do is pretend we got the sign off from the client and we now need
to deploy this application to the Internet.
So that's what we're going to do in the next section.