All right guys so we're going to create our first app in Django.
OK.
So again apps you have you have multiple apps per project.
This is going to be the pages app which is going to take care of displaying the home page and the About
page and any other static pages that you would want to create.
And you can bring models into it like for instance our home page.
We're going to want the latest listings on our boat page we're going to want realtors and this stuff
is going to come from the database.
So what we can do is we can import models from the listings app or from the realtor's app into pages
so that we can display it.
All right but for now we're just going to focus on just getting a home page and an About page set up.
So I have my server running down here so I'm going to open up a new terminal here and make sure you're
in your virtual environment and let's create the pages app so to do that.
We're going to say Python say Python manage dot PI and then we're going to say start app and then we
want to name it so we're going to call this pages.
OK so we'll run that.
And what happens is it creates a new folder called pages with a bunch of files inside of it.
So these are all the default files for when you create now.
So we have an IT UP HIGH just like we do and be Tiare it's just completely empty we don't have to worry
about it.
Migrations is for any database migrations we create.
We're not going to have any migrations for this particular app but we will in some of the other ones
admen is if you want to like you want to show stuff in the admin area.
We're not going to need to do that here in our listings app.
We will because we'll want to will want to manage our listings from the admin area but we won't touch
this one.
And then AppStore pie.
This shows you the class of the conflict.
This will actually have to go in our settings file or show you that in the second models.
This is where we create our models.
This particular app doesn't have a model but for instance listings will have like the the title The
address the number of bedrooms all that stuff is going to be defined inside of a model.
Then we have our tests if we want to run any tests and have used up my file where we can create methods
and we can actually link you or else to those methods.
So first thing I want to do it before I forget.
Because a lot of times I do forget is to add this app to our settings so lets go to the BTR settings
up high and what we're going to want to put here and the installed apps is a set of quotes and a comma
and we're going to say pages dot apps.
Daut pages.
Config.
OK so we want to go like that in where I got this page config from is in the App Store pi.
So whatever this is right here is what goes right here.
So if I save this that will cause Django to recognize this as an app right now what I saved I got this
message down here in vs code.
So if you're using the code and you get this auto pep 8 message this is a formatter.
Now if you just go ahead and click yes I believe it installs it globally and you're going to have some
issues with paths and stuff.
So what I would suggest doing is going to your terminal while you're in your virtual environment and
then doing a Pipp install an auto pap 8 like that.
And that should install in your virtual environment.
And if we close this up.
Let's just do a pip freeze.
This can become a real pain in the butt.
Yeah you see now we have autopay have eight so hopefully we don't get that message anymore.
All right so let me just try to resave this and make sure that we don't get that.
OK.
We don't.
Good.
All right so let's close that up.
And now what I wanted to do is create a pie file for this pages app.
So inside the pages folder here let's create a new file called Earles dot pi.
OK.
And we're going to have to bring in here.
See we're going to save from Django So the main Gengel package Daut you ourselves.
We want to import something called paff.
OK.
And if we look at the other you are a closed door pie file you'll see that they do the same thing because
if you want to define a path like this you have to actually bring that path package in.
So back to the other you are Elle's dot Pi.
We want to then bring in the views because the idea here is to have a path that or u r l or a path or
row whatever you want to call it that is attached to a method.
Inside this view file.
Ok so we want a u r l for our home page.
So to bring in the views we want to say from all import views.
Okay.
And then down here we want to define u r l patterns just like the other file.
OK.
So we'll set that to a list and then let's say path because we brought in path and the path that I want
is just nothing.
Which means the root path like the home page.
OK and a lot of not a lot of frameworks and stuff you'll see just slash but we're just going to leave
this empty.
OK the second parameter is going to be the method we want to connect this to in the view.
So we want to say views Daut and then the method which is going to be called index and then the final
parameter is going to be the name.
OK we're going to set a name here to easily access this path which we'll call index.
All right so going to save that.
Now we're getting in error here.
And it says that there's no index member So basically it's we're getting this because there's no there's
no method called index inside the views file.
So let's take care of that.
Let's go to views and we'll get rid of that line here and actually let me make this smaller.
And then let's write a function so we say def index.
When I say function or method I'm using those interchangeably.
So we'll define this as index and we want to pass in a request here as a parameter and then put a colon
and then what we want to happen here.
Now ultimately we want to render a template for the home page.
But for now I'm just going to bring in we're going to say from Django dot h t t p we want to import
and saying Poor HTP response need to get these drop downs because we have the python extension installed.
And then and here let's simply return let's say return HTP response.
And inside here we'll just say we can actually put h Tim Allen here we'll put an H on and we'll say
hello world.
All right we'll save that.
OK.
Now this isn't going to work yet.
If I go to our application it opens.
Where is it right here.
And we reload we still see this page because what we need to do is we need to take this you are Elle's
PI file that we created and we knew why is we.
Why are we still getting this error pages of views has no index member should it does
that's weird There you go.
All right.
Now we want to go to the other you or else.
Pi the main one in the very folder and I'm just going to get rid of all these comments because we don't
need those OK.
And we want to go right here.
Let's go.
But this will go above the admin and say paff tree put a comma here and then whatever we want the main
the the first segment of the R L to be for the pages app.
Now I don't want it to be anything because I don't want to have to go to like pages slash about or pages
slash anything.
Otherwise we would do that.
I want to be able to just go to slash about and just nothing for the home page just slash So we're going
actually going to leave this blank OK for listings and stuff like that.
Then we'll have listings slash or realtors whatever whatever the path may be.
But in this case I want to leave it blank.
All right.
And then we want to include.
So we want to include.
And then inside quotes here pages Daut you are Elle's.
Okay so we're essentially linking to the you are L's pie of the pages app.
If I save this we're going to get an error.
And the reason for that is because include we actually need to bring that in because that's part of
the Django you are Elle's package.
So we simply need to put a comma here and say we want to bring in includes so that we can use it and
I'll save that and now you'll see that that error goes away.
And now we should be able to access the index.
Okay.
Which should be just the home page because we left this blank.
So let's check it out.
Let's go to our It's the let's go here and reload and there we go.
So we're getting Hello world.
Now obviously we don't want to if I go back to our views we don't want to be putting our h team inside
of inside here like inside an HDP response we want to actually render a template.
So in the next video I'm going to show you how we can do that and we're going to create templates folder
and we'll start to create a structure there so that we can add our each team around to be served instead
of putting it right into a response like this.
All right so I'll see you in the next video.