All right guys.
In the last video we went ahead and we created our pages app.
We created a U R L to the index view or I'm sorry index method inside the views file which is right
here and then we're just outputting or returning and HDP response that outputs in H1.
OK so that's that's all we're seeing right here.
Now what we want to do is I'll put a template so there's a couple steps we need to take the first we
need to tell Django where to look for templates what folder to look at.
So in setting's dot PI you want to go down to the templates list right here it has a dictionary with
the all these values these key value pairs.
And we want to go to this der's this directory's and we want to tell it where to look.
So where I put my templates is right in the root so not in any of these folders here just right along
side them so to let it know that we're going to say OS dot path dot join and we're going to use our
base underscore Durr variable which just basically says the base directory or the root directory and
then we want to define the folder name and we want to use which is templates.
So it's go and save that.
All right.
And then we want to go into our root here and create a folder called templates.
Now it's up to you how you want to structure your templates.
I like to categorize them.
So for instance our pages app will have a couple of its own templates so we'll create a folder called
pages that will have a folder called listings and so on.
So we're going to create a folder in templates called pages and then I'm going to create two files in
here one is going to be indexed on each team.
And then one is going to be about the dot h t.
L k for the about page and just going to do an H-1 that says a boat can save for index I'll do an H-1
that says
home and save.
OK so now that we have our templates created we need to first of all go to our pages app and then you
are Elazar pi because right now we don't have an About route just for the index.
It's going to put a comma here.
Bring that down.
We'll call this one about.
And then the method name that I'm going to use is also going to be about in the route is also about.
So save this we're going to get an error here because there is no about method in the views file so
we're going to create that now.
So in views let's say let's say Def about.
OK.
Now we don't want to just return an H T P response for either one of these.
We want to render a template.
We're actually already bringing in render up here so that's what we want to use.
So instead of this we're going to say return render.
And this takes in two things for now which is going to be the request itself and then the location of
the template which is in pages slash index dot HMO.
I know we're going to do the same thing for the about so more tab over here and paste that in and just
change this to about and save with it oh I forgot my parentheses and request.
OK.
Now you are up high we're still seeing this error.
We just need to resave it and that will go away.
OK so now this should work.
Let's head make sure your server is running.
My server running in this.
This tab right here.
Also always make sure you're in your virtual environment.
OK.
Make sure you have this van or whatever you called it and I will mention if you install an extension
in vs code and you reload.
It's going to knock you out of your virtual environments.
You want to go back in.
If you're using your integrated terminal So now let's go back to Chrome and reload.
And now we see home.
OK so it's loading the index each time template in the pages folder in the templates folder if go to
about we see about.
OK so that's perfect.
All right.
Now the issue with with this what we're doing now is if we want to of course we do want to have like
a head section we want our age to smell had body tags all of our CSSA references javascript references
that stuff we don't want to have to repeat on every template like him in the index in the about anything
else we create.
So we want to extend a base layout.
OK so what world what we'll do is in the templates folder not inside pages but just inside templates
will create a file called base dot h T.M. and then this is going to be just that our base.
Each team that we can extend from other templates.
Okay and this is going to have like all our H.T. email had tags and stuff like that.
So when you use Emett by doing exclamation tabs just to give us a boilerplate here title will say Beati
real estate and I'll show you how to do dynamic titles later in our body.
This is where we want to output any template that we extend OK or that so that we use to extend this
layout.
So to do that we're going to use the Jinja syntax Jinja is the template engine that Gengel uses by default
and that is curly braces and percent signs.
OK so you can kind of think this is like ph P If you've ever if you've ever written ph P inside your
aged female you need to open up your Ph p tags to run that code.
This is similar.
We need to open up our Jinja tags or template tags whatever you want to call them.
And then here we want to save block content.
OK.
And then we need to end that block by doing another set of tags and say and block.
All right so I'll save that in then any template that we want to extend this layout from.
We actually have to do a couple of things we have to first go up here use our tags AUPs use our tags
and say extends a little save based on age Tamal and then we just need to wrap the content in that block
content content.
Okay.
And then at the end of it we need to do and block.
All right so save that now.
The way my editor is formatted it kind of pushes this up here which kind of sucks but it's just something
that we'll deal with for now.
So let's go back to the home page
and now you'll see that the title says Beati real estate.
And if I were to look at my source code it includes all that you know the doc type each Tamal the head
body all that stuff and includes all of it.
And it's like it's like inserting the template right here.
OK.
So now let's do the same for a bow because right now if we go to slash about you'll see that there is
no title it's not extending that leo.
So I'll just copy this here and go to a bow and we'll go ahead and push that down and paste that in.
And we just want to end the block
that you will go back and reload.
And now we get our title in it that that layout is being extended.
Now if you're using this code you do have the option to install the Jinja extension.
So if we go to extensions and we search for Jinja it would be this first one here I believe me just
check the downloads.
Yes so to 44000 this right here if we say install that I'll install it.
Now watch down here.
We're in our virtual environment.
When I reload it knocks us back oh ok it also got rid of my other tab.
That was actually running the server.
OK.
So that's something that just sucks.
I wish I didn't do that but it does if I reload.
Our server is no longer running.
Now notice the Jinja syntax now has this this highlighting here.
Unfortunately if I knocked this down I would like it to be like that.
But if I save it gets put back up there.
So I think what I'm going to try is I'm going to go to my settings and let's set format on save to false.
Ok I always have this on true but I just want to save that and see if that helps the situation out.
So if I go down here and say OK so now it doesn't do that now since they shut that off.
I'm just going to have to be a little more aware of how my code is formatted.
OK.
But I think that with when we start to do like loops and stuff like that it's going to look really messy
if I keep that on.
So I think that I'm going to just shut that off.
All right so now we actually if you're following along and you just did what I did you have to go back
into your virtual environment so we're going to say source then.
So slash then slash then slash activate case.
Now back in and if you remember if you're in Windows it's going to be then slash scripts slash activate
dot.
That way you might have to do an absolute path.
So now I'm going to run my server with Python managed up-I run server so this is kind of the disadvantage
of using the integrated terminal with Django but you know I don't want to keep going back and forth
to my regular terminal.
All right.
So now my server is running so I'm going to open up another tab hit the plus sign here and just go into
my virtual environment and this tab as well.
And now we're back.
All right so if I go back to the browser and reload we should get our site back.
All right so in the next video I want to start to implement our bootstrap theme at least for the home
and the about page at first it's going to be all static content.
OK.
But we want to slowly but surely replace that with Dynamic Content.
We're going to you know create our database soon install postgrads and set that up and then we'll go
from there.
All right so I'll see in the next video.