All right guys so now we're going to start to think about implementing our bootstrap theme bringing
it into our Django application so that that's what displays in the front end web site.
But I want to just take a look at how to handle static files because this is something that can be very
confusing it's something that confused me at first.
So I just tried to really follow along here.
So I have our project arbitrary project folder or this is just our route Gengel project and then we
have our Beati very theme which is included in your resources and we don't care about any of this stuff
or we care about is the disk folder which has our h team l files.
But right now I want to focus on this assets folder.
OK this has like all of our CSSA our bootstrap everything all the javascript all the images the fonts
for fun awesome all that stuff.
So we want to bring this into our application as as static assets.
So in our BTR project what we're going to do is go into this folder this Tiare folder and I'm going
to create a new folder and I'm going to call this static.
OK.
And then this is where I want to put our main static files.
So the whole CSSA folder or the whole JSM the whole web fonts.
I'm going to copy and bring that in.
Now the images some of this stuff we don't want because like the homes for example these are all images
we're actually going to upload through the admin area when we create our listings same thing with the
realtors.
So we don't want those all we really want is the light box and then the these images.
OK so we want these in a folder called I Am G.
So let's create I'm a Pierre OK.
And then we're going to bring let's bring all of these images and the Lightbox folder OK.
So just to reiterate inside our main BTR project we have a folder called B-tree that was generated when
we ran start project from Django admen and then we put our static folder in there and I just brought
everything into that.
OK.
So let's make sure that you have that.
OK so now we need to go to our settings file.
So we want to go to be Tiare settings dot pi and you can see at the bottom here we actually have a static
you are all set to static.
But we want to add two other things here.
One is going to be the static route OK and the idea of this is when you deploy your application you
run a command called collect static and it goes into all of your applications or all of your apps and
if it has a static folder it takes everything out and puts it into a root static folder.
So that's what we're defining here so we're going to say OS dot path dot joined just like we did with
the templates and say base directory and then static.
OK.
And then we want to do one more value here which is going to be static files underscore der's.
And we want to set the location of the static folder we just created which is in this BT houri folder.
So the way that we can do that is OS dot path join base Durer and then we want b t r e slash static
OK so that should be the correct configuration.
Let's save this.
Now if I bring this up here and I do a python manage dog PI help you'll see there's actually a command
called collect static.
OK so that should actually find any static folders we have and create one into whatever we define as
the static route.
OK and you could call this anything assets.
Well I'm just going to leave it a static.
But let's go ahead and try to run that.
So if you say Python mintage Daut PI and we say collect static Let's run that.
OK so for static files copied and you can see that it is actually created a static folder in our root
which has not only the stuff that we put in in the Tiare but also the admin.
OK the static admin files.
So when we deploy this is actually where it looks for everything including the admin CSSA and all that
stuff.
So once we put this on our server we want to run that command.
Now one thing we don't want is to push this to our repository.
So we're going to go to our dog get ignore and we're actually going to add slash static.
OK.
And then another thing that I forgot to do is to add a slash in front of media because I only want the
root static in media to not be pushed to the to the repository.
All right so we'll go ahead and save that.
OK and you can make your get comments in that on your own but now that we have that there are static
files set up we can move on to basically bring in our bootstrap theme bring in all that markup.
So that's what we're going to do in the next video.