All right guys soon the last video we took care of are static files.
We should have a BT houri folder with the static folder for all our stuff that we created you know with
our theme and then our main static folder in the room will have that all that plus the admin.
OK and this is when we when we deploy.
This is where it'll look to.
All right.
So now what I want to do is start to implement our bootstrap theme.
So I'm on my base.
Each team will lay out which is in the templates folder and we're going to start to kind of just add
stuff here to this.
This file from our bootstrap theme.
Now the way that I'm going to do this is I'm going to use Sublime Text which is a different text editor.
Hold on let me just open up a new window here and I'm going to open up the bootstrap theme in Sublime
Text that way I don't get confused by which is which you know so I'll know that if it's Sublime Text
it's just the theme just the each team.
And our main project is in vs code so you don't have to do this if you want to open it in the same text
editor or something else whenever you want to do is absolutely fine.
But this is what I'm doing so I'm going to go to a project and you guys can see the menu but I'm going
to project add folder to project and I'm going to find my C desktop I'm going to go to VTR resources
BTR theme and I want the dist folder or I don't care about any of this.
That's just for development for the theme.
So we just want our disks folder.
All right.
So now over here I'm going to open up in next each team Mallam We want to start to bring some of this
stuff over so we're gonna start with the head.
This is where we include our static files like Fonte awesome bootstrap our custom style sheet and so
on.
So we're going to copy these lines and go back to vs code into our base each DML and I'm going to paste
these in.
All right then I'm going to go and navigate to the bottom where we have all the javascript which are
these three script tags here and I'm going to copy these and I'm going to go to vs code.
I'm going to put that right above the ending body tag.
OK.
Now if I save this the way it is obviously I know that a lot of you guys know that this is not going
to work.
So if I reload this and we take a look at our chrome tools and our cons. we're going to get a ton of
errors here because it's looking for these files in there.
They're nowhere to be found.
OK because if we look at where that pointing to it's looking at assets CSSA we don't even have an assets
folder.
So the way that we can reference the static files that we just brought in we have to we have to actually
do a couple things here.
So at the very top of this each time I'll file if you want to use static if you want to use the special
static helper I guess we can call it you want to use your template tags here and you just want to say
load static like that.
OK.
Now wherever we have a static file coming in like let's say this all DOD CSX which is the font.
Awesome file.
What we want to do is in the ATRA if we want to first of all get rid of this asset slash because there's
no such thing in our jingle project.
And we want to open up a template tag.
So we want to do percent and we want to see a static static and just space and then we want to wrap
the CSSA slash all Dotsie SS in single quotes and then we want to end that and the tag like that.
All right so this will actually reference whatever our static folder is which we defined in our settings
and it will look for a CSSA slash all Dotsie SS and it should be able to find it hopefully.
So now I'm just going to copy this whole thing here.
And let's go to the next one which is bootstrap and we'll paste that in and we'll just change this to
bootstrap and then this one here will change this to stifle.
All right so that should take care of the CSSA actually.
I forgot the light box that's in there correct.
Yes.
Light box.
MAN Yeah.
All right so let's add that as well.
So say live blogs
and I'm just going to copy this
and this is going to be light box dot men dot CSSA OK and the reason it wasn't here is because I copied
this from the index page in the theme and the index didn't include this file.
So now let's go down to the bottom here where we have the these stack the javascript and it's the same
idea.
So what we can do is again use our template tags and say static wrap this in single quotes like that
and then close it.
So I keep doing like a peach tag.
Actually that would be a dollar sign for BHP but we want to do the same kind of thing so let's actually
just copy like this
and that should actually be G-S slash and then let's do the same thing right here.
And then we want just the end to be a single quote and then a closing tag like that.
All right so again it should be looking in whatever our static folder is and then looking at these locations.
OK.
And then again we want to add the light box so I forgot about that.
So let's copy that down.
We'll do J.S. slash lightbox dot dot Yes.
All right so I'm sure that that's saved.
And let's go back to Crome and now you can see bootstrap is already working here.
And we just move this over a little bit go.
All right.
So bootstrap is kicked in.
And the only errors we're getting over here because we don't have the the Jay J.A.G. loading gif I don't
have that there and that's fine.
This enraged hemol is because if we look at our main J.S. So let's take a look at our main J.S..
What's going on is in the template there's a class of year div with the class of year or a span I think
it is and we're just putting in the year dynamically using javascript and that that span doesn't exist.
So it's giving us an error as soon as we add that that error will go away so there's no need to to worry
about that.
All right but this is how we implement static files inside of our template.
So now what we're going to do is start to bring over some of the stuff that we want on every page like
the nav bar the top bar things like that.
So if we head over to sublime texts where we have our theme let's go up to the top and let's grab the
top bar.
So I'm just going to grab this.
All of it.
And then also the nav bar which is directly under it and stop there because the showcase Obviously that
doesn't go on every page so we're going to going to copy this.
The nav bar on the top bar.
Go back to our base.
Each team now.
And let's put this right above the block content.
All right so you put that above the block content and then the other thing that goes on every page is
the footer.
So I'm going to go back to our theme and go all the way down and grab our footer and this is what I
was talking about a spam with the class of year this is where the year gets inserted.
And it wasn't finding that so it was giving us that console error.
So let's copy this and go back and put this after the block content.
So right here right.
And have prettier formatting on save anymore so she can fix that up a little bit.
All right so let's save that and let's go ahead and take a look.
And there we go.
All right cool.
So these are going to show on every page if we go to slash about and see this go to sleep.
No this goes to about age DML But we'll fix that.
But let's just check out slash about.
And you can see now we're on the About page.
One last thing I want to do before I end this video is is show you that we can use Parshall's.
OK so I don't want our base each team out to be cluttered up with all of this markup.
So what we can do is we can create a separate folder in our templates folder called Parshall's
right now inside Parshall's.
I want to put the nav bar everything we just brought in the nav bar the top bar in the footer.
So we want to separate full separate file for all of those.
Now since there Parshall's the convention is to use an underscore in front so we're going to say underscore
nav bar Daut aged him well and will create underscore top bar door age Himmel.
And let's also create underscore for Dot aged him.
OK and then we can simply bring that stuff in.
So we'll start off with the top bar.
I'm going to go from here.
Went too far down to here and just cut that and we're going to put that in the top bar each team out
and save K and just close it for now and then the nav bar will grab all that mark up which ends right
here.
Cut that out.
Put it in here and save.
And then finally the FOTR will cut that.
Put that in footer save that.
And now we just need to bring those in and that's.
That's very simple with using the template syntax.
I'm going to just put a comment and say top bar
here we want to use our template tags and we want to just to include it in the Parshall's folder and
underscore taught by DOT HMO.
OK so I'm just going to copy that.
Or go down below.
And this is going to be the nav bar.
So it will include
nav bar each time.
All right.
And here let's say main content.
And then lastly we want the faulter
underscore for each email.
So save.
Now we should get the same results.
Let's go back and reload and we get the same thing okay.
All the logo.
So the logo is also a static asset.
So if to do the same thing we did for this like the CSSA and the javascript and all that.
So we're going to go to our NAV bar partial because that's where the logo is you can see we still have
it pointing to like assets.
So we want to change that.
Now remember if we're going to be using static we need to up at the top we need to load static Kay.
And then once we go down to her we have our logo.
We're going to get rid of the assets and we're going to put in our template tag and say static and then
put this in single quotes and then end it.
All right.
So go ahead and save that.
And let's go back reload and there's our logo.
All right so we can close this up.
And in the next video I want to start to add some of the stuff for the index page.
Will move to the about will also take care of the links here.
We can use some special conditionals to make these active when we're on the correct page.
All right so I'll see you in the next video.