All right.
So in the last video we took care of our Levo using bootstrap and using you know putting the top bar
the now on the footer and because these are things that are going to be on every single page.
So we wanted these in our base.
Each Al file.
I also showed you how to link static assets using load's static.
So now we're going to work on the inner content here.
So we'll start on the index page.
So let's head over to Sublime Text which has just daar our theme.
This is all just the HVM owl.
And what I'm going to do is copy everything that we don't have that we didn't put into the base aged
him.
So we have the footer and the script and stuff so let's start right here at the bottom above the water
and then go all the way up until we hit under the nav bar.
OK which already past's we want to go back down.
So right here to the showcase.
OK so going to copy all this and this is all going to go into our index each team.
Now remember right now everything is just static it's like this form is obviously not going to work.
We're not going to get the latest listings or have we haven't even installed the database yet we just
want to get the markup to show and it's going to be like that for quite a while until we get into creating
our models and all that stuff.
So just keep that in mind.
All right so let's head to when they have so many things open at once.
We're going to go to our project and close this up actually base each team so we can close up for now
and then let's go to let's see templates pages and then index each team out which should look like this
right now.
All right.
And then we're going to just replace this H-1 with everything that we just copied.
So I'm going to paste all of that in and save.
And then let's go back to Chrome and reload and there we go.
So we have basically just kind of a shell of an application.
So it's not actually fetching anything or anything like that it's just basically the H Tim L placed
in a template.
Now as far as the listings here remember we're going to be adding the listings from the admin area which
we haven't even talked about yet.
So the images will come from somewhere different.
They're not going to come from the static files.
Ok so this will look like this for now.
So don't worry about that yet and then.
Yes so the rest will just keep as is.
Now let's do the same with the home page.
So I'm going to go to the theme that I have open in sublime text and go to about aged hemol and just
get everything below the nav bar basically between the nav bar and the foot or so here.
And if I scroll down to here right above the footer I'm going to copy that.
OK we're going to go to the about dot each team L in our jingle app and we're going to paste that in.
So let's save that.
Let's take a look.
So now I'm just going to navigate to slash about and there's a boat page.
Now remember there is a static image on this page.
OK so there is that picture of the inside of the office.
So we do want we do want to include that.
So it's head on over back to to that about each team.
All this other stuff the realtors this is going to be coming from the database so we don't need to worry
about that or the seller of the month.
We just want to go up to see right here where it's loading this assets about J bag so we want to actually
load static and it's very important to know that when you extend a label like we are here it has to
be the first line.
So our load static can't go at the top it has to go below that.
So it's a load static.
And then we'll go back down to this about JPEG.
Let's get rid of this.
Hey we're just doing the same thing that we've been doing by saying static.
I want to wrap this in single quotes and then close that up right.
So I'll save that let's take a look and we reload and there's the image.
All right so now what I want to do is talk about linking.
OK so linking to.
You know we have the in the breadcrumbs we have a link.
We have a link here.
This will go to the listings which hasn't been created yet.
So we'll do that a little later.
We'll also do link in the nav bar at the home and the about at least so to link let's use the breadcrumb
right here so you can see it's going to index each year and that's obviously not what we want.
So here we want to put in our tags and we want to do you Arel single quote and then index.
OK.
So let's try that in a reload.
I'm going to hit home brings us back home now that index.
If you're wondering what this is where this come comes from is if we go to our pages app and we go to
pi we named this index so we can use this basically and you know to link to same thing with a boat.
So let's go to our NAV K.R. now.
Partial here.
And we have the branding which I want to go to the home page so we'll simply
throwing you r l index there.
Same thing for home.
And then for about
we're going to say you are old both because it's the name we gave it.
So save now for relo we should be able to go back and forth Okay now for listing know we have a featured
listings if we try and do that here.
You are all OK.
So if I save that we go back and reload we get an error because that doesn't exist.
It doesn't even let us put it as a link.
It just it's just just not going to work.
So for now I'm just going to do.
Index.
OK.
And then later on when we create our listings app we'll fix this.
All right.
So now what I want to do is handle the highlighting of the link because right now if we look if we go
on the About page home it's still highlighted it's still active and if you're not familiar with bootstrap
what's causing that is the class of active on the fly.
OK if we move the active to the ally of about that will be highlighted but we want this to be dynamic
if we go to the About page we want that to be highlighted and this is going to add a little bit of clutter
to your template because we have to use conditionals.
But if you want that functionality then this is this is how you're going to have to do it.
I mean there are there's other ways to do it.
There may even be shorter ways like cleaner ways but this is just the way that I do it.
So what we want to do is we need a conditional if that condition was met.
So if this is the home page we want to display class with active if it's not we want to display class
without active.
So I'm going to get rid of actually going to copy.
I'm going to copy this or cut it rather.
And this ally I'm actually going to go onto the next line and make sure that the year inside the ally
you the angle bracket down here and we want to do an F..
OK.
So in these these templates you can do if statements.
So I want to say if slash is equal to request Daut paff case who are testing the request path.
So basically the page if that's true then I'm going to paste in what we have.
So we want class and we want active included in that.
Now if it's not so we want to do an else if it's not then we want class with out active in that.
OK so let's save that let's test that that out.
So if I reload this unclose tag.
Oh I forgot the N.F..
So right here we have to do a
END-IF
OK.
So about there it is it's highlighted a I mean I'm sorry home it's highlighted.
We go to a about and it's not.
So we need to do the same for a bone.
So what I'll do is copy all of this.
So the whole Eli tag to the last angle bracket and then I'm going to just paste this in for this.
The ABOUT ally like that and the condition is going to be a bit different when it's not the home page.
So instead of doing like Slash equals request path we're going to do if
about.
OK so if about in request path request path OK if that's true then we want active.
If not we don't.
So save that and let's go back to our browser and reload and you see home is highlighted.
Now if I go to a boat a boat is highlighted OK or active.
So good.
Now once we do the listings We'll have that working as well.
Same thing with the register and log in but for now we only have the index in about page so that's all
we're going to do for now.
All right.
So just a quick note before we move on I know that I've said this I said this in the beginning but this
is a little different than a lot of other courses it's not just Django like here's how you do this here's
how you do this.
We're building an app a real application and I'm building it as if it were a real application.
And what I would do is have all of the templates created all the views in the UI before I do anything
with the database.
Setting up models migrations.
Stuff like that the admin area.
I just want to get the front end UI done before we do that.
OK so next what we'll do is create our listings app.
OK we're going to create our listings app and I think we'll create the realtor's app too at the same
time and get that template up.
So when we can actually go to a featured listings and we'll see the static content.
And then once we do that we can start to think about our models and how to set them up and you know
obviously we need to install postgrads and all that stuff.
All right so hopefully you guys can appreciate that it's not really a traditional course it's more of
a project you know hands on project course.
So that's it.
I will see you in the next video.