All right guys so now that we have our index in about page done as far as the display the UI I want
to create our listings app and also our realtor's app.
Ok so once we do this we should have two new folders listings and realtors and it'll be similar to the
pages folder structure with all the admin dot by the apps models test your Elle's in views.
Well actually you or else we create ourselves.
So let's go ahead and generate these apps so we're going to say Python.
Make sure you're in your virtual environment.
We're going to say Python managed Daut pi.
And we wanted to do start up and we're going to create an app called listings.
OK.
So now over to the left you can see it created a folder called listings lets do the same with realtors.
So Realtors is I mean listings obviously we have the listings page we have the single listing page and
all that stuff we have the search page thats going to be part of the listings app.
Realtors is more just for the model we're not going to have any templates or views for realtors.
It's just to basically to be able to add realtors through the admin area and then basically form a relationship
between the realtor and the listing.
OK so let's start off by adding our listings templates.
So we're going to go into the templates and well let's create a special folder for listing templates
and call this listings.
And inside here we'll create a folder called listing agent team.
OK Cingular that's the single listing page.
We also want listings pleuro for you know the the the list of listings.
And let's also create one called Search page to mail.
OK so those are all the templates that we need now for listings we're going to have to have some some
your elves obviously that we need to connect to.
So that means we need to create its own you are Elle's dot.
So inside the the main listings folder here we're going to create a new file called you or else dot
PI and it's going to be similar to what we did with pages you are closed up.
So I'm actually going to just copy that and bring that over to the new one here.
So we want to import path we want to import from views you are all patterns for just if we leave this
empty this pertains to slash listings or at least it will.
So we want that to call the index method inside of the listings views foaled views file.
OK and we'll name this listings OK.
Let's say for the single listings we actually want it to look like this so it will be our or whatever
are you are Ellas slash listings slash.
And then the ID like let's say listings 23.
So we need to include a parameter in our u r l here so it'll be slashy listings and then the ID.
So what we need to do is put in some angle brackets and we need to put the type that we want which is
going to be an int and then what we want to call it which is going to be listing underscore ID.
Okay so that'll be how we can actually access this parameter from within the view method.
So we'll have this go to views Daut listing that will be the name of the method and then the name will
call listing a singular and then the last you are all we're going to need here is going to be the search.
So we'll call this search and it will go to a method called search.
And as far as the the well we want it to be listings slash search.
So we just want to put in search here.
Okay.
And the reason we're not putting in like listings slash search here is because we're actually going
to link this to the main you are Elle's dot PI and tell it that anything that has listings slash should
look at this file so let's save this and we're going to now head over and we're going to get errors
here because we haven't created these methods yet.
But let's head over to the main beat.
Sorry you are up high and we want to do the same thing we did with our pages app.
Okay.
And one other thing we have to do is at our apt to the settings file which I always always forget to
do.
So let's go ahead and just create another one here and this time we're going to do listings slash.
Okay so anything that is listing slash is going to go to listings.
You are Elle's.
So save that.
And then let's go to our setting's file.
Before I forget again.
So we'll go to settings up high and go up to where the apps are which are installed apps and let's copy
this down twice.
We want to bring in listings dot apps dot listings con thig and then we also want to bring in our realtors.
So so be realtors con fig it'll be realtors dot apps.
OK so I'll save that.
So now we need to create our view methods.
So are you Olsdorf for listings of index listing in search Scholtz create those who will go into views
and see we're going to get rid of that let's to define index so indexes are going to be just the main
listings page.
Okay this takes in a request and what we're going to do here is render the listings view.
So we want to render which has already brought in above passen the request and then the view we want
to render is going to be in the listings and it's going to be listings dot aged him out okay.
So now what I'll do is just copy this and paste that in let's do one more time so we have index we also
have just the listing.
And what I'm going by is this right here index listing and search.
So those those are the three methods that we want to create right now.
So listing in the template that will load is going to be listing aged all then we have search and that's
going to load the search aged HUMO.
Okay.
Now as far as the small pages for now it's just put h ones in there so will say this is listing.
I'll save that.
The Swan is listings.
Save that.
And then this one is search.
OK.
Now if we try to save this Yarl's pie those errors go away.
OK let's just check on our server make sure that's still running.
Case that looks OK.
See what I have this open
I guess I can close one of these Kozo went up.
All right so now let's go to our application and let's try to go to slash listings.
OK so again error see page not found.
Why does it say about
see the mess something up here.
Let's check the route to you or else dot Pi so path listings slash include listings dot you are URLs
that should be right.
And then we have our listings app you are Elle's dot Pi which looks like this so views and its name
of listing so that looks all right.
And then we have our views
I you know let's
current path listings and match any of these
oh I have just listing the should have an S on the end try that.
OK so I get a different out of the view listings view index didn't return and HTB response object.
And that's because I didn't return the render.
So let's go back to views and make sure that we actually return these.
And I could edit this stuff out guys but I really don't like to because it's just real stuff.
It's stuff that happens in real life and I don't I don't like to talk fields and courses that are just
cookie cutter and it's not you know it's not it's not realistic to never forget something or make mistakes
or anything like that.
And it's important for new new developers to know that.
Let's save this and go back and reload and there we go.
Now we're loading our listings template now.
Remember we didn't extend the base HVM.
So that's why we're not seeing any of the bootstrap formatting or anything like that.
So let's let's do that.
Let's go to listings that age HTML.
And from here we want to extend the base HVM also it's got top and put in our tags and we'll say extends
based on age DML.
And then of course we need our block.
So I want to say block
content and right under that we want to end the block.
OK so now if we save that and go back and reload.
Now we have our crome.
Basically what do you mean by Crome is like our wrapper bootstrap wrapper.
OK so yeah we're just going to work on the listings page for now.
I just want to get at least the static stuff here.
So what I'll do is go to my sublime text where I have just the theme and go to our listings our age
team and we want to grab everything that is under the nav bar.
So this section here all the way down to right above the Forder because remember the foot or the now
by that stuff is all included in a partial.
Inside the the main layout so we want everything down to the footer and then we'll go back to listings
on each team so we're just going to pace that stuff in here and let's save it and go back and reload
and there we go.
Now we're not going to see the images because the images are actually going to come from when we when
we go to the admin area and we upload a listing we're going to upload those.
We're going to upload some images and that's what we'll show here so I'm not going to mess around and
just you know put a static image here just for show it doesn't really matter right now.
OK but let's see what I do want to do is I want to add a link for this to go to home right now it's
going to go to index each team which obviously we don't want.
And then these should go to.
Right now they go to listing each time.
But we want these to go to the single listing page so it will be listings slash and then whatever the
idea is.
All right.
Well I guess we'll do that after because we don't actually have IDs yet.
So let's at least add to the breadcrumb link.
So we'll go up to see where is it his breadcrumb.
So right here
we're going to go play that.
We're going to say you are well and we want this to go to the home page which is in the index.
OK.
Now let me just try that real quick.
So that works.
Now when we when we create the database we create our listings model we create all of our tables and
stuff.
What we'll do is reach into the database past the listings into the view I'm sorry into the template
from the view or from the used up high and then we'll loop through the listings and output one of these
divs.
OK because right now we have a listing one listing to we're not going to need all of this markup.
We're only going to need to loop through listings and I'll put one of these and have dynamic you know
like the price will be dynamic it will be whatever the price for that current listing is and stuff like
that.
All right so this will be overall this will be a much smaller file and we're done same with with most
of the HMO stuff.
All right.
So let's see now what I want to do is I want this to actually go to the listings page.
So let's head over to the nav bar which is a partial.
So we want to go to templates Parshall's underscore nav bar.
And right now it goes to index.
I want to change that to listings.
Okay so that's that should now work let's try it out.
So if we reload this page and go to feature listings there we go.
Now we don't have it highlighted so we want to do the same thing that we did with the other ones.
So I'm going to copy this ally with the condition inside of it and I'm going to pace this is in place
of this ally like that and we're just going to test for listings can save that go back to reload and
now we have highlighted listings link.
All right cool.
So that's going to be it for this guys and we'll see you in the next one.