The
Hey Guys welcome to Python Django dev to deployment so in this welcome video I just want to give you
an idea of how this course is structured so that you know exactly what to expect.
And it's it's formatted a bit differently than some of my other courses.
This is strictly a project based course.
It's not a linear like documentation type video course with slides and all that.
We're going to look at this as a practical project that was given to us by a fictional company called
Beati real estate and they want us to build them a Web site or a web app where they can add their property
listings.
They can have people search browse make inquiries and add their realtors and stuff like that.
So we're going to go from the point of you know absolute scratch starting with installing Python setting
up a virtual environment setting up vs code and then diving into Django.
OK we're not going to build the bootstrap theme in this course because I want to focus on just Django
but I have it all packaged and ready to implement into the project so it'll be included in your course
files.
Now at some point I will be doing probably a YouTube series on the travesty media channel where we actually
build the theme from scratch using bootstrap and SAS.
But like I said I didn't want to put that in this course.
I might change my mind later and put it in but for now we're just going to I use the package theme now
for requirements.
All you really need to know is basic HTL CSSA and some programming principles like you know if statements
and functions and stuff like that if you've if you've used any other language like javascript or PSP
or anything like that you should be fine.
We're actually going to have a section where we go over the Python syntax.
We go over like lists and dictionaries and functions.
The indentation syntax and all that stuff.
So you should be absolutely fine even if you've never used Python before.
And Django is a very very high level framework meaning that there's there's really only one way to do
pretty much everything it's not like like some frameworks like flask for instance which is a micro framework
where you can do things the way you want with Gengel you have some specific rules to follow which makes
it a little easier to learn.
All right so after you take this course you'll be able to build your own Django apps.
You're going to learn about set up templates view methods you URLs and routes forms models migrations
and much more.
OK we're going to be using post-grads as our database will also deploy to Digital Ocean using unicorn
and engine next to proxy.
So if you're interested in building this project stick around.
In the next video I'm going to go over the whole application and show you what what it entails.