All right guys so now I'm going to just give you a quick demo of the application will be building both
the front facing web site and the admin area.
So this is the home page you can see there's a big search box here with some fields.
I'm going to show you that in a second.
That functionality we have the latest listings so whatever the latest three listings in the database
those will be placed here.
Again we're using post-grads for a database down here is just some static markup with some services
and so on.
And then on the About page we have some about data and then we have some realtors OK so the realtors
can get added in the admin area and they'll automatically be shown here and there's going to be a checkbox
for Celera of the month so we can choose that in the admin area and now whoever the seller of the month
will automatically show up right here.
OK so some dynamic data on the About page.
This is the listings page.
So there's six listings total right now.
If I were to add one more it would add some pagination down here.
Right now I have it set to 6 per page.
So we have the main image the price some other data if I click more info that takes us to the single
listing page where we have you know breadcrumbs you have the title up here or the address we have the
realtor.
So realtors and listings are going to have a relationship so that on the listings page we can access
any of that particular realtors information that we want.
OK because the idea here is that each realtor will be assigned certain listings.
OK as you can see Cuyo Brown is the realtor for this listing here.
And we have a main image you have some smaller images that open up in a light box.
We're going to use something called light box 2 for this.
And down here we have some data like the square feet the lot size the price description.
We have to make an inquiry button if I click this it'll open up a modal.
Now if it were registered and logged in in the front facing Web site the name and email will be auto
populated from the database from that user.
I'm going to show you that in a second.
OK but let's take a look at the search.
OK so one of these has pool in the description.
So I'm going to search for the word pool and if I search you see we we go to this search results page
which has a form up here for we want to keep on searching and this is the result here.
So I'm going to clear that out.
You can search by like bedroom's.
So if I choose three bedrooms what it's going to do is it's going to look for any house that has three
bedrooms or less.
OK so it's going to be less than or equal to.
So if I submit you'll see that all of these these have three bedrooms this one down here actually they
all of the bedrooms.
But if there were two bedroom or one bedroom it would also show that OK if I say four bedroom submit
and I can see the four bedrooms included as well.
You can also go by price.
So it's two three bedroom and let's say four hundred thousand or less.
OK so that's how this is going to work.
Or less submit.
And we have to have one for two thirty one for 380 and they're both three bedrooms.
We can also search by state or city.
So let's say it's the this one's in Bedford so I'll say Bedford submit.
And there we go.
All right so the search is pretty simple it's not the most intuitive search in the world this isn't
Zillo dot com or anything like that but it's going to show you guys how to build query sets and how
to filter your data.
When you're when you're fetching from the database.
All right so now let's go ahead and register for an account case we have register and log in.
I'm just going to create a user called Let's call him Bob.
Say Bob Johnson and username Bob.
Email
password and let's register.
OK so we get a little message we're going to use Jango messages and kind of format them with bootstrap.
We also added a little bit of Javascript so that it disappears after three seconds so let's log in with
Bob case that takes us to a dashboard we get rid of this tells us we're logged in the message disappears
and the dashboard is basically just a list of any inquiries that you've made.
OK.
And up here you can see it says welcome in our username dashboard so obviously these links change once
you're logged in.
If I go to feature listings and let's say say were interested on this property make an inquiry and notice
that the name and the e-mails are already in here.
OK if you want you can put a phone number and message as well but that's optional.
So when I say send we get a success message saying they'll get back to us if I try to make another request
on the same property.
We're going to get an error saying we've already made that request.
OK so we're going to have that functionality if we go to the dashboard you'll see the Essex circle.
That's the one that we just made the inquiry to.
And if I say View listing it will take us to that listing.
OK.
So let's I want to inquiry for this one.
It could send and go to a dashboard and we'll see that here.
So that's the front end functionality.
Now let's take a look at the admin side.
I'm going to go to slash admen.
It's going to tell us to log out because Bob is not a staff user or are not logo but log in here with
an admin user so I'm going to put in my brad user which is the admin and you can see that we've customized
the colors to match the branding.
We've added the logo up here.
If we go to this site just see groups and users this is just standard Django functionality that's there
by default all your users and stuff like that.
But you can see we have realtors listings and contacts.
OK so any inquiries that are made will be put in contacts.
All of our listings are here and we can also choose to unpublished them.
OK this is not standard Gengel functionality we added this field is published in the database.
Let's say the United road we want to unpublished that I could uncheck and save.
And if we go back to the front facing Web site now we'll go to featured listings and you can see that
one.
What was that.
That was a United road you'll see it.
That one is now gone.
OK so we can publish an unpublished really easily if we go to one of these forms you'll see we can choose
a realtor.
So there's a relationship between the realtor and the listings.
We can upload images for the main image.
These are for the other ones published list state and so on.
And then if we go to realtors you know see we have Jenny Mark Kyle and if I go to Jenny notice that
is MVP is checked.
So I'm going to uncheck that and save and go to Mark Hudson and check is MVP and save and if we go to
the About page.
Now notice that Mark Hudson is now a seller of the month.
OK.
And whatever realtor you add is going to show up down here on the About page.
So that's that's pretty much it guys as far as the functionality.
So we're going to go through this course in a very just just practical manner as I would if I were building
this for a client.
You know so hopefully you enjoy it.
And let's get started.