All right guys so this is going to be the first video in the Python fundamentals section where we we
just look at at Python code.
Nothing to do with Django yet.
Just just basic syntax fundamental stuff like that.
So in this video I want to look at just the basics I want to look at variable's data types casting things
like that.
OK and if you already know Python then you probably know most of the stuff that we're going to do here
if not also if you want to skip this section entirely and move on then that's that's absolutely fine.
But if you haven't used Python before you're very very you know you just got into it.
I would suggest going through this section.
So starting off with comments in python we use a number sign for a comment.
I know that a lot of you are probably javascript developers those of you that have been following me
that you know follow my YouTube channel and stuff.
We do a lot of javascript where we use you know double slash for comments but in Python we're going
to be using the number sign now for multi-line comments there is something called a docstring which
has multiple purposes.
These are used often in functions to kind of describe what the function does.
But as you can see if you just use them outside a function they're there just ignored just like a comment
and you can use these.
It can either be single quotes or double quotes and there has to be three of them.
OK so just as this is a multi-line comment or docstring can be single or double quotes.
All right so as far as variable rules it's pretty much the same as as many many other languages are
case sensitive so.
So name all lowercase and name all uppercase these are going to be different very variables different
values.
They must start with a letter or an underscore.
They can have numbers in them but they can't start with numbers so these are very common rules for most
languages.
So let's go ahead and create a variable I'm just going to create when called X and I'm going to give
it the value of 1.
So in python we don't use semi-colons.
OK.
Like I said I'm going to be to I'm going to be referencing javascript quite a bit because I know that
a lot of the people that watch my courses in videos are javascript developers.
So going to reference it a lot.
And there's there's no semi-colons.
There's also not curly brackets and stuff like that but I'll get into that when we do when we do functions
and conditionals and stuff.
So this is how we can declare a variable.
Very very simple.
There's no VAR or anything like that we just you know just whatever we want to call the variable.
So I'll do that and then I'll put in another variable.
I'll do it say 2.5.
Let's create another one called name and I'm going to go over these data types in a second.
So this one I'll just say Brad.
And let's say is underscore cool and we'll set to true.
All right.
So I've created variables of different types here.
And Python has it has quite a few types.
The main ones though are going to be int.
OK so this is an int in integer for a whole number can be negative or positive a float which is a floating
point number or kind of like a decimal a string which can be really anything any string of characters
and you can use double or single quotes and then a boolean which is a true or false and booleans.
And in Python have to be uppercase have to start with an upper case.
OK so you don't want to do that.
You want to do that.
All right so we're just going to put some comments here.
I don't want to say ant and let's say this is a float and I want you guys to have this as a reference
so that you can go back to it if you ever need to.
So this is a ball.
It's actually called a ball not a boolean.
That's the the technical type.
All right so we can assign variables like this.
We can also do multiple assignments.
OK so if I want to do it say x y name and is cool.
And by the way you can do it this way with underscore or you can do camel case if you want like if you
want to do that.
I tend to do more underscore for just regular variable names.
I don't know why that's just what I want I kind of gravitated towards it but it's up to you how you
want to format your variables.
And then we can set all of these by using just parentheses and let's say one say two point five let's
say Brad and true.
OK so it's just kind of a shorthand to do exactly what we did up here.
So I'm going to just comment this self for a second.
Or not for a second but we're going to comment that.
And then I'm going to show you how we can actually output something so in javascript we usually do like
a console log in Python we're going to do print OK in Piatt Python too you could do print like this.
So if I try to run this with Python 3 we're going to get an error if I actually ran it with Python 2
we get one because in Python 3 we need to use parentheses.
OK so we want to stick to Python 3 syntax.
So it's a print acts like that.
OK we'll save that.
We'll go back down here and run it and we get one OK and we can print more than one thing if we want
to do all of them.
Name is cool.
And we run that you can see that it's going to print out all of our values here.
All right.
So I mean we can do like like basic math basic math if we want to do I could say a equals x plus y and
then we print a and from this we get 3.5.
OK if we want to check the type of comments in here so check type I'm just commenting it so you guys
have to go back to so we can do print.
And then we just wrap whatever we want to check in type.
So let's check will say x.
All right we'll save that clear up and run it.
This is just from this print up here but this is what we got.
So it just gives us class and because it's an integer if we do Y and we run that we get float if we
do name we get string and if we do is cool we get bored.
Ok so if we want to cast something like let's say we want to take this x value which is an end by default
and we want to define it as a string.
We can do that.
So if we say let's do casting.
So say x is equal to and then I'm going to just use s t r so if I wrap x in S T R It should make it
a string.
So now what I'll do is actually move this down here so we can check the type.
And I want to check the type of x K before it was an end.
But now I cast it to a string.
So now I can see we get class String.
OK if I want it to let's do y equals.
So why was a float I could change it to an int.
OK so if I ever do print type Y we get int and if I actually print the value of y ups you mean to move
that.
So if I print the value of y we get to K and N.
Initially it was 2.5 but it just basically rounded the two because it's in and it's a whole number k
if we wanted to change into a float.
Let's say we'll do what we did while say z equals and then we'll cast Y to a float K Y was initially
an integer.
So if we print the type of Z and we print out Z.
So you get.
So we get class flow because we change it to a float and then it adds point zero onto it.
OK because now it's a floating point number.
All right.
So hopefully that gives you an idea of how to create variables.
Some of the data types how to check the types how to cast to different types and stuff like that.
OK so that's it for this video guys in the next video I want to start to look at strings and how to
format them.
I want to look at some string methods and stuff like that.
All right so I'll see you in the next video.