Are you guys in this video we're going to look at some some different things that involve strings OK
strings or you know values that are wrapped in either double quotes or single quotes.
I'm going to show you how to format them.
Also look at some methods and stuff like that.
So first thing we'll do is let's create a string variable with a string and it's all say name equals
Bradd or whatever you want.
And then I want to show you how to concatenate.
So I'll say concatenate.
So if I want to print and will print a string We'll say hello world and save and then let's run this
by saying Python 3 strings dot pi we get hello world.
Now what if I want to put this name in here.
What if I want to say Hello Brad.
K what I would do to concatenate is I'd leave a space here in this string and then I'd use a plus sign
just like javascript.
Hey same exact thing.
And then put name.
So if I run that I get.
Hello Brad.
Now what if we wanted to put like my age in here which was an int case if I say age equals 37 and then
I wanted to do concatenate on say hello that's changed to how low I am Brad.
And then we'll do space.
And I am and then we'll concatenate on age and see what happens when we do that.
So going to clear this up and run it again.
Error says can only concatenate string not end.
So since this is an end it's giving me this error.
So what I could do is I could cast this to a string member we did that in the last video I could simply
wrap this in as TR.
OK so now if I run it we get.
Hello I am Braddon I'm 37 So now this is a string.
Now if you want to print strings out like this and you want to concatenate there's easier ways to do
this with string formatting.
So let's take a look at that.
And there's there's actually there's a lot of ways to do this.
I'm going to show you two ways one of these which is called strings is only available in Python 3.6
in the OP.
Ok but first of all we're going to look at his arguments.
I'll say arguments by position.
So if I say print and then and here I'm going to put in just empty empty curly braces like this.
OK so these are basically like placeholders.
So if I do a Daut format I can then put in here whatever I want to put in those placeholders.
Let's say a string of a string of B string of C..
Ok I'm actually going to comment on this can cottony up here.
And let's run it.
We get a b c.
Now if we wanted to do this in a specific order what we could do is we could put numbers in here like
let's say we want to do one and it starts at zero.
OK so it's 2 1 2 and then 0.
So you guys can probably guess what this is going to do.
If I run this way you get BCA.
So it's taken the one position and putting it here the one position is actually B because it's 0 1 2.
Ok so 2 is c and then 0 is a.
And it puts that here.
OK so that's that's using it by position.
We can also do arguments by name
I might spell some stuff wrong guys.
When I type I sometimes i just suck at spelling so I don't mind that.
And you know as long as it's in a comment.
So let's say print and let's actually do like a sentence like we did up above Bob will say my name is
and then what I could do is just use curly braces and put in that same name.
And I am and then H.
And then I could do a dot format.
OK just like we did above with the arguments by position and I could specify name equals Bradd age equals
and we want to string of 37.
All right so it's common.
So let's run this.
We get.
Hi my name is Brad and I'm 37.
And if you want to use these variables up here we can do that too.
Like name
meaningful age.
If we run that we get the same thing.
OK.
And there's no need to.
To wrap it in string like we did up here.
So that's arguments by name.
Now I want to take a look at something called strings.
So say f strings
only in three point six plus K I remember that we're using 3.7 right now and you should be using 3.6
or 3.7 at least at this time.
So let's say we want to do what we did right here.
My name is his name and I am and then the age so I can say print and just simply put an F right here
and there are quotes like this.
And you can use double quotes if you want and then I could say my
name is we have a variable up above called name.
And I am a judge.
OK.
So it's on that we get the same thing.
So it's looking at these two variables so instead of having to do Daut format and then assigning these
like that we could just simply take the variables above and stick them right in here.
So this is a much easier way of doing things.
And this is very simple is simple.
This is very similar to using template strings in javascript and ESX.
OK so makes things easier and you can return this as well you enough to just you know print it.
So now let's take a look at some string methods.
OK.
So I'm going to just create a variable called S and I'm going to say hello there world.
And we're going to look at some different methods so let's say we want to actually let's start off with
making these lowercase
OK so let's say
capitalise first letter.
OK so if we want to capitalize the first letter we can use a method called capitalize Sozzi s dot capitalized
You see we get the dropdown because we have the python extension installed.
So let's go ahead and run that.
Don't worry about the.
It's a method so a method is basically a function.
So it has to have these these parentheses.
And then we go hello there world and then the first one is uppercase.
OK if you want to make everything uppercase a copy this.
So if you want to make everything uppercase you can use the upper method.
If I run that is see here uppercase if you want to do all lowercase you could do that as well.
It's make all lower and simply start lower.
OK we run that everything's lowercase.
If you want to do a swap case let's try that's Swad case will say Prince Ascot swap case and then what
I'll do is make one of these uppercase.
So do that and see what we get.
OK it's going to be the last one and it does just that it swaps it.
So since this is an upper case it's going to do a lowercase here and then the rest are uppercase.
If you want to get the length of a string and this is not for just strings but this is for like lists
and dictionaries and pretty much anything then you can use the lende method or the lende function.
So let's say get Lang let's say print and this time we actually wrap it in the one function like that
run it.
We get 17.
OK if we want to replace something in a string we can do that.
So yes.
So we can use the replace method so if we say print dot or place and let's say we want to replace world
with everyone I'm going to clear this and run it.
And at the end here.
Hello there everyone.
So it will search for this and replace it with the second parameter.
All right if we want to let's say count something like let's say we want to count how many H's there
are in this in the string.
Let's say I'm just going to create a variable called sub and set it to H and then let's say print starts
count sub.
And if we run this we get one.
OK if I were to actually make this all lowercase.
So we have more than one way to make this a lowercase H and run it.
Now we get two.
Now I don't want to keep boring you by typing this out.
But there are a few more that I want to put in here so I'm going to paste them in and just quickly go
over them.
So you have starts with and ends with.
This will just basically starts with will start at the beginning and as long as it matches you know
we could put h here that would that would give you true H.E. would give you true halo gives you true.
But if you go out of sequence of what this actually is like if I do hello after something that's going
to be false and then ends with just starts at the back so ends with D would be true.
L.D. are L.D. that would all be true.
OK.
Next thing we have is split.
So this would just split it into a list which is which is like an array.
And I'll get into that.
I think in the next lecture we're going to look at the less fine position if you want to find the position
of any character.
So it starts at zero.
So this would be 0 1 2 and so on.
You also have is alphanumeric or is Al numb.
So if it's alphanumeric.
If it's numbers and letters if it has spaces in it this will return false.
OK here we have is alphabetic.
So with this just letters no numbers we also have is numeric and there's a bunch of them if you just
do like s dot and you'll see all the different methods that are available here.
OK if you go down.
So we have like is digit is space.
There's a ton of them.
So if you want to look more into string methods you can do that but I don't want to spend too much time
on it because it's not the most fun thing in the world.
All right.
So we'll get into lists in the next video.