All right guys and this video we're in it take a look at Lisse.
OK so a list is a collection which is ordered and changeable and it allows duplicate members a list
is basically an array if you come from javascript or Pietsch P or many other languages.
It's formatted just like an array and has a lot of the same array methods and stuff like that.
So I going to create a variable here called numbers and let's do one two three four five OK and then
we'll go ahead and print it's actually print the types if I see print type numbers and we take a look.
Whoops.
Clearly so.
And we're going to run Python 3.
Let's stop pi.
And you see class list.
OK if I were to type out numbers itself or print out numbers itself it just prints out the list.
So this is one way of doing it and this is the most common way let's say create a list but you can do
it another way and that's by using a constructor.
So to do that you would do like numbers
and then we would do a list like that and then pass in another set of parentheses and put in our numbers.
And if I were to comment so and save and run this you'll see the same thing.
OK.
So just a different way of doing it but this is definitely the most popular way.
You don't see this all that much.
So I'm actually going to create another array called fruits and going to set it to just a bunch of different
fruits so let's say apples
oranges
grapes and let's two pairs OK.
So we have this fruit survey and we can do multiple types as well like if I wanted to put an integer
in here I could certainly do that just to show you that that's not going to like throw an error or anything.
OK.
So I can do that.
It's it's not like like go laying or anything like that.
So we have this fruit's array.
Let's let's print out a certain index or a certain value.
So let's say we want oranges just like with just about every other language.
Lists are raised there or they're all zero based So this is going to be 0 1 2 3.
So all we have to do is print out and say we want oranges so say fruits 1 and run it and we get oranges.
It's a get value
OK if we want to let's say get the length of this list.
We could use the lende method just like we did with strings so we could say print when and then fruits
and it's going to give us the amount of values in that list so you can see we get four if we want to
append to this list.
We want to add something to it.
So what we do is say fruits and in javascript we would do push right.
In python we do append.
So say fruit's append and let's say Mango's and then down here I just want to print fruits and let's
run this and you can see that now Mango's has been added.
All right if we want to remove something we can do that.
So let's say we're move from west so say fruit's dot remove and say we want to move grapes and then
I'll print it out and I can see that grapes is now gone.
If you want to insert into a specific position I'll say insert into position
we could say fruit's dot insert and let's say two and let's say strawberries OK let's see what that
gives us if we run it in now Strawberry's is in the two positions 0 1 2.
All right if we want to remove from a certain position
remove from position we can say fruits and we could use the pop method.
OK so let's say we want her removed from the third position and we run it.
Now we get apples oranges strawberries mangoes.
All right.
I forget what was there before what was it.
Grapes.
I don't know what whatever was in the third position they removed.
If we want to reverse the array
I said array and yet I'll probably do that over and over.
Call the call list an array.
So and I'll probably call Diksha a dictionary and object.
I mean that's that's the thing you can learn so many different languages because a lot of the concepts
are are very very similar.
All right arrays in Javascript in lists in Python are virtually the same thing.
I mean there's a couple of different methods that are named differently.
But you can do the same stuff so it's easy to learn but sometimes the terminology you get mixed up with.
At least I do.
But let's go ahead and say fruit's dot reverse and go ahead and actually clear out and run it.
So now it's Mingos strawberries oranges apples.
So it's reversed.
Let's see if we want to sort it
we could say fruits Daut sort.
And now we get apples oranges strawberries.
Now it's ordered alphabetically.
If you want to reverse the sort you could simply say fruits.
Actually I'd say this is a comment or verse sort we could say fruits Daut sort.
And then simply pass in reverse.
Equals true.
And now we get it sorted alphabetically but it's reverse goes the other way.
All right guys so there's more methods in this if you want to look at the documentation you can do that.
But these are some of the really popular ones that you might find yourself using quite a bit.
So the next video I want to actually look at two things I want to look at something called tuples or
tuple and also something called a set.
OK so we'll get into that next.