All right guys.
Now we're going to take a look at tuples and sets which are two different data types.
We're going to take a look at two bills first which are collection which is ordered and unchangeable.
OK that's very important unchangeable allows duplicate members so let's go ahead and create a simple
tuple so to do that will create a variable I'm going to call it fruit underscore tuple and tuples or
they use parentheses.
OK so let's use brackets and tuples use parentheses and let's say Apple let's say orange and let's say
mango.
All right so if we do that and we go ahead and we print our fruit tuple and now we're one to make sure
you run the right file so Python 3 It's called What is it called tuple tuples underscore set start pi.
And there it is.
Those are our table.
So we want to get a actually before we do that I want to show you another way to create one and that's
using the constructor.
OK just like with less you can use a tuple constructor.
So if I wanted to say just copy this line here and we could say equals tuple and then just wrap that
like that comment that.
And that should give us the same result.
Ok so either way but I'm going to uncomment the first one in common this one no.
So if we want to get a single value
a single value so we could say print and say fruit tuple and just like as if it were a list we could
go ahead and put in a position let's say one and run it we get orange.
Now this is very important right here and this is that these are unchangeable So if I were to take that
position or that index and say equals let's change it to great.
I want to say cannot change values so let's try to run this and we get an error.
So it's this tuple object does not support item assignment.
K so it's constant you cannot cannot change any of these values and there's different situations where
you would use a tuple over a list and stuff like that.
Another thing to know about tuples is if they only have one value you should leave a trailing comma.
OK so the two tuples with one value should have trailing comma.
So for example if I say fruit tuple to.
And I wanted it just to have Apple what I would do is I'd say Apple actually let me show you what happens
if I print this out.
So say Print go to
website to comment.
So because it's throwing an error because I'm trying to assign something.
All right.
So we just get Apple like as a string.
But if I put an ending comma here and I print this out now it actually it it's the tuple.
OK so you want it and you want to include that because I noticed before I didn't have the parentheses.
If you want the length of course you can use the len
stew for a tuple
as if I go ahead and run that we get an error.
And that's because why is it unexpected.
Parsing
Oh I have a missing parentheses.
All right.
So let's run that and we get three so you cannot you can't delete individual items from the table but
you can delete the tuple as a whole.
So let's say this through tuple 1 we want to delete this.
We could just simply use del fruit table too and if I try to print that out or even a length of it we
get an error because true tuple 2 is no longer defined.
I deleted it using the Del del key word.
OK so now let's move on to sets.
So I'm actually going to comment though.
The prints here just so we don't get confused and we're going to move on to sets which are collections
which are unordered and an index.
And there's no duplicate members.
OK.
So it's important there's no duplicate numbers and sets sets use curly braces.
So what's it's clear that out and let's create a set.
OK so I'm going to say fruit from the score set.
And you want to use curly braces now.
Say Apple.
Orange and mango.
I will just say create set.
And if we go out here and print the fruit set and run this file shows us our set.
So if I try to add in Apple and I run this notice that it's not there OK it's going to basically just
ignore it because no duplicate members guy so keep that in mind.
But if we want to check to see if something is in a set we could do like and say check if in set so
we can do print.
And let's say our full in fruits and if we run that we get true.
If I say apples and we run now we get false.
If we want to add to a set
we can say fruit's set and we can use the Add method.
So Daut add in let's say Great.
OK.
So if we go down here and we print our fruit set and run that we notice that grape has been added.
If we want to remove something we can do that as well.
So I'm going to copy this and let's say Daut remove
say remove from set and now when I run it again grape is gone.
OK we removed it.
We can also clear the set completely.
So if we say fruit's that dog clear and we go ahead and run this and try to print it it's just going
to be just this empty set.
OK it's still there it's just there's nothing in it.
If you want to completely delete it then you use del.
OK so if we say Del fruits and we've run that then we're going to get an error saying that first set
is not defined so it's just like if we never even defined it at all.
OK so that's as far as we're going to go with tuples and sets in the next video we're going to take
a look at dictionaries which are very similar to javascript objects or Ruby on Rails or Ruby hashes.
They're very very.
They come in very handy.
And we'll be using them quite a bit in Django and you usually use them a lot in Python.
All right so we'll get to dictionaries next.