All right guys.
Now we're going to look at dictionaries which are collections that are unwatered changeable an index
with no duplicate members and these are very similar to javascript object literals and Ruby hashes and
even Jason so if you're going to work with Jason in Python a lot of times you'll you'll decode it into
a dictionary and I'll show you an example of that later on.
So let's start off by just creating a simple dictionary and we'll call it person.
And we use our curly braces here.
OK.
Now the key is going to have quote surrounded.
That's kind of a big difference between dictionaries and an object literals and javascript as we have
these quotes around the Keys.
So let's say first name and we'll say first name is a string of John.
OK then we'll do a last name string of dough and let's say age is an end of let's say 30.
OK so if I go ahead and print out this person let's see what happens.
I want to say Python 3
dictionaries dot pi.
Invalid syntax but that's because you put a frickin equal sign.
All right.
Start again.
There you go.
So print it out for us.
You can also use a constructor just like with the other data structures.
So what I'll do is copy this and I'll say person equals and we want to use dict like that except we
wouldn't do.
It's actually formatted very differently.
We do.
First name equals in the string.
There would have been better off just typing this in.
And then last name equals Doh.
And age
equals 30.
And we actually wouldn't want these curly braces we would want Actually yeah that should do it.
Take away that one as well.
OK.
So let's let's actually comment this out make sure we get the same thing right now.
And there we go so that's another way of doing it.
But I wanted to comment this one out.
All right.
So if we want to access a single value
then we can print person and in javascript to what we would do is say person first name right.
We use a dot in this case though we want to use brackets K which you can also do in javascript.
Actually I just never do.
I use used I always use the dot syntax but in Python We want to use the brackets and then whatever the
key is
so run that and you can see we get John.
OK.
Let's see if we want.
Actually there's another way we can access them as well and that's by using the get method.
So if we want to do print person Daut get and then parentheses and then the key.
So let's get a last name.
OK if we run that is c that we get.
So you can use either way if you want to add something to it like let's say we want to have a phone
number say add key value Obviously person phone
right now save it let's print out person.
And now you can see that phone has been added.
OK.
So they are changeable if you want to get just the keys say get keys.
Then we can print person Daut keys.
And I just want to show you if you want to get the values we can print person Daut items.
OK.
So save that and let's run it and you what I want you to look at is this right here.
So dict keys Keds is actually a view object and it gives you all the different keys.
First Name Last Name age and phone and then all the items which is going to give you a set of these
parentheses with first name John last name.
You know I guess these aren't really just not just getting the values it's getting a view object with
the items.
Now if we wanted to make a copy we could do that.
So it's a make copy so I'll say person too and sell it to person dot copy and then I'm going to take
person to and I'm going to add a city say city.
Oops.
No semi-colon see that's the javascript that made him the PDP and whatever other languages use semi-colons
and then let's print out person too.
All right so clear that and run it.
And let's see.
Person 2 is going to be this one right here that I added Boston to.
And obviously if I wanted to change some of the values I could do that as well.
So what about removing an item.
Let's let's get rid of the print out of person too and let's say remove item.
So to do that we can use del.
Let's say we want to remove the age.
So say a Dell person
age.
OK let's go ahead and run it.
And now down at the bottom here you'll see that there is no age value.
OK.
If we will actually there's another way to do this as well and that's using the pop method.
So if we want to do person Daut pop Let's see if we want to remove the phone.
So go ahead and run that and now the last one here just has first name and last name it doesn't have
age or phone.
If we want to clear the clear the dictionary completely we can say person Daut clear.
I saw run that and down at the bottom here just in.
It's just empty curly braces.
And again if you want to get the length of the list above but that's fine we'll say print Len person
to person to print the length of person to which is five.
OK.
So a lot of times you'll see a list of dictionaries.
So let me give you an example of that was a list of dictionaries so let's say people
said that to a list.
And inside here we'll have our dictionaries so like name say Martha age 40 and then will put a comma
here and then we'll do another one.
So name actually what I do here should should have quotes
age say 20.
All right so if we go out here and let's just print go the full list and down here you'll see we have
a list with two two dictionaries.
So again javascript people it's like having an array of objects.
And then if we want to focus on one of these like let's say we want to get the name for Bob for this.
This dictionary here I would say print people and I want the one index which would be the second one
because remember it's 0 1.
And then if I want to get a specific property I could go see a name so that should print out Bob so
if I go ahead and run that we look at the bottom we get Bob.
All right so hopefully this gives you a good idea of how dictionaries work.
Again very close to some of the other data structures and other languages if you know any other languages.
But yeah so in the next video I want to I want to get into functions because we haven't really talked
about the indentation syntax and stuff like that.
So we're going to get into functions indexed.