All right guys in this video we're going to talk about functions that if you have any experience in
other languages you know what a function is it's a block of code which runs when it's called.
Ok but in Python we do.
We don't use parentheses in curly brackets like we do in a lot of other languages a lot of C syntax
languages like javascript Python Java C-Sharp we do what we do is we use indentation and we use colons.
OK so let me give you an example.
So let's say create function and to define a function we don't do function or anything like that or
fonk we do DPF.
So define we're going to define a function called say hello and instead of doing this we do this with
a colon and then to be inside the body you just want to indent over one like that.
OK.
So this is inside the function this is outside.
This is after it.
OK so that's very important and if you're using a good text editor you will usually indent for you like
I just did for me.
So I'm just going to have this say print and let's print string.
Hello.
OK and that's just defining it to actually run it.
We need to call it.
So we'll say say hello and then down here let's say Python three functions dot PI and we get hello.
All right.
Now a lot of functions will take in parameters or arguments so let's say we want to pass in the name
and we want to just concatenated onto this name and then down here I'll pass in let's say I don't know
Sam and if we run this we get.
Hello Sam.
So what happens if we don't pass anything in and we were on this we get an error that says missing one
required positional argument of name.
Now if you want to have a default value you could easily just add an equal sign here and say Sam.
Now if I run it even though I didn't pass in a name it says Hello Sam.
And of course if I pass something in like let's say Beth that's going to override the default value
and we get.
Hello Beth.
All right.
Now remember in the variables file we have these these these triple quotes here and we use basically
just use them as comments here but these are actually dark strings and these are used to tell the user
what a function does.
So usually these will go in the function body.
So the first line here and we'll put triple quotes like that.
And then the convention is to start with an uppercase letter and then to end the periods so we'd say
like Prince.
Hello.
And then the name like that.
OK so you'll see this.
And it's just basically a comment.
It doesn't parse nothing.
It doesn't run or anything it's just there for the developer to see so that they know what the function
does.
All right so that's a that's pretty simple.
Usually you're not going to print something out from a function you're going to return something.
So let's say return value.
So I'm going to actually define a function called Get some shrieking.
Guess what this is going to do it's going to take in two numbers I say number one and number two.
And I'm actually going to define a variable in the function called Total And I want to set it to number
one plus two.
And then we would use the return keyword to return whatever the total is.
OK now I could just say return 1 plus 2 but I want to show you why I did this in a second.
But first of all let's say print because we didn't do a print in the function so that means we have
to do it outside and we'll say get some let's do four and five.
OK so if we run this we get nine.
Now another thing you could do and what you usually do in this situation is define a variable.
Let's call it numb some and we'll set it to that function say two and three and then we can print some
with no parentheses.
So basically what we've done is we've just taken the return value of the function and assigned it to
this variable.
So the reason I define this total in here is because I want to show you that if you go outside of the
function and we print out that variable if we do that we're going to get an error that says total is
not defined because functions have their own scope.
OK so whatever variables we define in this function they're not going to be accessible outside of the
function.
All right.
And I mean I could create another total variable outside and that's fine it wouldn't need it wouldn't
matter it wouldn't conflict or anything because they're are separate scopes.
OK so that's very important to understand and it's like that with most languages.
All right so let's create one more simple function.
So we get rid of this print and let's define we'll just say add 1 to numb and we'll pass in a number
in them will simply turn
say no only equals no plus 1.
Actually I'm going to do that.
I'm going to do
and then return.
All right so it's going to take in a number and it's going to set this number to whatever's passed in
plus one.
But an easier way to do this a shorter way would just be to simply do nothing.
Plus equals one that's a shorter way to do it.
OK.
And then if I go ahead and let's say
well defined no outside here and I'll just show you that it's fine to have some in here and outside
here so set that to five and then we'll say
new equals add 1 to none.
And I'll pass in Naam which is equal to five and then will print that out.
OK.
So if I run this we get six guy so down here I want to give you an example of what a lambda function
is.
OK so lambda is a small anonymous function it's a function that can take any number of arguments but
can only have one expression and they're very similar to two one line da javascript aero functions.
OK and I know I keep referencing javascript but these are very very similar if you understand aero functions
and you're going to understand this pretty easily.
So I'm actually going to recreate both of these this get some and add one to Naam in lambda functions.
So let's do get some.
To create a variable called Get some set to lambda and then we just want to put the arguments or the
parameters I'm going to say number one and number two and then we put a colon and then the function
body.
So we're going to do number one plus two.
Now notice I didn't do a return or anything like that.
You don't need a return statement just like you don't if it's a single expression arrow function in
Javascript.
So now I can go down here and I can say print
gets 9 to K and we get 11 so it's as easy as that if I want to do the add 1 to numb I could say equals
a lambda takes in one one parameter argument and then for the body I'm just going to do plus one.
OK.
No need to.
Typo return or anything like that.
And then let's say add two no and we'll pass in 10.
Actually let's do something that's going to equal something different than the last one.
I'll do five.
Run it.
And now we get six.
OK.
So those are lambda functions.
They're pretty easy.
If as long as they're simple like this but they can get pretty difficult.
All right.
So that's it for functions.
Guys in the next video I want to take a look at conditionals.