All right guys in this video we're going to look at conditionals if else statements which basically
are used to decide to do something based on a certain condition if it's true or if it's false.
So as you can see here we have some comparison operators like is equal to is not equal to is greater
less than greater than or equal to less than or equal to.
And then logical operators like and or not we have membership operators like not not in.
And then is is not what your identity operators.
All right so we're going to just kind of look at the basics here so let's create a couple of variables
will do x is 10 y y is 6.
And let's look at a simple IF statement.
So I'm going to say if x and then the comparison operator I'm going to use as equals to our equals or
equal to.
However you want to say it equal to Y and we want to put a colon so noticed that I didn't use parentheses.
No curly braces this is the syntax for an IF statement in Python.
And then of course we want to indent.
OK here we're not inside the if statement.
Here we are.
So let's just do a print.
And I'm just going to put an F string here so that I can take the variables that are above I'm going
to say x is equal to Y.
All right.
Now if I run this with Python three conditionals dot pi we get nothing because this is this is not a
true statement.
If I were to make it true and run it then of course would you get 10 equals 10 or 10 is equal to 10.
So if we want to put in.
Else let's do a simple if else and use a different comparison operator let's do of x is greater than
Y then we'll go ahead and do a print.
OK so we'll say x is greater than Y and ancy else and goes to a print and we're going to just change
this to less than
less than Y.
All right.
So let's save that and change the y back to 6 and run it.
So we get 10 is greater than 6 which is true.
We change the Y to 16 then the else should run and we get sick.
10 is less than 16.
OK so that's a simple if if else.
Now if you want to do more than one condition you can use and Aliff which is like an else.
If we could do like actually let's just copy this so you could copy that and then in between here we
could say Aliff and then another condition like x is equal to Y and then whatever we want to do we could
copy this print here and say x is equal to y.
OK.
So I'm going to comment this out and then run the file and we get 10 is less than 16 k if these were
to be equal then the this should run right here.
OK.
So we get 10 is equal to 10 this this one is also running that's why you see it twice.
And then let's see if X is less than the else should run this should run right here and we get 6 is
less than 10.
OK we can also do nested IFs.
So they nested IF.
So if I wanted to say if X is let's say greater than 2 and then I wanted to keep going and say if X
is less than or equal to 10 then I wanted to do a print
K to make sure that this is indented correctly and will say let's see.
So X is less than 2 and greater than 10.
All right and X right now is 6.
So that should be fine for that to run let's comment this
OK so we get 6 is less than 2 and greater than 10.
All right.
Now this is kind of a poor way of writing this.
I mean this probably isn't something you would actually write anyways but if you were to do that you'd
be better off using it and logical operator.
So you could just do if x is greater than two and instead of nesting just simply put and X is less than
or equal to 10.
OK and then you could just take this.
Put that in there.
All right so if we run this we should see it twice because it's running here and it's running here.
OK but I'm going to comment these action when to copy this one because I want to show you we can also
do or not.
So I could do or and then would be X is less than 2 or greater than 10.
So basically if we do it this way only one of these only one has to match or be true.
In this case they both have to.
OK so that's the difference between and and or.
And this is just basic programming logic.
We also have not.
So we could do like if not and then pass in like let's say x is equal to Y and then we'll do print
and say F X is not equal to Y.
All right.
So it's clear the sauted run it and we get 6 is not equal to 10 which is a true statement.
All right so let's move on here I'm going to just comment this stuff out.
I know these are the most exciting examples.
Guys I just want just for the beginners that are just learning Python I just want you to get a grasp
of the basic syntax before we get started on the fun stuff.
So membership operators these are not and not in these are used for things like checking to see if something
is in a list.
So let's say numbers create a simple list here and let's say let's do in so we'll say if x in numbers.
So what this is going to do is it's going to look at the x value which is 6 and it's going to check
to see if it's in this list.
OK.
So if it is I'm just going to print x in numbers and this will actually give me a true or false statement
or true or false value.
So if we run this we get nothing because this in fact is false.
If I do or if we change let's actually add the 6 to the numbers that way it is in it.
So out of six.
And if we run this we're gonna get true because this right here evaluates to true.
We can do NOT in just like we can do in
K so I can say if x not in numbers come in.
So if I run this we're gonna get nothing because it is six is in numbers.
So this doesn't get a chance to run.
If I go ahead and get rid of the 6 and run it we get false because this actually equates to false.
All right hopefully that makes sense.
And lastly we have identity operators.
So I mean this is pretty simple it's just is or isn't like we could do.
If X is Y and will print X is Y.
I just want to comment this stuff for you guys.
So this is.
So right now these don't match.
Let's make a match and then when we run this we should get true because this will if this is true and
then what we're printing X is why this will actually give us a true value.
So we get true at the same time we can do is not.
So it is not.
And then I'll change the values so they don't match.
And now this should.
We want to do is not this should evaluate to true because X is not Y.
And there we go.
All right so I don't want to spend too much more time with this guys.
It's pretty basic stuff but it's also very important for you to know for you know how to format these
things.
So in the next video we're going to start to get into loops.