All right guys.
Now we're going to look at loop's so a for loop is used for iterating over a sequence that is either
a list a tuple dictionary a set or a string.
So we're going to do here is create a list of people.
So it's a John will
Janet
and Karen.
All right so we have a list of people and I want to loop through them.
So when I say four Whoops I'm sorry for person.
The first one here is going to be whatever you want to use within the loop to identify each value in
the iteration.
OK then we want to do one in and then the name and the list so for person people and then we can access
each person.
So let's do a print.
So say print.
And let's just say current person and put another parameter of person.
All right.
So let's run this spicing Python 3 loops dot PI and there we go.
Current person John will Janet and Karen.
All right so if we wanted to let's say break out of a loop at a certain point I'm going to copy this
and comment it out.
I also want to do a simple for loop.
All right so let's say break ups break out
OK so this is the same loop but I want to break out of the loop if the person when the person is Janet.
OK so what I'll do here is go under the print and say if person so just doing an if statement comparison
operators is going to be equals and then Janet.
OK so if that's true then I want to break.
So let's see what happens if we run this.
So right after Janet it breaks it in Prince Janet because this runs before before the IF.
But if I were to move this down here and then run again it stops it.
Well OK so the positioning of the break really matters.
All right.
So let's say we want to just kind of skip Janet.
So in that case we could use a continue.
And he's going to say continue and I'm going to copy this first loop comment this one out and go and
pace that in and uncomment and in here I'm going to say if it's true if person is equal to Janet then
I want to continue.
OK I'm going to clear this terminal up and run it.
And now we just get John will and Karen.
So we wanted.
We skipped Janet basically.
All right.
Now we're going to move on to range.
OK so range is used to loop through something a specific number of times.
OK.
So it's a range
so we're going to do for I in range and then here we could for instance take the number of values in
this people list let's do that.
Remember we can get the number of values with the len function so we can say Lenn and let's say people.
OK.
So for as many times as show for as many people that are in there let's go ahead and print
and we'll do we'll say current person and here we want to say people and then we use the current index
so we do it like that.
More like a traditional type a for loop and we get current person and we get all their names.
OK.
And we can specify the range like manually it doesn't have to be the length of a certain list or anything
like that.
For instance if I want to do for I in range and I could say let's start at zero and go to 10 and then
let's just print oh say number and let's put it here.
All right.
So that gives us let's actually comment this one out.
So run that and we get what we actually get 1 through 9 because it's going to be up to this number.
So if I want if I actually wanted 10 I could go like that.
And that would give us 10.
All right so it's more like a traditional for loop.
So we also have while loops just like we do in many languages.
And while loops execute a set of statements as long as a condition is true.
Let me just clear this up down here real quick and then let's create a simple while loop so I'm actually
going to create a variable outside of the loop called Count I'm going to set it to 0 and I'm going to
say while count is less than or equal to 10 then I want to print and I'm going to say count and space
here and then let's do count.
OK and then we need to increment it so to increment it we're in the same count plus equals 1 which is
the same as saying count equals count plus 1 it's just a shorter way of incrementing by 1.
So let's save that exit's comment.
This part I will save this and we'll run it and we get count and we get up to 10.
All right.
So I think that's that's it for loops guys.
And we'll be using these throughout the throw the course in Django in the next video.
Want to take a look at module's these are going to modules are a huge part of Python especially with
web development you're always using different packages including different files.
So that's something that's really important to understand.
So that's what we're going to look at next.