All right guys.
Now we're going to look at modules modules are very important especially in web development because
you're constantly bringing in different things basically a module is a file containing a set of functions
to include in your application there's core modules the core Python modules.
We don't have to do anything you can just bring them in.
You have modules that you can install using Pipp which is the package manager including Django jingoes
install with Pipp and then broke basically brought in as well as custom modules so you can create your
own custom files and I have a file here that I'm going to I'm going to bring in and show you how to
use.
So let's let's first take a look at using core modules.
OK.
So one of that one popular one is Date Time.
So we can say import and then date time.
And this has just a it has a bunch of things associated with it.
So it has something called data which has its own methods and date actually has a method called today
that will get today's date.
So let's say we wanted to pull that out or create a variable called today and set it to date time which
we just brought in and then Daut date and then Daut today which is a method.
And then we'll go ahead and print today and let's run this with Python 3 modules dot PI and we get today's
day.
So seeing that this date belongs to this date time module we can actually pull this out we can import
it in a different way where we're not importing this entire thing but we're polling data out.
And the way that we would do that is by saying from date time import date that we were just bringing
in what we need.
So this is what you'll see most of the time.
So what we could do now and I'm just going to copy this because I actually want to leave this you guys
have it as a reference but what we could do now since we just brought in day we import a day we can
just say date today and that should work ok.
If I didn't have this line though and I just imported date time and I run it it doesn't know what date
is it's not defined.
OK so it's very important to know that you can basically pull things out like this.
So another example would be the time module.
OK so we could say in port time and it actually has a method called time so see when it's going to create
a variable here called time stamp because that's what it does is it gives you the time stamp.
So I could say time Daut time and then print
time stamp.
And here it is.
So this is the time stamp right here.
But again I could actually pull this out by saying from time import time.
And then I could get rid of this first one.
OK.
So around that I get the same thing I get the time stamp.
All right.
So let's take a look at it.
You installing something with Pip.
OK and we're going to be using Pip quite a bit later.
It's a big part of Gengel development.
Or basically any kind of web development.
So since we didn't create a virtual environment right now and we need to use Python 3 we also need to
use Pipp 3.
Ok so if we want to install something we use Pipp 3 I'm actually going to install something very simple
it's called camel case and it's used to.
For instance if we have a string with multiple words it will capitalize the first letter of each word.
It's just something stupid and simple that I can give you an example with because I don't want to bring
in something that's complicated.
So what we do is we would say Pipp 3 install and it's called camel case.
OK.
So let's go ahead and run that says requirement already satisfied.
So that means that I already have it installed now.
There's a command called freeze if I do Pipp 3 and then freeze and we take a look here this is this
shows me all the packages that are available that are installed basically and you'll see camel cases
there.
Now what happens when you create a virtual environment.
We'll get into this later.
Is instead of having all of the stuff that you install global like this you'll have a specific environment
and whatever you install while you're in that environment will be put in there.
But once you exit the environment it'll no longer be available it'll only be in that environment.
All right it's it's it's very similar to again going javascript It's similar to NPM when you install
something globally.
That's basically what we're looking at here.
When you install it locally it's specific to that project.
So that's kind of that's kind of how virtual environments work with Pipp.
But anyways we have camel case installed so we should be able to bring that in just like we could bring
any of these and so on and is going to go right here and I'm going to say Pip module and the same port
camel case and let's go
I'm going to get rid of these prints actually and move that right there.
OK so let's do camel is going to create a variable called Camel.
I'm going to said it equals two camel case Daut
camel case I like that.
And then let's just create some text.
So just put a string and I'll say hello there world.
And let's go ahead and print.
We'll take that camel variable and now is a method called whump and we can pass in text.
And what that should do is make each first letter upper case so save this.
Clear this up and run the modules file and there we go hello there world.
OK which is nothing special what it's doing isn't important.
I just want you to understand that we can install things with Pipp and then we can import them.
OK.
And there's a lot of great modules out there.
So now what I want to do is import a custom module so I have this validator dot py file and this actually
imports R E which is the regular expressions.
So this imports a core module and uses it in this custom function which validates an e-mail address.
OK so basically we're just saying if the length of whatever's passed in which should be an e-mail address
is greater than 7 then we want to return either true or false based on this regular expression.
OK so this is a regular expression that should match you know something at something Doc whatever.
You know the format of an email address so I'm going to bring this in this validator so I'll go right
here and I'll say custom
and we're going to do import I'll do it both ways so we'll import the entire thing.
Poort validator and let's go down here and let's create a variable called email and just say test at
test dot com which should pass and then we're going to do if validator Daut.
And as you can see there's a method called validate email so we can access that by saying validate email
even pops up here and via's code and we want to pass in the email.
All right.
So we'll go ahead and print email is valid and then we'll do an else.
And we'll print
not an e-mail.
OK.
We should be able to use it like that so I'm going to save this.
Let's actually get rid of that print.
So this is the only thing.
And we get e-mail is valid.
If I go ahead and put like let's replace that with a number sign and we run it we get not an e-mail.
All right so that's working.
Now we can do the same thing as we did up here where we where we basically polled methods.
Oh we can do that with the validator.
I could say from validator.
I want to just import validate e-mail and then down here I could get rid of validate or Daut like that
and simply use validate e-mail.
And if I run that we get the same thing it works.
All right so that's going to be it for this video guys in the next one we're going to take a look at
classes.