All right so in this video we're going to look at classes and classes are used to create objects or
basically blueprints for creating objects.
They have properties associated with them and methods which are basically just functions and almost
everything in Python is an object it is an object oriented programming.
But you can write code in different ways it doesn't have to necessarily be object in an object oriented
fashion like like like Java or something like that.
It's more like Pietsch P in javascript where you can choose to write in in certain ways.
OK so in this video I just want to give you an example of creating a basic class and also a little bit
of inheritance.
So basically you can extend a class from another class.
So we want to use the class key word here and then just name it.
I'm going to call a user just put a comment here Kirkgate class.
So we'll say class user.
And we inside of a class you're usually going to have a constructor or initializer say constructor.
And the way that we do this is we define a function or a method called double underscore and net double
underscore.
OK we go like that.
And then this is going to take in self now in many languages when you deal with classes you use the
this keyword which pertains to the class instance itself.
In python we use self instead of this.
OK.
And this needs to be passed into the constructor or into this this and net.
This initializer.
And then any thing that we want to pass in when we initialize the object we also want to pass in.
So let's say for this user we want name email and age.
OK so those will get passed in then we have to assign them to assign them as properties to the class
so we're going to say self taught name room remember self just pertains to the actual class instance
and then we're going to set that to the name that's passed in and we're going to do the same thing with
email and we're going to do the same thing with hopes with age.
OK.
So that's that.
Now I'm going to go outside of the class now.
So make sure that you're on the same level if your if your indented you're going to be in the class
so just make sure you are outside of it and they want to initialize a user object using this class.
OK so let's say in
user object.
So we'll call this user Brad and or you could do like User 1 or something like that but I'm going to
call it Brad and I'm going to say equals user and for name
I'll just put my whole name and then email
and age.
OK so this will actually instantiate or initialize a user object using the class and then whatever I
pass in here is actually getting passed in here and it's going to be assigned as a as a prop..
So let's say that I want to see the user's name I could say Print Save Brad Daut name.
So now I'm going to run Python 3 classes dot PI and I get the name OK if I want to see the age around
that I can get the page so we have we have properties assigned to this object.
So if we want to edit a property I can do that as well.
I'm going to go right above the print let's say at property and I could say Brad Daut age equals 38.
And now if we print out Dodd age we get 38 case we can directly access properties like that.
We can also create methods.
All right.
Before we do that let me create another one just so you can create as many users as you want.
So I'll just go ahead and copy this down.
Let's create a user called Janet
to say Janet Williams
is a 27.
OK.
And if I wanted to I could say print Janet Daut whatever.
Let's look at her e-mail and we get Janet's e-mail OK so we can instantiate as many user objects from
this class as we want.
So let's attach a method case close.
Right now we just have a bunch of properties.
Let's create a method and we'll just call this greeting where it just kind of says returns a string
basically.
So when I say define and we'll call it greeting and that's going to take in self K these methods are
going to take in the self and we're going to return and let's just return an F string so when you say
half and then some quotes and I'll say my name is and then to access that user's name for instance we
want to use self name.
OK and remember this is very similar to using this in other languages.
So self-taught name and I am let's say self Daut age.
OK so now we have a method attached to our user class and we can call this any user can call this method.
So let's go ahead and do a print actual do a comment here we'll say call method and we'll say Janet
doc greeting K methods have to have the parentheses because they're functions.
So let's go ahead and run this and get.
My name is Janet Williams and I am 27.
OK we can also edit properties if we want from methods so let's say we have one called has birthday.
So say has underscore birth day pass and self.
And then all I want to do here is just increment their age by 1 so also a self-taught age and wolds
we can use a shortcut here by just saying plus equals 1.
And that encouraged by one.
So let's go ahead and
let's.
I don't need to put a comment.
We're going to keep the greeting here because I want this output but I'm going to give.
I'm going to call that has a birthday on the Janet object so let's say Janet Daut has birthday and now
it was remember I was 27 before now we run it.
Now she's 28 because the birthday method ran witching incremented her age by 1.
OK.
So I mean that's pretty much the gist of it.
If you want to extend a class so let's say we wanted to create a class called customer and we basically
wanted to have the same properties and methods and stuff as the user.
So we're going to say class customer.
And to extend user we just simply pass it in like that.
All right and then I'm going to actually grab this and net and paste that in and I'm going to add on
to this.
Balance OK I actually you know what I'm not going to do that I'm going to do is I'm going to say self-taught
balance and going to set that to zero by default.
OK.
And then we'll have a method in here called Set balance.
OK so same self set balance that takes itself and it's going to take in a balance.
And then we can simply say self-taught balance is equal to whatever the balance is that's passed in.
All right.
So let's go ahead and initialize a customer so we'll go down to the bottom here will say in net customer
will call him John will say instead of use or we're going to do customer and we're going to pass in
same thing to John Joe
John at GM now 40 K so i can do a print John Daut name
and we get John Doe.
All right so let's let's set a balance for John so we can say John Daut set balance.
And that takes in a balance so say 500.
Now I want a way to check this.
I mean we could just we could do this
for grown now we get 500 but I'm actually going to I'm going to do is create a method that tells us
the balance and I want to actually overwrite the greeting to include the balance so we just separate
this with a comment.
OK.
So I'm going to take that reading method and put it in customer.
And I'm just going to add to it and say My name is name and I am however old and I owe a balance kind
of a greeting.
But I mean these aren't like very practical examples but I'm trying to give you just examples that make
your make it easy to wrap your head around.
So I would say self Daut balance now even though we changed it down here.
If the if the if the object is initialized as a user greeting should still just do this.
OK it should just say name and age however if they're initialized as a customer it should include their
balance.
So let's go down here and let's print out John Daut greeting and since he's a customer it should give
us his balance.
So it's run it and there we go.
So I know a balance of five hundred.
Now this the one before when we called Janet Daag greeting that one didn't include the balance because
Janet is not a customer she's just a standard user.
So that is so that other greeting was called.
OK so hopefully that makes sense you can overwrite the methods using you know using inheritance.
All right so I think that's it guys in the next video we're getting there.
But in the next video I just want to quickly look at file manipulation we can do certain things with
files we can create them we can write to files and so on.
So we're going to look a little into that next.