All right so as with most languages Python has methods for managing files creating them reading them
writing to them all types of stuff so I just want to take a look at some methods that we can use to
manipulate files.
So first thing I want to do is open a file and it doesn't even have to exist.
This will actually create it.
OK so we're going to create a variable.
Call it my file and let's set this to open case there's a method called Open where we pass in the name
of a file.
I'm going to call it my file and it's going to be a text file.
I want to be able to write to it.
So we're going to pass in W and we can get some info on the file.
Actually you know what.
Let's just run this let's save this good out here and say Python 3 files dot PI and just by running
Now I notice that now I have my file Daut text case that actually created it.
So we if we want to get some info on it we can do that and say get some info.
Well go ahead and print out the file name so we can do that by saying my file Daut name OK if we want
to get see if it's closed say is closed.
There's a method called closed and then the opening mode you have dot mode.
All right let's just see what this gives us if we run it.
OK so we get name my file that text is close.
False opening mode w.
OK so basically when we open it it's it's it's ready for us to to to write into it or to add to it append
to it whatever.
Once we're done doing that we should we're supposed to close it.
So let me give you an example.
Let's say right to file.
So we'll take my file and I'll say dot right.
And then we'll pass in what we want to write.
I'll say I love Python and then we want to close it.
So we want to say my file
Daut close.
OK so let's save that and then let's clear this out and run it.
And let's go to my file Daut text and there we go.
We actually wrote to the file using Python.
Let's say we want to do this to another right.
Right here.
And we'll add on to it.
We'll say I love Python space and Javascript.
OK so let's run that.
So take a look at my file that text and we get.
I love Python and Javascript so you can continuously write to the file.
So let's see.
After it's closed Do we want to add to it.
So let's say append two file case because now are pending to it.
So we're going to say my file equals open
it's my file Don t x t and we're going to put in a in here.
OK.
Because you want to append to it so.
Because if we don't do that it's just going to overwrite it.
If we do what we did up here it's just going to overwrite what's already there and I want to keep this
in here and I just want to append to the end of it.
So that's why we're using the a a flag there.
So let's say my file Daut right.
Even though we're doing dot right we opened it as a pen so it's not going to overwrite what's already
there.
So I'm going to put a space I'm going to say I also like ph.
OK.
And then after that we want to close it.
So I'll say my file thought close.
All right.
So let's run this.
And let's take a look and you can see that it didn't just overwrite it if I put a W here.
Actually I can just show you that I put a W here.
And we go ahead and run it.
We we only get I also like each piece so if you want to append to a file and not overwrite it you want
to make sure you put in there.
So if we run that then it's back to how it was.
OK so if we want to read from a file
we can say my file equals open and we want my file X T.
Except this time we want to do r plus K because this time we're reading from it's own going to say tacksmen
to create a variable called text and that said it to my file Daut read and let's pass in 10.
OK.
Now when I print no text.
Let's save this.
Clear this up and run it and you'll see what it does is it takes the first 10 characters of the file.
So that's what this is that's what this limit is if I put 100.
It's going to give us.
Well I mean there's not even 100 in here but it would give us the first hundred.
All right so we're not going to really be doing much of this throughout the course.
I just wanted to show you that you know you can do this stuff.
You can create files.
Our particular jingle project doesn't really require us to do this.
But again I just wanted to throw it in.
All right so in the next video I just want to take a quick look at working with Jason even though this
isn't really something we're going to do in the project either but it's always good to know how to work
with Jason because you know often you're working with third party API and stuff and Jason is the most
popular format so you want to know how to deal with that in Python.
All right so see in the next video.