All right Susan's video we're going to look at how to parse Jason in Python how to create Jason from
a dictionary stuff like that.
Now notice I called this pi underscore Jason up instead of just Jason PI.
The reason for that is because there's actually a module called Jason.
So we get an error if we try to call it Jason pi.
So that's the first thing we need to do is in port Jason.
All right and then I'm just going to create some sample Jason.
Usually this would come from some kind of AAPI you probably make a request and then get some Jason back
and then you can do what you want with it.
But I'm just going to kind of hard code.
It's also a user Jason and it would be formatted as you know double quotes for the key and the values
so I was the first name
John and let's do the last name
Joe and age.
And 30.
All right.
So that's that's valid Jason.
And what we would do is parse it to a dictionary.
OK so let's say parse to dictionary so will create a variable called user.
And what we would do is call Jason Daut loads.
OK Jason datt loads.
And again going back to javascript's hopes it's similar to doing.
Jason dot parse ok like that.
So we're going to pass in here the user Jason and then let's go ahead and print user see what we get.
So we're going to say Python 3 when I call this pi underscored Jason Daut pi.
And there we go so we get a python dictionary.
If we wanted to pull a certain value we can say print user outs to use her first name so we could do
that and we get John OK.
Now if we had a dictionary and we wanted to parse it to Jason we could do that as well so let's say
car equals and let's say make
say Ford model
Mustang year
1970.
All right.
So we have a dictionary here and if we wanted to parse this to Jason let's say a car Jason and said
this to Jason Daut dumps in passing car guy.
So if we go ahead and print car Jason it's from the file and there we goes.
You can see that this is now in Jason format.
So basically two important methods loads which is going to parse parse it to a dictionary from Jason
and then dumps which is going to take it from a dictionary and parse it into Jason.
OK so that's it guys.
I will see you in the next one.