All right guys so we're going to kind of look at this project as if it were an actual application we're
building for a client.
OK so for our client is Beati real estate and they want an application where they can you know have
a basic web site but also have the ability to have an admin area where they can add their listings they
can add their realtors they can connect realtors to listings and all that stuff.
So we have a folder here and you have this in your project files called Beati our resources and we're
going to take a look at what that folder includes.
OK.
So it has a couple of things that has an app requirements doc that basically gives us all the specifications
and requirements for this project.
We have an images folder with all the images.
We'll take a look at their logo.
And then we have their theme.
OK so in the next video we're going to actually dive in and take a look at the whole theme.
So it's basically the the Web site with no functionality.
OK.
So let's start off with looking at the logo.
Ok so very simple logo.
We're going to be using the white version on the Web site and then we also have a dark version.
Actually let me put this in a different view.
Let's do let's go like that.
All right so we actually have a couple of files to have a CD which is a photoshop file.
Don't worry if you don't have photoshop it's it's just a resource.
We're not editing their logo or anything.
This is the logo PNB G which is the white version and then we have the dark version.
OK so in addition to logo we have images and there's a couple for subfolder is one site.
And if we look in here we have the showcase image which is like the main the main image on the home
page.
Then we have a building Jay Pegge which you can use as a background image which mode which is used as
a background image in the theme and then the about image which goes on the About page.
All right.
And then we have realtors.
So here we have their team.
Basically it's a three person team.
Jenny Kyle and Mark.
So we have images of them.
Those will go on the About page we have.
And we already looked at that.
We have homes.
So these are the actual listing images.
So they have six homes that we need to add and then we have the home inside one through six.
These are just inside photos and we're just going to use these as the inside for all the homes as opposed
to me having six different images for every home.
OK so those are the images.
Now let's take a look at the app requirements document.
And this is just a doc file so you'll be able to view it in Windows or Mac or Linux.
So basically this would be like either what the client sends us or what I would suggest is if you're
dealing directly with clients is to sit down with them and get the exact requirements specifications.
So you know what you're doing and you guys are on the same page and they don't try to you know say well
are you supposed to do this or supposed to do this.
And they didn't pay for that so you need to come to a mutual understanding of what actually goes into
the projects.
OK.
So we have some front pages here.
These are the pages we need to create.
Again we have the theme already made for us and we'll just pretend that was created by a designer or
whatever.
But we have a home page about page listings single listing search register log in and dashboard.
OK as far as the design specs which are already taken care of with the theme we have the BTR logo that
is to be used on the front end and admin.
OK.
When I say front end I just mean the front facing web site and then the admin area then branding colors
so they have certain blue and green.
These are the hexadecimal values.
It's mobile friendly responsive and social media icons and contact info should be clearly displayed
and it doesn't have to be fancy but must be clean so that the design specs as far as the functionality.
This is the stuff that we have to actually make happen because right now we're just going to have an
empty theme that doesn't do anything it's just the UI.
All right so they want to be able to manage listings realtors contact inquiries and Web site users through
their admin area.
So they should be able to create read update and delete all of these things here and then roll base
users.
So this means that some of the users should be able to be staff and some not.
So most would not but there should be some staff users that can access the admin area display listings
and app with pagination.
OK so they do want pagination as opposed to just having a never ending page of listings.
Ability to set listings to unpublished so we'll have to figure out a way to have like a checkbox where
they can either publish or unpublished a listing that show on the front end search listings by keywords
city state bedrooms and price so those are the fields that need to be searchable.
Some will be input boxes some will be select lists and the search should be on the home page as well
as on the search page.
OK list realtors on a boat page with seller of the month control via adman's So they want to be able
to add and manage realtors in the admin section right while they want these realtors to also be displayed
on the above page.
OK.
So we have to do that.
And then they want an option of seller of the month.
So what we'll do is create a checkbox inside the admin area for Selar of the month and if that seller
or that retailer has checked off the no show on the About page as seller of the month.
OK we also have listing page should have fields listed below.
Meaning these down here we'll take a look at those in the second listing page should have 5 5 images
with lightbox.
I believe it's actually 6.
But we'll we'll get to that.
So a light box just means you know they want thumbnails and we should be able to click on it and then
have a box open up that shows the larger image and then this next one light box should scroll through
images.
So they want to be able to like have an arrow that we can click and just scroll through all the images
for that listing.
OK listing page should have a form to submit an inquiry for that listing.
So they want every every single listing page should have a form where they can put their name and email
and contact info and stuff like that.
All right.
And that form should go to the database.
It should also notify the realtors with an e-mail.
OK so we need to set up some kind of e-mail system so front and register log in to track inquiries meaning
that users should be able to register on the from the front end web site not as a staff member not as
an admin user but a regular user and they can log in and if they make any inquiries about a property
then they should be able.
That will be displayed in their dashboard on the front end.
OK.
And then both unregistered and registered users can submit a form meaning an inquiry if the if they're
registered in law then they should only be able to submit one per listing.
OK.
Meaning if they're logged in and they submit to let's say you know 55 main street and they try to submit
another one for 55 Main Street.
It should say you know you've already submitted an inquiry for this property.
So these are the basic fields they want on the listing page title address.
Most likely the title will be the address.
But we want the ability to choose something else if they want price.
Bedrooms bathrooms square feet lot size.
How many garages.
The listing date the Realtor of that property meaning their name and their image and then a main image
in five other smaller images with a white box.
OK impossible future functionality.
Google Maps on listing page and Beier testimonial.
So this is stuff that's not going to be in the course currently but I might add later on.
All right so these are all the specifications for the application.
So in the next video we're going to take a look at the theme and that will give us an even better idea
of what we're doing here and what it's going to take to to make this happen.