All right guys so I just want to quickly go over the bootstrap theme that we'll be using K so through
throughout the course we'll be plucking things out of this theme.
You know the HVM will be putting in two templates in Django but I wanted to go over it and I will be
doing a tutorial on how to create this theme from scratch.
And that's probably going to be on my YouTube channel when that happens.
I will add a note to the course if you guys are interested on actually building the theme.
I didn't want to include it in the course because it would be too much focus on bootstrapping aged team
Tim Allen CSSA and that's not what this course is about.
So a lot of times on a team you'll get handed something like this.
You know if you're if you're the back and the Django developer you'll get handed this and you'll turn
it into a real application.
OK so if we look over here you'll see a disk folder that's where all of the team pages are all of the
compiled assets like the CSSA all the boots decompiled bootstrap and stuff like that.
But also notice that we have a SPSS folder I use SAS in this project in this theme because I wanted
to really customize the bootstrap colors.
So I do these all these underscore files here are part of the bootstrap SAS that comes in the source
code and they edited the variables to match the the branding colors so like they're blue and green and
stuff like that.
So that's why you use Sassa also have a style dot SPSS file with all the custom styles.
So the Parshall's the underscores they don't get compiled.
The only two files here that get compiled into regular CSSA is going to be style and bootstrap.
OK so if we look at are deceitful there and we look ans assets CSSA you'll see the compiled styles file
compiled style file and the bootstrap VSS.
OK and this is the custom bootstrap CSSA file with those custom colors.
Now this all got CSSA is actually font.
Awesome.
OK I'm including everything locally I'm not doing any CD ends or anything.
So if there's like bootstrap 5 or 6 out by the time you watch this you have everything here and there's
no need to use a later version and then have to go and change classes and stuff like that.
So I'd highly recommend using all of these files.
I even included Jay query locally so you can see we have Jay query here.
Now you might be wondering what this light box is.
So we have a light box CSSA and Javascript.
This is actually from something called light box 2 which is the solution we're going to use for the
listing page for the light box.
No we want a light box too.
And it's this right here.
And I can give you an example.
So the reason I chose this is because it looks nice and because it allows us to do sets.
So if I click on this image here I can actually scroll through a set of images and that's exactly what
we needed for the requirements.
Remember when we looked at the document it said we needed to be able to scroll through all the listing
images.
So this is a great solution for that.
So that's also included in the theme.
All right.
So if we want to take a look at what this looks like you can either open up an aged him file or what
I'm going to do is use an extension that I have in vs code called Live server.
So say open with live server.
And here's the home page.
OK so basically we have the top bar here with the contact and social stuff we have now bar with the
logo home about listings register log in.
We have the main search with the main background image five fields.
Now we have the three latest listings.
OK so we have the the image the price.
Address some of the some of the specs here like the bedrooms and bathrooms the realtor.
How long ago it was posted.
Stuff like that.
And then just the services area just a static you know icons and text and then a simple footer.
OK so that's our home page.
Take a look at about.
So about all the inner pages have this kind of a title format so you can see they all have that with
the background building image and stuff.
We have breadcrumbs on the site so that we can navigate easy.
Home page is very simple.
We have the seller of the month.
Remember this needs to be controllable by the at through the admin area and then any realtors we add
in the admin area should show up here as well.
So this should be dynamic.
This shouldn't be just statically you know placed in the template.
All right now the listings page will look like this.
So we'll have six per page and then we need to have pagination and we also need to style that pagination.
We want it to look like this and then it had this.
These are basically just like the featured or the the latest listings on the home page.
So if I click more info it takes a single listing and this is the main image we have all those smaller
images with the light box.
OK so the light box is already implemented.
We just need to make the images the source come from the database.
OK.
And then we have all the fields we have the description the realtor.
OK so we'll be connecting realtors to the listings and then an inquiry motile so people can make inquiries
if they're logged in their name and their email should already be filled in here because we already
have that information in the database.
Then we have the search page.
So if I just submit this form it'll take us to search each team.
And basically the same as the listing page except it has the search fields appear in case you want to
keep searching.
And then let's say we have the register page which is very simple log in and then the dashboard which
I don't think we can get to from here so I'm just going to type in Dashboard daughter aged him now and
this is just where you can see your inquiries.
OK so if you made an inquiry to a listing it'll show up here and you can view the listing if you want.
OK.
And if you're logged in look like like this the requirements said if you're logged in and you already
made an inquiry and you try to make another one it shouldn't go through what should say you've already
made an inquiry.
So that's part of the requirements.
All right so that's basically what the the theme looks like.
So throughout the project we'll be plucking stuff out and putting it into templates and having you know
we'll be using the Jinja template system to make it dynamic.
And if you want to check out all the h t mail you can do that.
So it's pretty it's pretty clean pretty semantic.
We use section and header and footer and NAV and all that stuff.
All right.
So that's it guys in the next section we're going to get started on Django.