All right guys so before we start to actually install Django and work with stuff we want to create what's
called the virtual environment in Python.
And you want to do this because you want to keep all your packages and dependencies and all that isolated
inside of your project rather than in the global scope.
OK and this is a documentation page for Python 3 and this is the creation of virtual environments.
And before version 3.6 you actually had to use you to install a package with Pipp called Virtual ENVI
there's some other ones as well.
But now with Python 3.6 and hop you can just use the actual V and V package it's included with Python
2 to create your environment.
So you would run Python 3 or something.
Or if Python is Python 3 like on Windows for example you would just use Python and then dash MVP envy
and then whatever path you want to create that that virtual environment.
OK so I'm going to be using my visual studio text editor.
But before I get into that I just want to create a project and open it inside vs code.
So I'm in my home folder.
I do have a whip's folder called dev that's where I want to create my projects and get a CD into dev
and of course you guys can create your project wherever you want.
But I'm going to go ahead and do a make directory.
I'm going to call this project b t r e underscore project.
OK.
And then we're going to see D into b t r e underscore project.
And here's where I'm going to open my text editor so we're going to say code Daut that's going to open
up vs code inside that directory.
All right and if you're not using VS code just go ahead and open up your textedit are inside this directory.
All right so now I'm going to open up my integrated terminal I'm going to use this instead because this
is going to be using this throughout the course.
So if I were to do.
Let's see.
So we have we have PIP and we have PIP 3.
I'm going to say Pip three frees.
And what this shows us is basically the packages in.
And you know dependencies that are installed on a global scope on our system and we don't want this
we want to have we want to have our own environment for this project.
And I don't want like beautiful soup and all this other stuff included in that project environment that
virtual environment.
So let's go ahead and create a virtual environment now if you're on Windows or Mac or Linux.
The creation of the virtual environment should be virtually the same.
But to activate it is a little different so I'm going to show that you know the people on Windows how
to do it after how to activate it after but to create it it should be the same it should be Python whatever
your Python 3 is if you are on Windows and Python is Python 3 Like just do a dash dash version if it's
Python 3 then use that.
If not then you want to use Python 3.
And then we're going to say just like the documentation dash em and then VI envy and then wherever you
want to create this this V.N. the folder.
OK.
And you can call it whatever you want.
I like to just call it V and V and I want it in the current project directory.
So I'm going to say dot slash wiii envy.
And that's that's it that's where I want to put this.
I'm going to go ahead and run this OK and then notice up here.
It's actually created a folder called wiii envy.
Now if you're on Windows it may look a bit different.
You're going to have a folder called scripts with an uppercase ass and inside scripts you'll have an
activate dot batch file.
Ok on a Mac you'll have a bin folder with an activate file.
So that's where it kind of differentiates and how you activate.
Because right now we just created the environment we're not actually in it.
If I do a pip freeze we still see all that stuff.
So we're not we're not currently in that directory.
So I'm sorry in that environment.
So to activate that environment we want to on a Mac OK so this is on a Mac I'll do windows after.
We want to do source and then we want to just point to one source and then point to that folder so we're
going to say current directory dot slash and then wiii and VI.
OK.
And then we want to go to slash Ben and then slash activate.
OK that'll run the Activate script.
OK once I do that.
Notice that before my computer name here we have the ENVI inside parentheses.
All right.
So now we're inside of our virtual environment.
Now watch this if I do.
Just Python dash dash version remember was version 2 before.
Now it's 3.7.
So from now on when we're in our virtual environment we don't need to run Python 3.
Ok Python is going to is going to be Python 3 from now on.
So no more Python 3 no more Pipp 3 as long as we're in our virtual environment.
OK because we created this virtual environment with Python 3.
All right so now to leave the environment we want to say D activate.
OK that's it just deactivate.
And now we're out.
Now if I do a python dash dash version the global version is 2 for that.
So now we would have to do Python 3 for anything Python 3.
All right so now let me show you how to activate it in Windows.
Now when you created it like like where it's like this if if it didn't work for some reason do the absolute
path here instead of dot slash go like if you're on Windows like C you know C slash users slash whatever
your user name is wherever you put this V in the folder.
OK try that and then to activate it in Windows you want to do Python and then you want to go dot slash
V and the slash.
Actually no you don't need to even do Python.
I don't believe so just the and the slash and then instead of been you want to go into scripts and then
you want to do activate dot that.
OK so that should run your virtual environment if you're on Windows.
OK.
I don't believe you need the python.
If that doesn't work you can try it.
Also if this doesn't work try an absolute paths so start at your what C or whatever drive you're on
and then navigate to the V V V folder.
All right so try that.
If you're on Windows and that should get you into the virtual environment.
All right so I'm going to go ahead and activate my virtual environment again with this right here.
All right.
And if I do a pit freeze nothing goes so I have nothing installed in this particular environment and
that's what we want.
And then when we install Django it'll get installed in this environment if we deactivate the environment
it won't be installed in the global scope.
All right so hopefully that all makes sense and hopefully you're in your environment.
Hopefully you see this right here and in the next video we're going to install Django.