All right guys so in the last video we created a virtual environment so we have a folder called mind
B-tree project.
And then my virtual environment is called wiii envy and to activate that on a Mac we do source and then
we do go into our Wii and Wii folder and then bin and then activates.
OK.
And on Windows it's going to be the envy source slash activate dot bat.
And you don't put the source in front of it.
OK.
So now that we're inside the environment we know that because of this right here we want to install
Django.
OK.
So if we do a pip freeze right now you can see there's nothing there.
So let's do a pip install Django OK and this is only going to install it inside of our environment.
That's the beauty of this is it doesn't install it globally.
It's just in our environment.
So now if I do a pip freeze you'll see we have Django and it's dependency of Pi Z.
All right.
Now to to create a Django project we want to run Hey want to use a special Selye program called Django
Admin..
So if we say Django Dasch admin help you'll see that we have a bunch of different commands Harry of
stuff to deal with like migrations in the database ask you all stuff start app now.
I'm going to explain this a little more but Django has it has a project entity which is like your main
project and then apps.
OK so you have one project which is which is essentially your your main application.
In our case it's our real estate application but it's called a project.
And then inside that you have apps like we're going to have listings app for our property listings.
We're going to have a realtor's app for our realtors OK so stuff like that.
I'm going to explain more of that as we move along.
Now the command that we're interested in here is start project.
Okay so that's going to create a project for us.
So let me clear this out and let's run Django dash admen and we want to run start project and I'm going
to call I'm just going to call it free.
And then just put a dot for the current directory and let's run that.
And then up here you'll see what it's created.
It created the BTR folder with some files and I'm going to go over these files in the next video.
But it also created a managed pie.
Now this managed up pie we're never going to touch this code here.
This this is basically the tool we're going to use now instead of Django admen.
OK.
It has.
Actually if we do Python and you always need to run it with Python.
So Python managed PI help.
You'll see a lot of the same commands that Django admin has only it's more localized to this project
so we're always going to use managed up-I when doing like migrations run server will run our Python
server.
Create creates super user will create a user for our admin area.
So we're going to be using managed up-I quite a bit.
OK so now I want to address something that that mostly has to do with if you're using VS code so you
can see this little pop up down here of Linter Pioline it is not installed.
So you may have some issues if you use the Linter because it doesn't always recognize your virtual environment.
So you might get like inport errors said because it thinks that Django isn't installed because it's
looking at your global environment to fix this what usually works is you want to open up your command
palette with shit shift command P or shift control P and you want us to go to our search for Python
and you want the select interpreter OK.
And in that interpreter you should have your VTR in virtual environment and that's what you want to
use so I'm going to choose that.
And you should also be in your virtual environment here or in your command line whatever you're using.
All right.
And then once you do that you can go ahead and click install here if you want.
You can also disable it but I'm going to click install and now the the Linter should only be installed
in my virtual environment.
And also notice up here we have a special vs code config for the settings and the Python path is now
pointed to our virtual environment Python path.
OK.
Or location.
So now our lending should work correctly even if we're in our virtual environment.
All right so we're going to clear that up.
And now if I open up a python file I'm just going to open this up and now you shouldn't get that pop
up again.
If you do that means that you haven't selected the correct interpreter via your virtual environment
interpreter.
All right which should create this setting's file that I just showed you.
I know I can get a little complicated if you're having trouble you can you can post in the Q&amp;A and either
myself or someone else else can try to help you.
But I would suggest doing a quick Google search and you'll probably find the answer it's there's there's
a lot of information about this.
Now the last thing I want to do here is just initialize it get repositories so I would highly recommend
that you use get version control.
I'm not going to be doing my commits stuff on screen and you guys can do you know commit whenever you
want but I would suggest using it.
So if you don't have get installed you can either you can go to get dash SVM dot com I believe or dot
org.
Just search for get and then.
Or you can use like homebrew or if you're on Linux you can use your package manager whatever.
And then just do a get in net.
Cases that initialiser get repository and then let's create a new file in the root here called Daut
get ignore.
OK.
And what this does I know a lot of you guys know this but what this does is it allows you to add stuff
that you don't want to be pushed to or get repository would see what does this say has too many active
changes.
I don't want to see that but yeah.
So whatever you put here won't be pushed to the repository.
Now when you're dealing with a new framework it can be kind of difficult to know what you're supposed
to push and what you're not.
So what I would recommend doing is using an awesome Web site called Get ignore dot I O.
And basically you can just pass in the name of a framework or anything at all and it will give you like
a default good ignore file.
So let's say Django even has a little pop up and you can search multiple ones as well but let's just
for Django and it gives us kind of a default good ignore file that we can use.
I'm just going to grab this.
We're going to copy this and go over and paste that in.
And these are just comments we can get rid of these OK.
Now one thing I'm going to add here.
When you get rid of this as well I mean you can keep the credits if you want but I'm going to get rid
of all the comments.
But one thing I'm going to add here is the virtual environment because I have that in in this this file
or in this folder so I don't want that being pushed.
So I'm going to put a van or whatever you called that folder.
You should also put in there.
OK.
So let's go ahead and save that and I'm just going to do my initial commit here but unlocking it like
I said I'm not going to be doing all my commits on camera so I'm just going to say Get add all and get
commit and he's going to say and this show will just say initial comment in case that's now pushed to
my local repository.
All right.
And we're going to be using get at the end to actually deploy to push to Digital Ocean or to get hub
and then pull to digital oceans so you definitely want to get it installed.
All right so that's it in the next video we're going to go through some of these files here and talk
about what they are what they do and I will see you then.