All right guys.
In this video we're going to do a couple of things.
First of all I want to just run our server OK so Django actually comes with a dev server that we can
run and that's it will be used to.
That's what we'll use to develop locally.
And then we're going to take a look at the files.
OK.
And when we run our server it will actually create a file or two as well.
So let's go ahead and run it had to do this we use our managed up-I file remember when we did the help
we saw the run server command that's what we want to run.
So let's say Python manage Daut pie and we want to do run server.
All right.
So when you run this you're probably going to see this you have 15 unemployed migrations.
Don't worry about this.
This is normal.
I know that they make it look like it's some big error but it's not it just means you have migrations
that you haven't ran yet and that just has to do with like some of the the default apps that come with
Django like the like like The Office and the admin area stuff that that will be applied to the database
that hasn't been yet.
So don't worry about that message.
But you can see down here that it says starting developer server at 1 2 7 0 0 1 port 8000 and we can
quit the server with control C..
All right.
So let's head on over to our browser and let's go to.
We can use that loopback address or local host.
So if it's a local host port 8000 in there we go.
So now we have Django up and running.
All right.
Now I'm not going to I mean this is just the landing page here it's it's nothing special.
It's a lot better looking than the Django one landing page but there's really nothing here other than
links to documentation and stuff like that.
All right so we'll obviously replace this with our application.
Boy let's go back to the code and notice down here we have a bunch of stuff this is just the logs from
our server.
So every time we visit a page it's going to show the request and all that.
So when we run our server we're going to want to open up another file and just close that up.
We're going to want to open up another tab here for our terminal to run commands and we can switch back
and forth.
So if we want to go back to the server we can do that.
All right.
Actually what's on this first one here.
I can I guess yeah we'll use the first.
Why not get rid of the one I just created.
All right.
So our server is running Actually I'll just leave that one open but I want to now take a look at some
of these files so notice that this D-B Eskew a life three file was created when we ran our server actually
wasn't here before.
Same thing with some of the pie cache files here.
Now this D-B Eskew Alite three filed this is this is where your data will be stored if you use the askew
a light database which we're not going to be because it's not it's not a database you would use for
like a real production application it's nice for prototyping and testing.
And maybe if you have a really small Web site that has very little data very little traffic.
But it's not really suitable for real production apps.
But this is where your data would be stored if you were to use Eskew or light and even if there were
data here we couldn't read it within a file like in vs code.
We'd need some kind of client to view the data.
All right.
So we don't really have to worry about that.
And that's actually in our Get ignore.
So that wouldn't be pushed to our repository whether using it or not we could actually delete it if
we wanted to.
And then this pie cache folder you're not going to have to worry about this either these will be generated
when you run your server and you'll never have to touch them at all it does is really make your program
start a little faster when your scripts change they'll be recompiled and even if you delete these files
or you delete this whole folder it'll just reappear once you run your server again.
OK so no worries about that.
We're not really going have to worry about this in net.
Py file either.
This is always empty to begin with and we usually never touch it.
In fact I don't even think we need it after version three point three.
Because the purpose of it is to basically make sure that we can use files as packages and it prevents
some of the directories with common names like let's say string or something like that from unintentionally
hiding valid modules so it just keeps everything in order so that we can use packages but we don't have
to worry about that we're not going to touch it.
So the settings file is probably the most important one here.
I'm just going to make this small are you.
So this has just a bunch of like a key value pairs.
It imports the the os module which has to do with the operating system or package I should say not module.
And this base Durr is our projects base directory and where they're getting it by using a bunch of different
methods attached to this OS package.
So like OS path to our name and so on.
It just ends up getting us the base directory.
All right then down here the security key is for production.
OK so if you deploy a jingle Web site you never want this to be shared.
You want to keep the secret.
And later on when we get to deployment I'm going to show you how we can actually hide it so that we
don't have to like include this in our good repository or anything like that.
Let's see.
So de-bug So we have the option to set this debug to True or false which in development we want it set
to True but in production we want it set to False.
OK.
This gives us very helpful error messages and warnings when things go wrong it displays info about our
code right in the browser.
So in production even if something goes wrong you don't want that information displayed in the browser
because that anybody that's using your web site can see it and they can figure things out and say it's
a security risk so make sure that before you deploy you change this to false and keep it on true when
you're developing.
So loud hosts is basically just an empty area at first.
But when we deploy when we change debug to false you want to put a list of host domains that this web
site can serve.
So for instance the Digital Ocean IP address or any domain names anything like that should go in this
allowed Host List.
All right down here we have installed apps.
So Django has a concept of apps and you can have multiple apps per project like our listings app will
create will create a realtor's app but these here are actually default apps that come with Django by
default so we have like the admin which controls the admin area the off sessions messages all the stuff
is included with core Django.
Then we have some middleware.
So this is just a list of middleware that Django uses like the CSIR af.
This is for cross-site forgery a lot of this is security based but yet any middleware that is being
used will be put in that list.
And this route you are all.
This is just a string that represents the full import path to the route you are at a con where your
initial where your initial u r l file is.
This will usually be the name of your project which is Tiare and then you are Ell's.
OK templates are what are used to generate aged female for our application to you know to this display
to the user in the browser.
And this tells Django where to look for templates what options to use and so on down here W-S G-I application
this is the path of the WS G-I application object that jingoes built in servers use.
So when we create our project you can see a file here called W-S G-I dot pi.
And I'll talk about that in a minute.
So database's this is where you want to set up your database parameters as you can see the default engine
is eschewing light 3.
We're going to be changing this to post-grads while this is also where you put like your password and
your user name and stuff like that.
See off passwords validators.
So this is basically a setting where we just set types of rules for our passwords.
Not really going to get into that.
And then we have some stuff to do with like language and time and then the static right here.
This is actually the path that we want to use for static files like CSSA some javascript images things
like that.
And you can change this to something else if you want but we're just going to keep it at static.
So that's the gist of the settings file.
So now let's take a look at you or els dot pi.
So this is kind of like our routing file.
We have this URL patterns list and we put in paths so you can see there's one here for the admin area
and the path.
Usually you should have a forward slash at the end and then it can be linked to a view method.
OK so we have something called views and you'll see that when we start to create our apps and you can
link to a view method or you can link to the or else from another file like in this case we're linking
to the admin you are Ell's.
All right.
And then every app that we create like let's say when we create our listings app it'll create a new
folder called listings and we want to create a new you are Elle's dot pie in that listings app.
And then in this main you are Ell's dot PI We'll bring that in just like they did with the admin.
And then any specific route that we want.
Like let's say listings slash ad we would put that in the listings you are l py file.
Ok so this is like the collection of all of your your apps you are Elle's links which are look like
this.
OK.
And in a way you'll learn more about this later.
This is you know if you're confused don't worry about it.
I'll show you exactly what I mean later.
So this W-S G-I file this is a little difficult to understand you don't have to completely understand
it but basically it stands for web server Gateway Interface.
It's a specification that describes how a web server communicates with web applications and how web
applications can be chained together to process one request.
And it just has a lot to do with hosting your site so that other people can actually access it.
And we'll be talking more about that stuff later.
And you know when we get into the deployment stuff like that.
All right guys so we now have jingoes set up we have a server running.
So in the next section we're going to create our first app which is going to be our pages app.
I want to create a separate app for any any static like pages because we do want to have like an about
page so I want any anything like that the about page the home page should be part of the pages app so
we'll get to that next.