All right guys so now we come to the fun part.
Ok at least in my opinion this is the funniest part of the project and that's fetching data from the
database and displaying it in the front facing Web site.
So all of these listings we added in the admin area these are all in the database.
In fact if we go to PGE admin and we go travel down here to our database and to schemas public and tables
and we look in our listings table if we go ahead and just choose view edit data and then all rows you
can see all of our our fields in our database.
OK.
So we want this stuff to display here because right now this is just h t m l it's nothing it's just
markup.
So in order to do that we want to open up our fiest code and you want to open this file.
This is the views of Pi that's inside your listings app or your listings folder.
And we our already have index listings search indexes what we're looking at it's displaying the listings.
HVM Well OK and if you forget why this is displaying it's because in our URLs dot PI We have just slash
listings.
OK this is this represents slash listings and it's calling the index method inside the view file.
Ok I know it's been spent a little while so you might have forgot that but yeah that's why this is displaying
so the idea here is we fetch our listings using our model and then we inserted into our template and
then we can just simply loop through and output the listings that are in the database and in order to
do that we need to bring in our listing model so we're going to say from DOT models we want to import
listings.
OK and we can bring in any model we want into any file we want and we can use it.
So down here actually before before I fetch the listings I just want to show you guys if you've used
any kind of you know view rendering are you know any kind of MVC related framework in any language you've
probably seen this before but you can pass in values into a template and we do that with a dictionary
so let's say I wanted to do like name Brad.
OK so I'll save that and then I want I want to go to this file here listings dot age HTML and let's
say right here in this H-1 I want to output that value.
I would do double curly braces and say name.
So now if I go back and reload you can see that it all puts Brads So that's all we can pass values in.
So obviously I don't want to pass a name in or anything I want to pass in the listings but I just wanted
to show you how that works.
Now usually what I do when you see a lot is instead of actually putting the dictionary as the second
parameter will create a variable with the dictionary and then pass that in.
So for instance we'll go and we'll say all things context and set that to that dictionary and then pass
in context.
All right so you see this this format a lot.
Now we don't want a passing name we want to pass in our listings so let's fetch them from the database.
So the way that we do that is creating a variable.
I'm going to call it listings.
I need to set it to the model name which is listing and then dot objects dot all.
OK.
Now when I save this you'll see we get a couple of variables.
I mean a couple error is this.
This is just a warning we haven't used the listings.
We're going to use that right now actually so I can get rid of that.
I say listings and for the key will say listings and save.
Now we still get this right here it says listing has no object member and this isn't an actual error.
What's happening here is this code is not is not picking up that it's not picking up the Django special
functions in the pylons that we have and saw the Linter doesn't recognize it but there is something
called Pilot dash Django that we can install.
So if you're in if you're not see if you're not in vs code or you're not getting this error don't worry
about doing this.
But if you are just make sure you are in your virtual environment let's do a pip install and let's say
pi lint.
The Pioline dash Django.
OK.
Now just doing that isn't going to get rid of the error.
In fact I forget exactly what to put in here.
Let me just search this real quick so say Django has no objects member.
And the first stack overflow.
Basically they're having the same problem.
And you can see we just did this.
Now we want to add this in our area code.
So this python glinting and args and then pass that in.
So let's clear up grab that and let's put that in our setting so you can do go down to the gear here
and go to settings or you can do control or command comma and then I'm just going to pieces over here.
See go like right here and paste this.
Whoops.
We actually don't want these so we'll just do that.
OK.
So let me save that and let's go back to our views dog pie.
And now that that red line is gone.
OK.
They wouldn't have given us an error or anything it's just it's just lending it's just in the editor.
But that's how you can fix this.
So this will fetch all of the listings.
We don't have to do any rah like Eskew Well queries or anything like that.
And then we're just passing it into the dictionary here and then we pass that in the context into the
template.
So now let's go to listings and I want to go down to where we have this section for our listings and
we want to loop through these.
OK.
Inside our template we want to loop through and output this from here.
Basically the first listing.
We're not going to have six of these in here we just want one loop with this.
Basically the section of each team will with some dynamic variables here.
OK.
So let me see we're going to
try to figure out where to put this so we want.
Yeah we'll go right above where it says listing 1 so right in the row here.
And let's do our tags and let's say if listings I just want to first of all check to see if there are
any listings and I'm going to just do it here now and then I'll put all of the markup up here after.
So let's say if and then let's do one else OK else and then let's do and if.
OK.
So if the listings and Jeff let's take care of the else if and what this means is if there's no listings
in the database.
So if that's true then I'm going to put a div with the class of call M.D 12 which would take just the
whole row and then I'm just going to put a paragraph here that says no listings available.
OK.
Now if there are listings then that's when we want to loop through them and to do that.
We use a for loop and we can do that with the Jinja template syntax.
So it's put in our tags and let's say for listing in listings and then we want to end our four loops
so we do that with and for.
OK.
So what I'm going to do now is grab everything from listing 1 so this div down to where it ends here
and I'm going to copy that and I'm going to paste that in here in the loop.
OK.
And then we can get rid of all of the other listings so listing one all of this stuff up to listing
6 which ends right there.
I believe let me make sure that that that ends there.
So I'll actually delete up to listing five.
I just want to make sure that this ends at that div..
Yeah it does.
OK.
So I want to just delete that as well.
So this just made this file a hell of a lot shorter.
OK.
So now if the if the listings were fetched from the database and were passed into here and were looping
through them correctly it should show six listings but all have the same markup because we haven't added
any anything dynamic in here yet so let's at least try that will save.
And let's go back to our browser and go to that listings page and reload and there we go.
So you can see that it's still it's showing six listings but there are all this drive would circle because
it's just static markup.
We haven't added any any dynamic values in here.
OK.
So in the next video what I want to do is replace all of this stuff like the hard coded price and the
title address.
All this stuff we're going to replace this with dynamic values so that it actually shows the correct
data because right now it's not.
All right.
So we'll do that in the next one.