All right guys so in the last video we went ahead and took our basically took our model our listings
model and took out all the objects from the database and pass them into the template.
We also looped through those listings.
But right now we're just outputting static.
Each team all for each one we're basically outputting the same exact thing for every listing that's
in the database.
OK.
You'll see we have six here which is correct.
There's six in the database.
As you can see we added six but there's no dynamic data here so that's what we need to do now is fix
that.
So let's go to listings dot each team L and go inside our FOR loop here and just replace all the static
data with dynamic variables and we can do that by let's take this tile for example.
We can do that by using double curly braces.
OK so that's the template syntax for this.
Now when we loop through we said for listing in listings remember listings is what we passed into the
template.
And we're saying for every instance or every iteration I should say we're going to call it listing.
OK so we can say listing and then we can access whatever property we want.
So here we want the title.
So listing title.
So if I save this and I go back and reload and we look at the titles you'll see that now they're all
different.
OK so now they're actually reflecting the correct titles that you can see here that are in the database.
So we want to do that with every field that's here.
So another one we want to do is the image now Gengel makes it really easy by using that member that
image field that we used.
It makes it very easy because we can simply just do our syntax here and we can say listing and then
the name of the the image field which in this case is main What was it main photo.
Was it main photo or photo main.
It was photo main.
So let's do listing Daut photo underscore main.
And then we just want to do dot you are l.
So if I save that we go back and reload.
Now we get all of our images so these are the correct images that were uploaded.
So now let's do the price.
Let's leave the dollar sign and let's do listing price.
OK.
So we'll go back and check now it worked it's getting the correct number but we want calm is here OK
this doesn't this doesn't look very professional.
So you have a couple of options for this one simple option is to use something called humanised it's
actually an app that is not included by default in the settings but we can include it and then we can
use it and it has a method called into Khama that we can just simply tack on to listing dot price.
So what we're going to do is go into our settings.
So it's going to be Tiare settings up-I and there's a lot of files here kicking the can get kind of
confusing.
That's one thing I don't really like about the Django structure it always seems to just be just a ton
of files and if it's a big application but what we want to do is go up to our installed apps.
OK so right here installed apps and I'm going to go on to the end here and I'm going to do Django dot
con Trib dot humanize.
OK.
So that will just allow us to use human eyes.
Now we're going to save it and go back to our listings and we actually have to load it.
So up here we're going to put in our syntax like that.
We're going to say load humanize OK.
Now we have access to a whole host of different functions that we can pipe on to two different values.
So let's find our price right here and we want to just add a pipe character and then inte comma.
OK let's save that and let's see if it works or reload.
And there we go.
It automatically puts the comma where it needs to go.
All right.
And if we actually just want to show you something real quick if you search for Django.
Human is.
So this will actually show you his intercom.
This is what we just used and it shows you what it does converts an integer or float adds commas.
We have the AP number so return the number spelled out.
There's a whole bunch of cool functions that you can use with this humanised.
So just keep that in mind.
All right so let's go ahead and finish the rest of our fields.
So what else do we have here that needs to be added.
Right here we have the full address.
Now remember these are separate fields city state zip codes so here we're going to do
listing dot city.
And you can actually copy this and then this is going to be the state and then this is going to be the
zip
coyotes go around here square feet.
So this was I believe Eskew F.T. garage pieces and I will say listing dog garage in what else we get
bedrooms and bathrooms.
So listing
bedrooms listing Daut bathrooms
OK.
Let's see we have the realtor.
So since this is actually really cool since we have a relationship with between the realtor and the
listing we can just simply say realtor and whatever we put in the model for the realtor and we just
check real quick just to show you if we go to realtors and models dot pi.
This right here self-taught name is where we claimed what we want to display here if we just do dot
realtor which is really cool.
So that should display the name.
Now this this two days ago to be able to do this we can actually use part of humanised which is time
since so I'm going to just get rid of that and we're going to say SpaceX is going to be list date.
That's what it is in the database lists underscored date.
And then we can put a pipe in and we can see a time since and that will actually do exactly what we
need.
All right.
So let's save that and let's check it out.
OK.
So everything should be different for each listing of the address square feet garage.
All that stuff.
And notice the time since it actually gives you the hours.
So one day four hours which is pretty cool.
Gives you the realtor's name so everything seems to be intact.
All right.
Now let's see this right here.
Just goes to listing age Tamal that's obviously not what we want.
I'm trying to figure out if this would work yet because we we don't have our route for single listings
right.
We didn't do that yet.
Let me just double check.
So you are Elle's.
Oh we did so this route.
Here are the CRL is listing our listings slash and then whatever the ID.
So that's what we want this button to go to wups.
We want to go back to this and instead of just listing each team which doesn't make sense we want to
put in our tags and we want to do you are l and we want to say listing and needs to have an ID parameter
so right here we can say listing Daut ID.
And that should take us to the correct listings so let's save this and see if it works for you reload.
Now if I if I hover over this and you look down in the left in the corner you'll see listings slash
2.
This one's listing slash 4 slash 5.
So it just gives you the idea if I click on it we get this error.
So what it's saying here is the listing that they got an unexpected keyword argument of listing ID so
I can show you exactly why we're getting this error.
It's because you are Elle's we passed enlisting ID.
This is for the listing method OK which is in views dot pi which is right here.
Now when you pass in a parameter like that you also need to pass it in here.
So we need to actually pass in listing underscore ID.
So if I save that and we go back and reload that fixes that error and it loads the listing aged him
all template which we're going to get into in a little bit.
But I think what I want to do next is Hindle the pagination.
OK so I don't want just a never ending list of properties of listings.
I want to be able to page through them.
All right.
So in the next video I'm going to show you how we can implement that and also how we can style it to
look like bootstrap pagination like this so we don't just have like an ugly looking next in previous
or whatever.
We can actually have it look nice it might not look exactly like this but it will look similar.
All right so I'll see you in the next video.