Right guys we're going to start to look at adding pagination to our application for our ad for our property
listings.
Before we we do that I just want to address the little squiggly lines that pilot is now giving us for
not putting doc strings here basically comments defining what the method does and things can get quite
annoying sometimes.
So what I wanted to do is I'm just going to basically tell he'll tell the winter to shut up about stuff
like this.
So I'm going to go to my settings file you can do control or command comma or just go down to the gear
and then settings.
And I already have the python glinting dot PI args over here.
What I'm going to do is just add to this.
I'm going to put make sure we put a comma there and then I'm going to say dash dash errors.
Dash only.
OK we'll save that.
And let's go back.
And now those squiggly lines are gone.
So let's get into pagination Now this documentation here at Gengel project dot com This explains pagination
you want to go down to using paginate or in view and the first thing we need to do is edit some stuff
in our method.
Our index method we want to add a paginate are.
So basically we see paginate or equals paginate and we pass in.
In our case it's going to be our listings.
We say how many per page we want and then we go out here and we get the page from the get requests because
if you're on let's say Page two you're going to have a u r l parameter that says Page equals 2 and so
on.
You need to get that and the need to pass that into paginate or doget page.
So let's let's handle that first.
So we'll go to our index method here.
All right.
And then we already have listings equals objects at all.
So right underneath that I'm going to add in a paginate her and we're going to set that equal to paginate
or just like it said in the documentation.
And we're going to pass in the listings which comes from the database the variable above and then the
number of listings we want per page.
Okay and I'm going to do I want 6 per page but just to test things out I'm going to do three.
OK because we only have 6 total and we can't test it if we do 6 per page.
So when want say 3 per page.
Ok then we need to create a variable called page and set that to request dot get dot get and then pass
in here.
Page because that's the parameter we're looking for then we want a variable called Page underscore listings
and set this equal to that paginate or value.
And we want to say dog get underscore page and palps that should be an underscore.
And then we want to pass in page k.
Now instead of passing the listings directly into our context instead of passing this we actually want
to pass past in our page listings instead.
So let's do that let's just go right here and say paged underscored listings.
All right so that's the first part.
Okay that takes care of this.
Now I am getting an error saying that paginate doesn't exist or undefined variable paginate or that's
because we actually have to bring this in so up at the top here we're going to say from Django Daut
core Daut paginate or we want to import.
Actually going to import a couple of things here we're going to import empty page page not an integer
and paginate.
OK.
And now that paginate should be once I save that red line should be gone.
All right.
So like I said that's the first part that takes care of fetching from the database what we need.
Now we have to deal with actually displaying it the right way.
So if we go back to the documentation it shows us how to do that.
Except they're using contacts we're using listings but basically we can check to see if there's a previous
page we can put that previous page number or put a link to it.
So you see we would go to the URL and then the parameter of page equals and then the previous page number
down here we can see if it does next.
And then we can make a link going to the next page number.
Now you could simply copy this and paste it in but it's going to look like crap.
What we want to do is make it look like this.
OK like bootstraps pagination.
And if we look at the markup we have a UL of pagination class of pagination and then every list element
has a class of page item.
OK so that's really important to remember and then every link has as a class of page link.
And if there's no previous Then we want to have a disabled class ok.
Whichever one is active we have an active class so we're going to kind of combine this and this together
so that we can have a nice looking pagination.
But just to show you why reload this page we only get three three listings.
Now this here doesn't work.
This is just this is just markup.
We have we haven't added anything dynamic to this so let's head on over to our template listings daughter
aged him how and what you what you saw there is just this there's nothing there's nothing dynamic it's
just age you know.
All right so what are you going to do is I'm going to go see.
Let's first of all do a check to see if there are other pages for instance if there's six listings total.
And we put six per page than we don't want anything to show we don't want any pagination to show so
we want to wrap the whole thing in an IF statement.
So at our tags here and we'll say if listings and there's there's something called has underscore other
underscore pages.
OK so we will see if there's other pages and we want to end this down below the UL so down here we just
want to do.
And if like that.
And I'm just going to tab the UL over.
OK so that takes care of that part.
Now we want to check to see if there's any previous pages.
So let's go see and try to think if I should just delete all this.
And yeah you know let's let's get rid of all the allies it will just rewrite them.
So I just want to check for previous pages so we're going to do and pagination is always at least in
my experiments.
Experiments experience it's been a pain in the ass in Django actually makes it pretty easy.
It's one of the easier frameworks to deal with pagination and in my opinion.
So let's say if listings DOT has underscore previous.
When I keep putting a plus for an underscore.
So if it has previous And then let's do an NF
OK.
So if it has previous And we want to put an ally in I want to give it a class of page dash item they
should all have this class all the allies and then inside we want to tag with the class of page Dasch
link.
And as far as the Tref goes we just want to do.
It's going to be the current page and then we want to add a parameter of page equals and put in our
double curly brace syntax and say listings Daut previous pervious previous underscore page number on
a page underscore a number.
And inside here we get put like the word previous.
I'm actually going to put some some left facing arrows so we can do that with the entity of Ampere's
stamp L. A.
Q You go and put a semi-colon.
OK so give us the arrows.
Now we actually want to have an else so read here.
We're going to say else K else then let's say because remember this is if there is a previous item then
we want to link to to go back to the previous.
If there's not then what I want to do is have a disabled link so let's say my class of page item.
And also going to give it a class of disabled OK.
And then within here let's just put in a tag
and we're going to give us a class of page link.
So they should all have a class of page link.
And I'm actually just going to do a class I'm not even going to do in a trough because remember there
is no previous pages.
So I just want to have it like a disabled arrow link so I'll just put in another L A.
Q You know entity and that should do it for that.
So if I save this and we take a look and see if it shows anything it's free load.
OK.
So this is disabled.
Notice there's no pointer I can't.
It doesn't do anything because there's no previous on the first page.
So that's that.
Now let's move on to all of our links.
OK all of our pages are links to those pages.
So after this END-IF Well we're going to want to do is loop through our page range.
So we do this by saying 4 and this is all in the documentation that I just showed you were just doing
it in a way that styles it in with bootstrap for.
So let's say for I an
listings dot paginate or dot page underscore range.
OK so whatever that page Drange is and let's put our end for down here.
All right.
And then we want to do in site here and if
so we want to do and if listings Daut number
save listings that number is equal to that index and then we'll do and END-IF
OK.
So if that's true then let's put in line here.
This is going to be the active link so we're going to do ally we're going to have a class of page Dasch
item and also a class of active
K and then inside there we're going to have a link with the class of page Desch link.
And as far as the see we're not going to have in a track it's just going to be an A with a class because
this is the active page.
But in here we want to put whatever the index is so we're just going to go like that.
Right.
And we want an else.
So this list if listings number equals I want an else to this all right.
Here let's put in else OK and then we're going to put an ally.
Class of page item no active.
We only want the active if this is true if it's on the current page.
Otherwise we just want page item we want a class of page Dasch link.
And as far as the A-Trak it's going to be it's going to have a page queery and it's going to go to whatever
the value of it is like that.
And then inside here we're going to have eyes as well.
All right.
So let's save that and see what we get.
Ok so I'm going to reload and now we get one into one as you can see one is the active I go to two.
Let's see let's make sure these are different.
So you can see 18 Jefferson lane which is the latest.
Or is it actually we didn't even do it by by day did we.
We'll fix that in a minute but yeah now we can go to the second page.
Notice the parameter.
So it's question mark page equals two.
All right.
And we can go previous.
So now that there is a previous We can actually hit that and it brings us back to once this is working
perfectly.
The only thing we need now is the next day if there is a next or not.
Because right now we're on one so there should be a next button here to go to.
So let's let's finish up and do that.
So you have a lot of a lot of ifs here let me just make sure that we're in the right place.
And if
it's the so we want to be outside of the end for you know we want to go right after the end foreign
just like we did with the above.
We did.
If we say we said if listings dot has previous.
So we want to do the same with next.
So actually what I'm going to do is copy that and the else one do the same thing with the next.
So right up to the end for I'm going to pay set in and I'm going to change this to if it has next.
OK if it has next then we want to display a list item with page item we want in a tag with the class
of page link and instead of doing listings to our previous page number we want to do next page number
OK and that should do it for that except I want it I want the arrows to face the other way so we just
want to change the L to an R.
OK and then at the same time if it's disable our Or if the if has next is false meaning there are no
there is no next page.
Then we want a disabled link but we want it to be a right arrow so we want to just change that to an
R and that should do it save.
Let's go back and reload.
OK so now we're on page 1 so if I click the next arrow brings us to page 2.
And now it's disabled because there is no more there are no more pages to go to.
I can go back and now I can't go back because wrong page 1 and we can of course switch and if with the
more we have the more listings we have.
This should grow with it.
And just to prove that let's go ahead and let's change the initial number of listings to 2.
And that should give us an extra page so I'll change that to.
We'll go back and reload and now we have three down here.
Okay.
So we can page through all of them all three.
All right so we know that that's working that's good.
Now I'm just going to change this to 6 because that's what I actually want and if I save now the pagination
should go away very low.
There's no pagination because there's all there's six total.
If I add another one if I add a seventh listing then we're going to see the pads down here.
All right.
Now like I said I wanted to make sure that we ordered these by date.
So what we can do is go back to our view and go to our index method right here.
And instead of just doing it all we can do Daut order underscore by and we can pass in a value.
Okay we want to pass enlistee but I want it to be descending So we're going to do minus to put a hyphen
here list underscore date.
OK so let's save that.
Check it out for reload.
Now the earliest should be first.
Okay.
Now we really can't tell because they're all three days three hours because we added them all the same
time.
But I know that lexing Lexington was the last one that I added.
So that's what I want the most recent should be the first one here.
Okay.
Now one other thing that I want to do is make sure that if they're not published in the back end in
the admin area that they don't show if I go ahead and I whereas it a circle that's the yeah that's the
Lexington one so I'm going to unpublished this and save and if I go to the front end and I reload.
It's still there.
So we need to add another condition and to do that we can just easily change that on and we do that
with filter if we want to filter something out and then we can put the field that we want.
I'm going to say if is published case this is just whatever the name of the model field is and we want
to say is equal to true.
So now it shouldn't show anything where the public should only show if is published is true anything
that's false should not show.
So let's go back and reload and now you can see the Lexington House does not show.
OK if I go back and publish it and save and reload now it shows.
So that's exactly what I wanted to do.
All right guys.
That's going to be it for this video and I will see you in the next one.