All right guys so in the last video we went ahead and added pagination we made it so that only the published
listings show on the front end web site.
We also did.
We made it so that they're ordered by list state.
Now what I want to do before we move to like the single listing and all that I want to make the home
page listings dynamic the latest listings here because right now this is just mark up.
All right.
I want to take care of that.
I also want to take care of the About page because we have some dynamic data here that needs to be displayed
like the realtors and the seller of the month.
So we're going to work on that.
All right.
So let's head on over to vs code and we're going to close up the pie from the listings app and we're
going to open up views not pie in pages which I mean just close this too.
So don't confuse people close everything up and go to pages.
We want to go to views dot pi which is very simple right now it's just loading the templates.
I also want to go to the pages index study each team a template where we have the static markup which
is right here so listing 1 2 and 3.
All right we're basically going to do the same thing we did for the listings page except we only want
three listings.
No pagination or anything like that.
So in our view even though we're inside the pages app we can we can get any model we want.
So we want to bring in the listing model so we're going to say from listings basically from the listings
app models.
We want to import the listing model.
Okay.
And down here this is going to be pretty simple we're just going to create a listings variable set it
to the listing model.
I do want to order it by dates and when I say order and order underscore by and we want to do by list
date.
So just underscore day.
And of course we only want the ones that are published even though this is the home page.
We still don't want to show unpublished listings.
So we're going to do dot filter and we're going to pass and is underscore published and we only want
to show ones that are true.
And then I want to limit this to only three listings so I'm just going to pass on some brackets and
do Colan 3 that's going to say that we only want 3 listings and then we'll just create a context variable
just like we did in the other views file so intact in text context equals dictionary with listings and
we'll set that to listings.
Okay and then we just want to pass that into the index template here like that.
All right.
So that should do it so I'll save now we're passing it into the index each time.
We just need to now receive it and loop through them and display the dynamic data just like we did with
the listings each team I'll file.
All right so we're going to go right here.
OK right in this row and we just want to do the exact same thing just use a for loop loop through first
of all we want to check to see if there's any listings.
So for now I'm just going to go right here below the div. of Roe and I'm going to put in my IF statement
to check if there's any listings.
So if listings and let's end that if and if then actually we wanted the else as well
okay so if there if there are no listings then let's just put a what should we do here.
Let's put a div.
So we'll do a div call M.D 12 just a 12 column div in them will put a paragraph in will say no listings
available.
OK.
Now if there are listings that means we want to loop through them so we're going to go right here.
We're going to put in our tags and we're going to do a four.
So we want to save for listing our singular in listings plural.
OK then we want to make sure we end that for
and in here is where we want to put our listing mark up with some dynamic values.
And I'm just going to copy this listing one so this div to this div.
Can I grab that
and I'm actually going to cut it out and put it in the four because it's going to display that for each
one.
And then I'm going to get rid of listing to enlisting three.
OK.
So that's listing to just static stuff listing three ends right here so one can delete that as well.
All right so we shorten up this file quite a bit.
Whoops.
OK.
So let's go ahead and start to change some of this over to dynamic content.
So I'm actually going to Tab this over a bit
so we'll start with let's say the one to do here let's do the image.
So for the image it's going to be pretty much the same exact thing we did on the listings.
So we want to do listing Daut and the field name as photo underscore main.
And we just want to do dot.
You are L since it was an image field.
All right for the pricing.
I want to do the comma thing just like we did before and remember we used an app called human eyes which
we loaded in the settings file but we have to also load it up at the top to be able to use it.
So we're going to say load
humanised like that.
OK.
And then we're going to go down back down here and we now should be able to put in the listing price
so listing price and we can put a type character and say int comma case that should work.
Now let's do the title
see a title I actually like to put spaces on the ends here like that.
You don't have to.
But I think it looks a little cleaner.
All right.
And then what else do we have.
Here we have the the address.
So actually this the listing title and then I'm going to copy this.
And we have three different values here.
So going to paste in all of these and then we're going to change this first one to city.
We're going to change this one to state and this one two zip code.
Sort of reach into the database and they'll get those fields for us.
Then we have the square feet.
So I'm going to go ahead and say listing dots as q f t c with the garage.
So just
just copy one of these.
So this will be listing dark garage.
OK then we want bedrooms.
The bathrooms
Let's see.
So for the realtor we should be able to just do listing our realtor and that will automatically give
us his name
and then for the date
we're going to do listing Daut listee.
So list underscore date and then we want to add a pipe character and we want to use time.
Since.
All right.
Now for the more info obviously we don't want to link to listing each team.
We want to use you are l to make sure we're going to put this in our tags.
So we want to use you Arel and we want to go to listing and we also want to pass in the listing dot
I.D..
OK.
For more info.
So let's save that.
Let's go back to our home page type Object listing has no attribute.
Ordered by.
Let's see what's going on there because that's not right.
Listing Daut order by you know what I forgot.
Objects should be objects ordered by.
Sorry about that.
And there we go.
We have our latest listings and these are now coming from the database which is exactly what we want.
All right cool.
So the next step is for the for the about page K so for the about we want to have the the team members
of the realtors and we want to have the seller of the month as well.
So let's go back to the used up high in our pages we have about right here.
So that's what we want and want to do the same kind of thing except now we're dealing with realtors
so we need the realtor model.
So we don't just copy this down and instead of listing we want realtor.
And this is going to come from realtors dot models.
Ok realtors dot models import realtor and let's say we'll do comment here we'll say get all realtors.
So create a variable called realtors and set it to the model.
And we want to do Daut objects and I'm going to do order by hand let's do by hired de.
All right so ordered by hire date.
And let's see we also want to get the seller of the month.
Now remember the sell of the month has the MVP check.
If we go back to the admin area I don't think we actually set it for anybody.
So let's go.
Let's set up for collops we want to go to realtors.
Let's set up for Kyle Brown.
So right here the check I'm going to say is MVP.
Well go ahead and save that.
And now he should be.
We want to make it so that he shows on the About page in that section.
So let's go back and let's say get in the P and all just two MVP underscore realtors.
Now even though we plan on just having one MVP or seller of the month I'm just using these anonymously.
I still want to I still want to grab a group.
Basically there can be more than one.
OK just in case they want to add more than one.
So we'll set this to set it to the same thing real Turcotte objects stock order by.
Actually we don't want order by we're just going to do it all.
So dot all and then the filter.
So we want to do a filter is going to be by is underscore NBP it's going to look at that field and it's
only going to grab the ones that are true and checking that box off that they just showed you is going
to make that true.
So now we just need to make a context.
OK so we'll set this to a dictionary and we'll do realtors set that to realtors and then let's do MVP
realtors
so that too MVP realtors and then will just pass the context into the about perfect.
So save that and now we want to go to the about each team Al which is right here and let's start off
with just doing the whole realtors section so down at the bottom let's see we have like here team.
So we have this column this column all these call em d as these are all the team members.
So what I'm going to do is go right here above the first call M.D for and I'm going to check for realtors.
So if realtors I'd like to just do all my logic up at the top and then we'll just put in what we need
instead of just trying to wrap everything.
OK let's do one else as well because if there are no realtors we'll just say I don't know.
No team member is available.
OK.
So so for the else let's do a call dash empty dash 12 paragraph and we'll say no realtor's available.
And if there are realtors then we want to loop through them
so let's say for realtor in realtors and we'll end that for
and then we want to grab just one of these div with the call declasse of call em D4.
So just go ahead and cut that out and put that right in that for loop and then we just want to get rid
of the other two.
OK.
Because they're just static.
So this one and this one go up to here.
Get rid of that so shorten our page up good.
So now we just want some dynamic stuff in here like the realtor's name.
So we'll go ahead and replace that.
So realtor Don name and then the image or the photo.
So we have real door.
And we just called it photo I believe but it's a you are also want to make sure we put that in there.
OK we also want.
Let's see we have the phone number.
So it's a real to her dot phone
will do the email
like that.
And I think that's it.
So let's go back to the about and reload and go down and there we go.
So these these are actually coming from the database.
OK so what
see.
Let's take care of this now so Realtor of the month or seller of the month MVP whatever you want to
call it let's do that.
We're going to go back to that same template go up to right here.
So sell over the month are going to go in this call M.D four and we're going to check for an MVP so
let's say if MVP underscore Realtors like I said we're going to do our logic First up here.
I'm not going to do it but in house because if there's no MVP we're just we're just not going to display
anything here.
So we'll do the if and then if there is one then we'll go ahead and loop through.
So because remember it's going to return in our objects multiple objects but we're just going to make
sure that just one is checked.
But it is possible to check more than one.
So it's safe for the let's just let's just call a realtor.
We can do that in MVP realtors.
That's what matters.
And then we're going to do an end for
k and then I'm going to grab the card.
So this right here I cut that out and put that right in there.
And then just replace the name right here
with realtor dot name and remember they also have a description that's it's going to go here
like that.
OK so let's say actually the photo to make sure we do that
so let's see if we want to do realtor dot photo dot you are l and save.
OK let's go back and let's reload.
There we go Kyle Brown.
So let's test it out and let's uncheck Kyle Brown.
So if I do that we should have no seller of the month.
And let's go ahead and let's make Ginny JOHNSON So our of the month or MVP and reload and there we go.
So this is completely dynamic now.
All right good.
So next thing I want to do is focus on the single Wisting page so we'll make our queery for a particular
listing because when we click this it takes us to whatever listings slash and then the ID we want to
take that Id make our queery fetch that listing and then load the template.
OK.
Now for the template we're going to have to copy a bunch of H.T. mail from the bootstrap theme and then
more we'll just make it dynamic just like we did with these other pages.
All right.
So that's it.
I will see you in the next video.