All right guys soon this video we're going to start to think about the single listings page.
OK so when we go to our listings and we click on more info.
The road is all set.
The template is displaying But we want this to display the correct mark up as well as we want to reach
into the database and display the correct listing data.
OK so let's jump in the VS code and basically two files we're going to need to work on.
One is listings views dot pi.
OK because now we're dealing with this method this is the single listing.
And we also want to open up the template in templates listings and then listing it aged himself.
So these two files.
So first thing I'm going to do is get the markup.
Now remember I have in Sublime Text I have our bootstrap theme.
Just all the static data not data but static markup each time.
And we're going to open up a listing Daut aged mail.
We don't want to take everything because remember although like the head tag all that stuff that's in
the base lay out we don't need that we don't need the top bar or the nav bar.
All we need is from here.
So this section right here and we want to go all the way down.
To right above the footer I believe is what we want.
So right above the footer.
OK so we're going to grab that and we're going to first of all before I paste that in I'm going to extend
the base layout so I'm going to just to extend base Daut each team now they want to make sure we do
that.
And then remember everything that we want in this template has to be wrapped in a block.
So let's put right here we want to do block content and we want to end that block.
Another thing I'm going to do is load humanised because we're going to want to use that as well.
So we might as well throw that in now while we're here.
All right.
And then in between the block content I'm going to paste everything I just copied so if I save this
and we go back and reload.
There we go.
OK now it's just it's just static markup right now.
The form will open if we click the make inquiry because we do have the the each team for the the motile
But let's start to make this dynamic.
OK so in order to do that we're going to need to to reach into the model and grab this particular listings
data.
So to do that we need to go to use dot PI and down in the listing method.
OK we want to use de-listing model which we already brought in.
You can see we already brought that into this file.
Now I'm going to set a variable called listing singular and instead of just doing listing objects I
actually want to do something called Get underscore object underscore or underscore 404.
Now what this is going to do is it's going to make it so that if I go to like let's say listings slash
10.
OK if I go to that right now nothing happens but I want that to show a 404 page.
So that's what this is going to do.
It's going to check to see if it exists.
So we need to pass in two things one is going to be the model.
And second is going to be the primary key we want to set P K equals and then the listing underscore
ID.
Now this comes in right here and this listing ID is passed in through the u r l right here.
OK and if you look at the browser it's this here.
OK.
So now that we've done that let's go ahead and create our contex variable contacts not Konst So contacts
and we're going to set listing and let's set that to listing and then we'll pass in the context
that.
OK let's go ahead and save this.
Now this object of 404 you actually have to bring that in.
It's from jingoes shortcut.
So along with the render we hadn't bring that in so we'll say get underscore object or UPS or underscore
404.
I will save now that red line should go away and it should work.
So let's go back and if I go to listings slash 10 which doesn't exist we get page not found.
All right if we go to six slash six that does exist.
So that's going to work.
OK.
So anything I go to five that should work.
We have six total.
So we should have I.D. 1 through 6.
All right so now we've done that we should be able to access the listing data within the template because
we passed it in here with with the contacts.
So it's good to listing each team now.
Let's go up to the very top and I want the title displayed right here.
So we should be able to just simply say listing dot title.
Okay let's see if that works we'll go back and reload.
There it is 12 United road.
If we go back to the listings page and click on let's say Giffard that works as well.
So let's head back to listing dot HVM balance.
Finish this up so I'm going to copy what we just did here with the listing title and we're going to
do the same for the city the state and the zip code.
So this will be city
state
and zip code.
All right now down here in the breadcrumb we want to fix these links here so to go to the home we want
to do our tags and we want to say you are ill and we wanted to go to index and then this should go to
the listings page so this will be
you are Al
listings.
OK.
Now this here is the title again because this is in the breadcrumb so I'm also going to put listing
title here.
So whatever the title is will actually be in the breadcrumb and then for the listing itself this back
should be the same as this.
This right here your L listings.
OK we never want to do an H html page that that's just what we did for the theme.
So it's do you l listings and then down here we want the main image.
So I'm going to pay Sison and it's called Photo underscore main is the name of the field and we want
to you are l.
So let's just see if that works we'll go back and reload.
And there we go and you can see the title is now on the bright chrome we have our links to go back in
the breadcrumb we have the main image.
Now we want to do all of the smaller images underneath.
Right now they're not showing because this this doesn't exist this location.
So what we need to do is just put in dynamic values just like we did for the photo above.
So we want to do photo underscore one Daut you RL And we want to do the same thing for the image tag
so this should be for the link and the image tag that's how the Lightbox chooses the images.
OK so we want to just paste that in and let's do that for all of these.
So we're going to just grab that and the next one.
OK paste that in except to will the photo to answer the same thing here.
So highlight this to a control D to get the next one pasted in changes to three we'll do it here as
well.
Change this to control d paste save for 4.
All right.
And I'm going to show we get if we have to do another step after this because we might not have these
photos so we do have to do an if statement around them or will get an error or so let's go ahead and
put these in here this is for photo 5.
Can this last one here is going to be photo 6.
All right so let's take a look at that.
Let's save this.
Let's go back and let's reload.
Now this this particular listing happens to have six images so there's no issues and you'll see if we
open it up and we can pretty much just navigate through all the images which is part of the requirements
for the project.
But let's go back to a listing that doesn't have all of the images.
And notice we get an error saying photo four attribute has no file associated with it.
So what's going on is it's it's trying to load photo for when there isn't a file for it because we didn't
we didn't add photo four for this listing.
So the solution for this is just to wrap these in if statements checking to see if the photos actually
there because remember they're optional.
So where we want to put this is right above the call M.D to.
OK so we're going to put an if statement here.
You know we're going to do if listing dot photo underscore one.
OK that's it.
And we're going to end it after the div..
So we're going to do and fight that and right under it we're going to do another four photo two sort
of say a photo or two.
And what I'm going to do is copy the end if in the beginning if here go under this div pace that we're
going to check for a photo or three.
OK will go to the next one.
We're going to check for photo for next one.
Check for photo five.
Next on Fotos six.
And that's the last one so then we just need an and if we don't need this here.
So we'll get rid of that.
Now if I save and we go back to that page it just gave us an error and reload it works and it just gives
us the images that it has which is which is only three images and we can still go ahead and navigate
through them.
All right so that's perfect.
So now we want to move on to these fields because right now it's just static HD a mouse.
Let's go down a little further.
Let's go to our price here.
OK we're going to leave the dollar sign and we're going to say listing Daut price and remember we brought
in humanised.
That means we can use the pipe character and we can say it comma so we can add the commas.
Let's go right here.
Two bedrooms and this is going to be listing two bedrooms and I'm actually going to just copy this and
we'll do bathroom's
OK garage
and see what else we got square feet.
Is it Eskew T.
So we get squiffy we get lot size.
So right here I'll pass and listing a lot on their scores size.
And then for the listing date I actually do want the listing date I'm not going to do like the five
days ago or whatever that's on the main that's on the listings page on this I actually want to put the
listing date so will say listing Daut list underscored date.
And then we want our realtor since we have that relationship between the models we can just simply say
realtor and it will give us his name or her name and then the description.
OK want to replace this right here with the listing datt description.
All right.
Let's see then we have the the seller.
This all says seller of the month.
That shouldn't be there I'm just going to get rid of that because this isn't the seller of the month.
This is just who whoever the realtor of the property is and to get his name.
So right here we can just do just like we did above realtor.
All right.
Now see
think great here I think we're good.
You know we should be good for now.
We're not going to handle the increase yet I just want to get the actual day that displayed so always
photo for the photo.
What's cool about about the way that we created the relationship between the listings and the realtors
is we can get any realtor field so we can just simply say listing realtor dot photo dot you r l k so
save that let's go back let's reload and there we go.
So the stuff is all coming from the database if we go to a different listing Let's see.
By Mark Hudson we should see his image over here.
One thing I'm seeing though is this each six tags so something is off.
So let's go to the bottom here and just check that out.
Where is it.
That's the motile.
Yeah we just need to add that
ok cool.
All right so I think the next thing that I want to work on is the search.
OK so we have the the listing on the home page letus listings.
We have these listings.
We can go to a single line and we can go to them from the home page as well obviously.
So I want to work on the home search right here.
And once we submit this it'll go to a search it will show a search template which will look like the
listings page like this except it'll have another search form up here if you want to make another search.
OK so we're going to get into that in the next section.