Art guys who in the last video we went ahead and created the single page listings.
OK so these are now working for the inquiry form but we're going to get to that later.
What I want to do now is work on the search.
OK and before we do the search submission I want to shore up the template and let me show you what I
mean.
So if I go to pages index dot index each time how all of the select lists here I want to shorten this
up so all these states and and the bedrooms and prices so we can shorten this up by putting these values
into a python dictionary and then just importing them and looping through them and then just outputting
these from the loop.
OK so I'll show you what I mean.
I'm going to create a file inside the listings app since these have to do with listings.
And we're going to call this choices Daut pi.
OK.
Now I'm actually going to paste all this stuff in.
You can copy it or you can go to the final project files and you can copy it from there and paste it
in.
I'm going to go through it real quick.
Basically we have three dictionaries we have bedroom choices.
OK.
And then each one has a key a key value pair.
OK so the key is going to be used for the value attribute.
OK so for like the state this will be the key whenever we assign this will be the value.
In the dictionary.
So bedroom's we're just going to have 1 1 2 2 and so on pricing.
The actual value that's going to be searched in the database will be this.
This is what will be displayed to the user in the form.
Same thing here.
This will be searched and the databases will be displayed to the user base.
We just have all the states and all the prices and the bedrooms.
We're going to save this file and we want to go to our pages app and then fused up high because the
index page the home page is what we're working with.
So we want to bring that file and so I'm going to say from and since it's in the listings folder or
the listings app we have to save listings dot choices and then I'm going to say imports and we want
price choices bedroom choices and state choices and then we just simply want to pass them into the index
age him all through the contacts.
So I'm going to say state choices will be state choices.
Copy this down two more times and this one here will do the bedroom choices
bedroom choices and then this one here will be price choices
in price choices.
OK.
So now these are going to get passed in soon to save this.
And remember these are just separate dictionaries with values.
So now in the index each team now we're going to loop through each of these that have these option fields
OK and we want to have a value and just display text so let's start with the states.
I'm actually going to we're going to keep this because it's like the heading.
It just says you know what this is.
And then I'm going to get rid of everything else.
OK all these options are going to replace these and that's you'll see it's going to make this file a
lot shorter.
So just all the options keep the select.
So get rid of those.
And then we're going to loop through by saying for now we want the key and the value OK meaning key
and value not just the value so you could do whatever you want here you could do Cavey.
I'm just going to do key value like that and we're going to say in state underscore choices because
I was remember that was passed in.
And then we want to end the for loop.
So it's OK and for OK now for each one what we want to do is output we want to output an option with
a value.
So let's say option and the value is going to be the key and that sounds a little weird.
The value would be the key but the actual value of the dictionary is going to go here that's going to
be the text that displays like that.
OK so let's save that.
Now this should work if we go back to our index and reload we should see the same thing all the.
Well that's not right.
That is not right.
See what happened here.
So for key value.
Oh you know what it is.
We need to do dot items here.
I think that that should fix it.
Because up to that point it's just getting He is just getting the first letter.
There we go.
All right.
So now we have all the states and it's coming from that choices file.
So now let's do the same thing for the other ones I want to copy this whole for loop now for the bedrooms.
For some reason we don't have the value here but that's fine because we're going to have it now.
So going to replace all of these pay sat in and we're just going to say instead of state choices is
going to be from the bedroom choices dictionary and leave the same thing here.
Key value that's fine and let's do the same for price.
OK leave that.
Leave the first option and then just replace all of these.
And we're just going to change this to price choices dot items.
So let's try that will reload.
So for a state that works bedroom's good price good.
So now what I want to do is handle this submit if I submit it now it goes.
It tries to get a search done each time which isn't even a thing.
So we have to change that.
First of all so in our form Let's go.
Let's see where is the form.
Where is the form.
I'm missing you right here.
So as you can see we have action to search out each time.
We don't want that of course so I'm going to go ahead and put our tags in.
We actually want this to go to you Arel and then search.
OK.
So save that.
And if we go to our you Earles dot PI inside listings we have search right here and you can see name
equal search.
So what should happen is it should call this this view method the search method which if we look at
the used up high in listings we have right here and it's just going to load searched each time.
So what would she have and now once they reload and we submit it to just go to that search template
that's what we should see which right now just hasn't H-1 in it.
OK.
And if we were to put values in here like in the key words and city and cement you can see that they're
actually up here.
So these are get requests values.
So let's let's actually add the markup to the search page.
So I'm going to go to back to Sublime Text which has our bootstrap theme and there's a search for each
team page.
Obviously we don't want the top stuff the top bar nav bar.
We want to start let's see what is this.
Yeah we want to start right after the NAVs So this section here
is second so we want yeah because this is going to have this search.
Another search box in it.
So let's grab from here all the way down.
We're going to do the same thing with the choices that we did in the other form as well.
So scrabble all this OK down to right above the footer and then we're going to go back to let's go to
templates listings search dot reached him which is right here and we're going to paste all of this in.
All right so I'm going to just save this and then go back to our Web site and let's submit the form
so it brings us to that page right now.
I forgot to extend the base layout.
That's why we're not seeing any styling or anything so up at the very top.
Let's go ahead and
want to extends
beseeched him our dog paged him now and we're going to need human eyes as well so let's load that
OK and then we have to wrap all this stuff in a block so block content and then down at the very bottom
we want to end that block.
All right.
So I save that we go back to the search page.
Now we have the layout and as you can see there's a little form at the top.
And then this is going to be just like the listings page.
Ok except it's going to actually have our search results if we search for only Massachusetts we should
only get those listings.
All right.
We probably won't get to that in this video but I at least want to get our choices into the HDMI like
we did in the other forum.
So let's go to this time listings used up high.
In fact what I'm going to do is go to the other views dot Pi from pages and just copy this because we're
going to bring in all the choices into listings.
So up at the top here I'll paste that in and just like we did here we're going to pass in all these
choices.
So let's go back to listings used up high and we're going to go down to search and actually know what
we need a context here.
K they will pay so Zen
and pass in the context
and then we should have access to those dictionaries just like we did in the in the home page.
So from the home page I'm just going to copy one of those loops we did this right here.
And go to our search.
Aged hemol and do the same thing where we have our options so and go away up to the top.
See way up here.
So for pricing Let's leave the first option.
Replace all these OK so this is going to be price choices.
Guy.
This is going to be the bedrooms.
So one through 10 or replace that with price choices.
And then we also have states so we're going to replace those that are in that state.
All right.
And then one thing I forgot to do is on the listings used up pie we don't need to actually say listings
because we're already in that out.
So we can just do door choices and save and now go back and make sure that that form still shows which
it does.
Well two prices for bedrooms yet.
I must have good prices for a bedroom.
So let's go back to the search.
Each team will then go down to the bedrooms and right here I just want to change this bedroom choices.
Here we go.
All right.
So we have our search form.
One more thing I want to do before I go before we move on to the next video is the breadcrumb which
is right below it.
And we want to change.
Oh no we already did that.
Sorry.
OK so that's good.
All right.
So I think what we'll do in the next video is start to work on our queries so when we actually put some
search fields in.
It's going to get caught in this search method right here.
And we're going to have to make some queries we're going to base our extraction from the database or
the objects that we take from the listings we're going have to base that on whatever the user puts in
the search fields.
All right so I'll see you in the next video.