All right guys so now we're going to get functionality to this to search forms both of them.
Basically what we need to do is when we make a search like let's say we put like pool or something or
we choose bedrooms.
Any field we fill in when we submit we're going to want to first check to see if that field exists.
And then we're going to want to pull it out of the request or pull it out of the request I guess we
could say and put it into a variable and then we're going to want to base our query set based on that
variable we're going to want to filter by that.
So if they say state Alabama then we're going to want to put a filter for state of Alabama.
OK.
So we want to do this one by one and we're going to do this in the listings used up high in the search.
So right up at the top here I'm going to start what we're going to call a query set list and we can
build on to this.
So we're going to see a query set on this score list and I'm initially going to set this to the listing
model.
OK.
We're going to say Dot objects dot order underscore by and let's order by this date.
OK so this this query alone is basically just just like the listings page writes the same thing it's
just going to get all of the listings.
So what we need to do is just add filters for the search.
But I think I think what I'm going to do first is just pass it in like this so we can get the template
all set up.
I think that's that's a better idea so that we can actually see our results so let's go ahead and pass
in the contacts and we'll say listing our listings and hopes we want to set that to our queries set
list.
OK.
So now before we do all the search stuff here let's actually just render the what we're getting from
this in the template and we can do that by just copying just literally copying what we have in listings.
Each team will show up at the top here are not the top but right here where we check for listings we
do all that stuff.
We actually want the same thing in the search results.
OK so let's copy from here if listings down to the END-IF.
All right and then we're going to go to our search Daut Tamal.
And we want to put this right under the ROE So we want to get rid of listing 1 2 and 1 through 6 actually
right.
Six of them.
So when it go that's 5.
All right.
So that's down to 5 and I just want to make sure I'm right about where we're listing 6 ends so I'm going
to just highlight that div and it ends right here so I want to get rid of that as well.
Listing 6 Okay.
And then in this row is where we want to pace what I just copied
okay and everything should be the same really because it's coming in his listings.
Okay.
It will be filtered but for now it should just show all of the listings.
Let's say that let's go back to searched on each team L and see if that works so if we reload we get
all of our listings.
All right and we might as well add the pagination as well.
Actually no what I don't think I'm actually not going to keep the pagination here on the search Yes
let's get rid of this this mark up here where it is and that row is here that may or may not be in your
version of the theme because we're not going to use it.
All right so now that we're actually showing listings let's go let's add some filters so let's go back
to the used up PI and see how we want to do this.
Let's just start with searching for keywords.
Okay because we have a keywords field.
So when we go right down here and I'm going to just comment all the fields so I'll say keywords and
first thing we want to do is check if it exists so we can say if
keywords in request Daut get.
Okay.
When you make a request with this form it's a get request and you can actually test to see if it exists.
OK.
Now if it does let's to let's indent over.
If it does then we want to do keywords create a variable called keywords and we can get the actual form
value by saying request dog get.
And then inside brackets keywords OK.
So after we do that I'm actually going to do another if I am going to say if keywords.
And the reason I'm doing that is because I want to make sure it's not an empty string.
So if keywords then we want to take our query list or query set list and we want to set a filter on
it.
So we're going to do a query query set list Daut filter and remember the filter method.
And we actually want to search the description for any words that are typed into this keyword box.
So the way we do that is say description.
And if we're doing a search like that that's not an exact match like with our states we're going to
we're going to say we want to look where Alabama equals Alabama in that in that actual database field
in this case we want to search a whole paragraph for let's say the word pool or something like that.
So when we do that we use this double underscore after the field we're searching and we do I contains
OK because we're seeing if that paragraph contains this word and it's going to be keywords like that.
OK.
All rights.
So I think that should do it.
I mean we could probably just test it now so save.
And no we don't have great descriptions.
I think we just have dummy data.
Let's say let's reload ups we have an
sure what happened here.
All right looks like our service stops did something wrong.
Let's take a look.
I'm going to go into my server terminal OK.
So if keywords and requests get oh I forgot the code on it's an if statement so we need our coal and
parts and our servers running again.
Good so I'm going to go back and let's reload.
All right.
So if we look at like one of the descriptions it's I mean it's all this dummy text search for this word
here.
Pro-and.
So if we go back here and we say Parowan and search I think I think they all have the same description
so that that may not help.
Let's go let's go in the admin area and let's actually just add something to a description we can search
for.
So I'll go to listings go to thirty Esack circle and then the end here we'll just say has pool.
OK I'll save this.
So ideally you want to save it and then let's go back to the home page here and let's search for pool
and submit and there it is.
So we just have our Essex circle property because that's the only one where the description has poor.
All right so that's working.
And we should be able to do it from here as well.
This should go to the same place which it doesn't.
It still goes to search HD Maol So that's something we need to change.
So in our search each team will go up to the form and change this to
you are search
pools.
OK.
Now if we submit this with no search fields here we should get everything OK all the listings.
All right.
Now for the other fields here like let's let's do City next city is also a textfield but with city we
want to match the exact We want to match the exact thing if we put Chicago we want to match that exact
text string in the database.
So inside of used up PI here let's go under where we did the keywords and let's do City.
I'm actually going to copy this
and we're going to say if City in request get there we're going to create a variable called City
change that we're going to see if City
then let's do query list equals queery list not filter and we want the name of the field which is going
to be city but instead of contains We want to match it exact rights we're going to do I exact equals
and then the city very variable.
So let's go back and let's reload and let's see we have let's do Bedford
so Bedford's submit there go see we had Lexington actually.
We have them in the drop downs here.
Lexington good Norwood.
All right so cities working let's search with a lower case so what's to Lexington with a lower case
L OK and that works as well.
And the reason that that works is because I used I exact which is case insensitive.
OK if you want it to be case sensitive then you would just use exact.
All right so let's move on here.
Next thing we want is the state.
So let's copy this.
And if you ever want to add a field you basically just have to do this just add to the query set.
So I'm going to do a control d again again and again and again and just change them all to stay.
OK you can try that out.
Load OK.
So if we reload it still in the Get request.
So what I'll do is just go to the home page and let's just choose choose something we don't have like
Alabama.
So we get no listings.
OK now let's choose mass and we only have our mass listings.
None of the New Hamp none of the New Hampshire ones.
Good.
So that's working let's try the city and state together so if we do like Norwood Alabama and submit
that doesn't work if we do.
Nor would Massachusetts and submit that works.
OK.
And I'm going to show you guys in a bit probably in the next video how to keep your like if we put Norwood
in here and we search.
I want Norwood to stay in there.
OK.
So show me how to do that.
But let's finish actually being being able to search these fields.
So next we want to do bedroom's.
So when we grab that
you know we're going to change all these two bedrooms.
And again we're going to do exact.
Actually no I'm sorry we're not going to do exact since.
I mean there's there's different ways you could do this if you wanted to search for exact You could
but the way that I want this to work is if someone chooses four bedrooms I want them to get everything
up to four bedrooms.
OK.
So they shouldn't see anything 5:06 or anything like that.
I want them to just see what they what they're basically searching what they could afford which is a
four bedroom.
So anything up to that and you could make this more advanced if you wanted to you can change different
parameters and stuff but I'm just going to do up to four bedrooms so to do that we don't want I exact
you could do exactly like I said if you wanted to match the bedrooms Exactly.
But what I'm going to use here is LTE.
OK so this is it will basically be less than OK.
Less than or equal to LTE.
So let's try that.
We'll save let's go back and I forget exactly what bedrooms we have here sort of 5 3 3 3 4 3.
So we don't even have any two bedrooms so let's choose a let's choose three bedrooms and then this five
shouldn't show up.
This shouldn't show up.
OK.
So let's go back here and let's choose bedrooms
so choose three and submit and there we go.
So we only get the three.
If I choose four we should get four four and all of the theories but we don't see the five because that's
that's beyond our search.
OK we're not looking for anything more than four bedrooms.
All right so we're going to do the same kind of thing with the.
Actually we don't have a bathroom search that's right.
All right so we're going to do the same thing with the price though.
I'm going to say up to a certain amount because that's usually how people search and what actually I
just bought a house is what actually prompted me to build this application because I was using apps
like this to look for a house.
So it's changed this to price.
And then of these two price we're going to leave LTE and then that should be it that's dead should do
it for the search for go back home and let's say we want to price to do up to 400000 submit.
OK so that didn't work because this is showing that it should be showing 400000
OK that did work.
Three hundred thousand.
All right.
Let's go back to the home I think we might have something might have something to do with how this form
is set up let's choose 300 and submit.
OK.
So that's not working.
So what I'm going to do is head back to the index page.
So templates pages indexed age HTML.
Let's take a look at the price
OK.
And the issue here is that the select for price doesn't have a name.
So it's not knowing to look for the price.
So if hopefully I remember you guys probably won't have to add this.
I'm going to add it so you guys don't have to.
But just in case I forget for some reason just go ahead and put a name equals price.
OK.
But I think I'm going to fix that after this video.
So now if we go home and we go to 400000 and submit.
There we go.
So now it works because that name attribute that's what the server sees.
OK when you're when you're in your search here you're on your search in your views file and you're looking
at requests I get dog bedrooms.
What this is looking at is the field the form field that has the name of bedrooms.
OK this is looking for the field with the name of price.
If you don't have that name attribute it's not going to know what you're talking about.
OK.
So that's when you're dealing with server side that one in the front end the name attribute is the most
important when it comes to submitting a form.
All right.
And of course the action of the form tag because that that tells it where to submit to.
So in the next video I want to show you guys how we can actually make it so that when we search for
like a city it will stay at that point if we pick a state and we submit it doesn't go back to State
like this.
OK so we'll do that in the next video.