All right guys so in this video what I want to do is make it so that when we search something such as
bedrooms or price or whatever that it stays in the form once it shows us the results.
So to do that we're going to edit our search each time I'll file but we also want to go to our listings
used up PI.
And I just want to pass in something with our contacts so I'm going to add to this.
I'm going to add he's using me I'm going to add values as our key and then I'm just going to pass in
the whole get requests we're going to say request Daut get get like that.
All right.
And then whatever we search for if we put like pool in keywords then request dot get keywords should
be available to us as values dot keywords.
OK.
So let's go back to search a CML and let's go to our keywords right here and we're going to add in a
value attribute OK so it's a value and we'll say values which we just passed in through our context.
Key words.
Let's save that.
Let's try that out.
So if I go and we go to our home page and he's going to reload and search for pool and submit OK so
we get our results and now pool is still there.
If I search again for boards still there good.
It's exactly what we want.
So when do the same thing for City.
So we're going to add and value equals we want to have our quotes here.
So this is going to be values dot city.
Now the text fields the input fields like that those are easy because we can simply put a value for
the select list.
It's a little different.
What we want to do is have a conditional in here.
So we want to put an if statement and what we want to search is we want to say if key.
OK so if the key is equal to values dot state you know what we want to put this in here because the
way that we makes an option selected is we add selected like that but we need to loop through and decide
which one is going to be selected.
So this if statement actually needs to go within there so we're going to just cut it from here and go
right here after the double quote.
Put a space put my statement in and I think we can get away with doing this on separate lines so let's
do that just to make it look a little neater.
So remember right after the single quote here and we're going to put our F and then our END-IF
K so if the key K right if the key is equal to the key is actually the value of the option.
But if that's equal to values not stay then we just want to show selected.
Right.
So we're just going to put in here the words selected.
We want to add that as an attribute.
So that should work let's try it out.
So I'm going to go to the home page and I'm going to search for California and submit.
And now California is still there.
OK if I submit again even if I put let's say pool let's say city.
I don't know what's a city in California San Diego.
I spell that right.
I don't know.
Submit.
And they all stay good.
So let's go back and let's do the same thing for the other subjects.
So I'll actually copy let's see option key and then we did our if statement here.
So we're going to grab this just this just to the END-IF like that and then we'll go down to the next
option.
We want to go right after the quote After the key going to go in a separate line here and paste that
in TAB this over just to look a little better.
OK.
But we don't want to do values dot state because this is the bedroom field so we're going to save values
dot bedrooms.
OK whatever the name is because that's what's getting sent to the server.
So will do that.
And then down here we want the price so again right after the quote record here.
Place that in and we want to save values dot and this is price.
All right.
So that should do it.
So let's go back and I'm going to go to the home page and let's just do everything.
So poor city will say
Boston Massachusetts bedrooms for price 600 and submit and they're all still there.
OK and then we could change our search up.
So let's change it to something that will actually show up.
So say 600 and let's do nor would get rid of poor I think Norwood had four bedrooms.
There we go.
All right so our search searchers now working guys.
So I think they think the next thing that I want to work on is the authentication.
We want to be able to register from the front end log in them or work on our inquiries.
We also want to have messaging.
So for instance when we log in we want something that says you have been logged in stuff like that.
So Gengel actually has a messaging app that comes with it by default so we'll be using that.
All right so I will see you in the next video.