All right guys so now we're going to do is start to get into accounts.
We want users on the front end to be able to register to be able to log in and we're going to have a
little simple dashboard.
We want this functionality not so much just for that so they can see their inquiries.
But just to have the functionality in case you want to add something else later where it's you know
you have to log in to do something.
So most applications that you're going to build are going to have front front web site facing user accounts.
OK so I did want to throw that in to this course.
I didn't want to just make it you know only the admins had logging privileges because I think that it
wouldn't give you a full view of Django.
All right.
And I know that I I mean I can't cover everything in this project or in this course but I'm trying to
cover all the all the core fundamentals things that you're going to be doing a lot.
And obviously authentication is one of those things.
So I think that the first thing we need to do here is create a separate app.
OK.
And what I mean by app is like the listings realtor's pages these are all apps within Django.
So we're going to create an account app.
Ok so let's let's go to our terminal down here.
I have my server running in the other one so that's still running there.
And what's that actually what's the error right there.
Oh that's just for the Jay query loading.
If I don't have.
That's fine.
So we're going to go ahead and create a new app and if you guys remember we do that by doing Python
and we haven't done anything in the terminal for a while so manage dot pie and we're going to do start
app whenever we want to create a new application start app.
And this is going to be called accounts.
OK.
So let's go and run that.
And now over on the side you see we have accounts and we have all the default files here.
Now Gengel already has a user system in place so we don't have to create an account or use or model.
We don't have to do any of that stuff.
We're just going to use the the the the user table that is already in place.
So if we go to PGE admin and I guess I'll just leave this open here and you can see that there is a
off user table and it's probably not going to let me see.
I'm going to have to reload and probably am probably gonna have to rely again because it's been quite
awhile now.
OK so I'm going to navigate.
I do have to log in if you let it go so long without touching it.
You'll have to log in again.
So we want to go to our database and let's just check out tables and we want to look at Auth. user extend
that if we look at the columns you can see all the different columns so user name first name last name
email is staff is what is going to allow them to log in to the back end or not.
There's no super user or they have the last log in the date joined if the users active.
All that stuff.
And if we were to look at the data using Where is it to view data all rows we just have our one user
who is the admin.
OK so it's a super user and staff you can see as true.
So obviously when a user creates an account in the front and we don't want them to be staff we don't
want them to be able to log into the back end.
All right so I think the first step here is to actually have a route or a couple routes for a register
and log in.
We can at least load those templates case we're going have to create those templates.
So let's go to templates and going to close all these are or minimize these and in templates we're going
to have a folder called accounts and inside accounts we're going to have a couple of files log in each
team.
All we're going to do register HMO.
And then we're going to have a dashboard that's also part of accounts so it's create dashboard Daut
aged him.
All right.
So at least we have our templates.
Let's just put an H1 in here for now.
So this is Dash K H-1 this is
register and log in.
OK so we have our templates now let's go ahead and set up our routes.
So remember when we create a new app it doesn't automatically come with the DOT PI file and that's what
we need.
So we're going to create that in here.
So you are Elle's dot pi.
And before I do this before I forget we need to go to our settings so it's going to be in the Tiare
and then setting up high.
And we just want to add our app.
So I'm going to go below the realtor's app.
I'm just going to copy this down and this is going to be accounts config
and this is going to be accounts.
And that's something I always forget to do when I create a new app.
All right so you are also pie Let's actually copy from one of the other ones so we'll grab the listings.
You are up using Yarl's not pie and paste that in here.
So we're going to need four different you are Elle's.
OK so first one is going to be log in it's going to go to views Daut log and that will be the the method
name or the function name and the name will be log in.
Next is going to be register.
OK that's going to go to register name will be register.
All right.
And then let's see we also want to log out so log out that will call method Lago go in and then let's
copy this down one more this is going to be for the dashboard
spell right.
OK so Method views on dashboard
path dashboard.
All right now we're going to get these these errors here because we don't have the methods inside the
view.
So let's open up in the accounts folder we want the views.
Hi guys what's going on like this by default.
And we want to add all of our methods or should say views or their view methods.
So let's do register when I say define register.
And this takes in a request OK.
So this for this what I want to do is render a template.
So when you do render her return render.
And we want to pass in here.
First of all the request second is going to be the template which is going to be in the accounts folder
and then register for each team.
OK so that's that.
Let's actually just copy this because we need three more functions here or views.
You methods.
This one's going to be log in.
This will change that to log in will change the template that I want to load to log in.
So this is going to be log in each time now.
This next one is going to be the log out now log out isn't going to render a template.
It's just it's going to you're going to put some functionality here to log the user out.
But ultimately at the end what I want it to do is redirect.
So I'm going to say return
redirect and that's put in here.
So we want to redirect to index.
All right now to use redirect we have to bring it in and it comes in just like render does from the
jingle shortcuts.
So we just want to make sure we bring that in.
All right.
Whoops So last one here is going to be the dashboard method
and that's just going to simply render the dashboard.
And there we go.
Save.
OK let's go to PI and we just want to resave this and now we have no errors.
Good.
So let's try the trial the Rutz.
So if we go and reload these are still going to register dot HVM will log in each and.
So those aren't going to work yet we're going to fix that but let's go let's manually go to accounts
slash register.
OK so we're getting page not found Let's try logon
and start working either let's say using the oh we didn't bring in we didn't bring it into the main.
You are Alza up high.
So we need to go to BT houri you are up high.
We need to add here just like we did with the listings in the pages.
So we're going to see accounts slash.
So anything that is accounts slash we're going to include the accounts you are Elle's like that.
Okay.
So now that should work let's reload.
There we go.
So now we have accounts log in register.
Okay.
So now let's actually let's let's make the navigation go to the correct places.
So we want these links.
So those are in the nav bar partial.
So in the templates we want to go into Parshall's and underscore now barged him all down to register.
Okay so obviously we don't want this we want you are el
register and for log in
let's do this or no log in.
OK so let's try that out.
So it's load and click register that works good log in.
That works.
Now once we're actually logged in we were going to change is we don't want to see the register and log
in it for a log then that doesn't make any sense.
So what we're going to do is have conditionals that it's going to display a link to the dashboard will
actually have it say welcome and then our username have a link to the dashboard and also have a link
to logo.
OK but we'll do that later.
Before I end the video what I want to do is just go back to the template and just have the functionality
where the links are highlighted if were on those pages.
Obviously we're not going to see that yet because we don't have the layout but we'll just add the ifs
just like we did up here.
So I'm just going to copy this like we did for the listing and we want to go to the ally that's wrapping
the register link here and just basically just get rid of this class.
And right after the high here I'm going to just enter to go on the next line and then here's where we're
going to put the conditional cad's which sees over and all we want to do is change this to register
so if register in request path then it'll have the active class.
All right we'll do the same thing down here for log in.
So we'll get rid of this and go here paste that in its policies over and this is going to be if log
in OK we can't test it yet because you know on the template we don't have the layout but we'll do that
in the next video.
All right so I'll see you then.