All right guys so now that we have our accounts app created and we have but we're basically loading
up the correct views.
So if we go to accounts and we go to our CEO used up pi which is right here we're loading up registries
to mail log and aged him out.
So let's open up those those templates someone to open up log in age to e-mail and registry's to mail
and going to go back to my sublime bootstrap theme or bootstrap theme opened and sublime and I'm going
to go to Register.com each team now.
We're going to go down past the nav bar to this section right here where it says Id register and we're
going to grab that section and that's basically it.
OK we don't want the footer or anything like that and we're going to put that right in register.
OK.
Then we're going to grab.
Let's go back and let's go to log in each team and do the same thing.
We're going to grab section and that's.
Take that and we'll put that right in the log in each time out.
OK.
Now we have to extend the base layout so we're going to do that in both of these.
So let's do
extends based on age him now.
Let's see what else do we want to do we need to wrap this in the content block.
So I'd say block content and then at the end we need to end it.
Whoops wrong symbol.
So we want to do and block.
All right so we're going to save that.
I'm going to copy these two lines here and put that in register as well.
OK.
And then at the end we want to end the block as well.
OK so now let's go back and reload and let's go to register.
OK so it shows the registering.
Notice that it's highlighted that's from what we did in the last video.
Go to log in and we get our log in.
All right.
Now let's see.
We have all of our fields and stuff like for the register you can see we have username make sure we
have our name attributes because that's what the server is going to read when we submit the form as
far as where this gets submitted to.
It's going to go to accounts slash register.
OK so if we go to accounts used up PI it's going to submit to this log and we'll submit to this.
OK.
Even though it's rendering the template that's for a get request if we post to it then we want we wanted
to actually do the registration and the logon.
So in register dot each team Mel let's go up to the form tag which is right here and change the action.
So for the action we want to put in our tags and we want to say you are Al and we want it to go to counts.
Slash actually we should be able to just to register
it should be able to do that.
And we want to specify the method because by default it's going to do a get request.
We don't want that.
We want it to do post.
OK so make sure you do that and is going to copy this and then go into log HCM I'll go to the form and
paste the sin and just change this to logon.
Now one thing that's very important when you're when you have a form and you're making a post request
you want it you want to add a what's called a CSIR token.
And this prevents cross-site forgery So basically it ties it ties your form to the user's session in
the current session so that no forgery can take place.
It's just it's a security precaution and it's very very easy to implement with Django.
All we have to do is simply go right in the form tag put in our template tags and we just do C-s R.F.
underscore tokened guy.
So we want to do that.
I'm going to save this.
I'm actually going to copy this and we want to do this in the register form as well.
So right under the form and we can actually take a look at this.
If we go to the to the front end and reload and I'm going to open up my console here and let's inspect
the element.
OK.
So we want to go right here.
So see the form right under it we have this in this hidden input and this is the this is what we just
added.
Ok so you can see this is the token this long long string.
All right so that will prevent cross-site forgery.
So let's see if we have our forms in place they should submit to to our view methods much going to do
the actual logic.
But let's go to our views dot PI and when they get submitted we need to identify if the request to register
and log in is a post or a get.
OK so let's let's just put an if statement in here.
And we're going to say a free Quest Daut method is equal to post.
Ok so if it's equal to post then we know that it's the form submission.
So for now I'll just I don't know let's just do like a print and I'll say
submitted or submitted wreckage and then we'll just do a redirect just to make sure it works.
And we'll just redirect to register.
Same page.
Okay.
And then I'm going to have an else.
So else then we just want to show the form.
OK we want to render the form so let's save this.
And now where this will print out is in our console so if I go down to my console and my server is running
let's go here and let's reload and let's submit all we have to fill this stuff out.
Let's use your name and.
Test test Jeem now.
And doesn't matter.
We'll put some validation in later on.
But let's submit.
OK so we just it just redirected us.
But let's take a look at our terminal.
I mean our terminal here and we get submitted wretch.
OK so we know that a post request was made.
So that's all I want.
I want to do.
I'm I'm going to do though the actual registration in the next video but I wanted to make sure that
that's being submitted.
OK.
So let's just actually get rid of this the stuff in here and this is where our logic will go so we'll
say register user.
OK and then we're going to do the same thing down below I'm just going to copy this whole block right
here and replace this and just make sure we change this back to log in.
OK.
And this will be logging user.
All right.
So we're going to get an error here because actually why.
Yeah because we don't have nothing in here.
I mean we could just put a return like that.
It's sort of that OK.
Just so we don't have an error.
But in the next video we're going to go ahead and add our logic to register the user.
We're going to do a little bit of validation.
We need to for instance I'm going to keep a lot of the validation on the client side.
So basically what I mean is we have required OK sort of required here.
We could do min length if you want.
I'm not going to get too deep into validation on the client side.
Just some basic stuff like just the built in each team or five javascript stuff on the server side.
We need to make sure that these passwords match.
OK.
Another thing we want to do is check the e-mail to make sure that there is not already an e-mail in
the system that matches that as well as the username.
OK so we need to check that.
And I think that's that'll do it.
So and then we'll just register the user which is actually very easy.
OK another thing we want to do is we want to have a message we want to basically like a bootstrap alert
message that says success you're now registered and you can log in.
You can make it so that when you register you log in automatically but I don't really like to do that.
I like to just let them register and then have them log in afterwards.
But it's up to you how you want to do that.
All right.
And I'll show you how to do both.
So I will see you in the next video.