All right guys so I apologize in the last video when I put in the form I didn't have the first name
and last name fields you guys should have that in your version of the template.
I just forgot to update mine with them.
But we do want them.
So I wanted to do the registration.
But before we do that I want to configure messaging.
OK are messages alerts.
Basically like if we get something wrong here like the password doesn't match I want to have a nice
bootstrap formatted message that tells us that.
So there's a few things we need to do in order to make that work now now Gengel comes with a messages
app.
OK.
So in the installed apps there's actually Django doc contrabass messages and we need to just configure.
We don't need to do this.
What we do need to add is message tags right here into our settings file.
All right so I'm actually going to copy this in and let's go to our settings file so we want to go to
be Tiare and then setting's up PI.
I'm going to go down to the bottom down to the very bottom and let's say messages and I'll paste that
in.
OK so basically we're saying from Gengel dot com trip Doug messages import Constans as messages.
OK.
And then for message tags we're going to get rid of this.
I don't care about that.
What I do want to do is we have certain classes for bootstrap for different light colors like danger
is for red right.
So I'm going to actually change messages and change info to error and I'm going to set that to danger
like that.
OK and you'll see why.
We're actually going to create a separate partial for messages or alerts I'm actually going to call
it alerts.
But yeah there's a whole messaging system and you can see up here and installed apps that messages is
one of the default apps that are included with Django.
So just go ahead and add this to your settings and save it.
All right.
Now once we do that we want to then create a partial.
OK so inside templates Parshall's let's create a file and call it messages.
I'm going to call it underscore alert or alerts dot HMO and we just want we want to add the bootstrap
markup so that it looks nice but of course if you weren't using bootstrap or you were using a different
framework or custom styling you can style it however you want.
But basically we first want to just test to see if there's a message.
So we want to say if messages
can't because we don't want like we don't want the mark up or anything showing if there's no messages
it's doing and def and then we want to loop through the messages if there are any.
So we'll say for message in messages
and for.
All right.
So this is where I'm going to put some mark up.
So when I actually put a div with the idea of message and a class of container.
OK.
And then we want to put out our bootstrap markup.
So with bootstrap we have a class of alert and then we usually have a class of like alert dash danger
or something like that.
Now remember in the settings I said error equals errors danger.
I'm actually going to replace this this word danger with messages.
Our message dog tags.
OK.
And then I want to make this Divx dismissable.
So in this class I'm also going to say Alert dash dismissable meaning that I can just close it.
OK so it'll have an X and then I also want to text dash center and then I'm just going to put a roll
attribute as well.
This is just standard bootstrap syntax for an alert.
And then inside this div if it's a dismissable alert we need a button.
So I'm going to say Button give it a class of close.
OK we also want to give it the type of button
right.
So class of close it also needs an attribute of data Dasch dismiss which is just straight bootstrap
and that's going to be alert.
So data dismiss alerts.
Let's see we also want to put the Xmarks who we're gonna use the entity of Ampere's stamp.
Let's do yeah ampersand times semi-colon now.
Give it a little x and x.
That's right I think we need to wrap that in a span this is just like if you go to the bootstrap Web
site and you go to components and then alerts.
This is what you're going to see.
Actually want to add the aria dash hidden attribute like that and it should be true.
All right so that's the dismiss button underneath that I'm going to put in some strong tags and inside
here I'm going to check to see if if the message is in error.
So we can say if
message DOT level comes level is equal to default underscore message underscore levels dot error OK
and then we want to do an else
and let's do our.
And if
so if that's true then I just want to put the word error
right.
If not let's see soon that.
We want to put in our double curly braces and we want to see a message dot tags and then put a pipe
character and title.
OK.
And then right under that.
And if I'm sorry under that strong we want to put the actual message which is going to be a message.
OK.
So this snippet here you can use this in all of your ad if you're using bootstrap in all of your bootstrap
Django applications you can use this partial and use it as your error output or you or your message
outputs will save this and to test it.
Let's actually just tested by outputting it when we when we when we make the poster request when we
submit the form.
OK so to do that I'm going to let's do a redirect.
See you return redirect
to and say Index OK and then we have to we have to help with the partial wherever we want errors to
be to be able to go.
Let's actually redirect to register K to the same page.
Right above it if we want to output a message we do message Daut error if we want it to be an error
or pass in their request and then whatever the error is let's just say testing error message.
All right now to be able to use messages we need to bring an end so up here we're going to say from
Django dot contrib we want to import
messages.
All right.
So let's see.
Undefined variable message.
It's because it should be messages on error right now.
This is this is it's not going to show up because our partial isn't inserted into the register template.
OK so that's why we're redirecting to.
So what you want to do is open up the register HVM owl which is accounts register each team now.
And I need to figure out where to put this.
So I'm going to actually put it right below the card body so we can say alerts so any alerts that are
output we want to include and we want to include Parshall's slash underscore alerts H.T..
All right so let's save that.
Let's also put it in the log in.
So I'm going to just copy this go to the log in each team mail and go right below the card body same
place and put that in there as well.
All right.
Now let's test it out.
So if we submit this form we should see that test error no matter what.
So let's just put whatever
there we go.
Error testing error testing error message.
OK.
Let's actually put a colon right here.
So basically that if statement was just going to put this out if it's an error and we can dismiss this
as well.
So let's go back in and go back to our partial.
And I'm just going to put a coat on right here and it's up to you if you don't want to put the word
error.
That's fine.
That's that's all US is doing.
Yes.
We'll go ahead and save that.
Now one more thing I want to show you is if you want the error to disappear on its own we could add
a little bit a custom javascript so if we go to our beat every folder and go to static J.S. main dot
ass and put some words just use a little bit of J.A.G. to do a fade out.
So I'm going to say set time which isn't Jay Corey it's just a javascript function to just kind of hold
off on doing something or hold off and then do something.
So it takes in a function Guice will say function.
And what we want to happen is we want to use J.A.G. to grab the element with the idea of message and
we want to just do a fade out.
So Dot fade out and we'll just put in this takes in the speed or just too slow.
And then the second parameter for set time is the time so we'll say 3000.
So basically after three seconds of the message showing it should fade out.
All right.
Now since we put this in a static folder in Beati sorry we need to run create static so that it goes
into the main static folder.
So down here in the terminal Let's go ahead and do Python managed it.
PI create static.
I'm sorry collect static create static
collect static overwrite let's say.
Yes.
OK.
So let's go ahead and try it now I'm going to reload this and just put a bunch of junk in here.
Register.
OK we're going to wait three seconds.
And nothing.
All right.
Let's check out the console there's nothing there.
Let's see.
Let's look at mean chess
it's not there you know what I think we might have to restart the server.
So what I'm going to do is go to my other terminal here and just restart.
All right.
So let's try that again.
OK let's run it
now.
Still didn't work.
What the heck is it not there when we run collect static what it's supposed to do is put it in here.
So if we look in Manges here it is there it could be cash cashed
let me just clear.
I'm going to clear the cash with command shift.
Or you could do shift F5 on Windows.
Let's try that.
So hopefully this works.
There we go.
All right.
So it was cash that's why that didn't work.
So if you want to do that you can if not just remove that line of Javascript.
But I like it to go away on its own.
So now that we have the messaging figured out and I know that that was kind of like a sidebar.
Now we can continue to do the register because now when we get when the passwords don't match for instance
all we have to do is we can close up close up all we have to do is inside our view is just call message
dot error and redirect to register and it will show the error.
So in the next video we're going to cover the whole user registration.
All right so I'll see you then.