All right guys so in this video we're going to start to work on our registration.
We need to do a little bit of validation for our form and then we're going to register a user.
Right now we're checking to see if it's a POST request if it is in the last video we just tested out
the messaging.
So I'm going to get rid of these two lines and we're going to want to put everything into variables.
OK so every every form field that's submitted we want to put into variables so let's say get form values.
So we're going to create a first name and the way that we get these values is by using request.
But instead of using get like we did with the the you are l queries and the GET requests we want to
use post since it's a post for and then we just want to put whatever the input name is in this case
this first name and we want six of these so two three four five six.
And we're going to change this one to last name
K then we're going to do a user name
then we're going to do email
OK we also want password
password and we want the password to
OK.
So now that we have those we want to start to do some validation lets say check if passwords match.
So we simply say if wups.
No no parentheses.
Password is equal to password 2.
Then we want to actually let's do our else first so else.
So if there is no or if the passwords don't match then what do we want to do we want to show an error
or I just like just like I did before.
So we're going to say message is you know WANT THAT THERE.
When do message or messages I'm sorry dot error takes in request and then takes in whatever we want
to output as a message which is going to be passwords do not match.
OK.
And then after that we're going to redirect.
So we want to return redirect and we're going to redirect to the same page or just register.
OK.
So let's actually just try that so far make sure that the validation works.
Let's just put a return in here for now just to shut the error up.
OK so we'll go back to our registry and reload and doesn't matter what we put in here.
This can be anything.
Password.
Now I'm going to make this not match so I'll do like 1 1 1 2 2 to register.
There we go passwords do not match.
And after three seconds that disappears that's exactly what I want to happen.
All right.
So let's go back now.
They do match.
We want to move on but we have some more validation to do we don't want to have duplicate user names
or duplicate emails so that's those are some things we're going to have to add here.
So let's say check user name and to do that we need to actually bring in the user model.
OK so we didn't create the user model but it comes default with Django.
But we still need to bring it in to use it.
So a peer will say from outside it's going to be from Django dot contrib dot off dot models and then
we want to import uppercase U user and then we can use that model just like we could use any model just
like we did with the listing in the realtor and so on.
So for the check username we're going to do it if we're going to say user dot objects remember objects
fetches from the database.
We want to put a filter case we want to do filter and we want to filter by user name equals username.
OK we're checking the user name field in the database for this value which is this this variable up
here and then we simply want to tack on Dot exists.
Ok so it's just a helpful method that will let us know if that user name exists.
So we'll put a colon colon here and if that's true then we want to show an error because that means
there is already a user with that username right.
So we don't we don't want them to be able to register so we're going to send an error say request and
the error will say that user name is taken.
And then again we're going to return a redirect to the register.
So this needs an else.
So if there is no user name that means we want to continue but we want to check for that e-mail because
we want that to be unique.
So it's going to be virtually the same thing.
So I'm going to just copy this right here this whole if else and we want to make sure we're and we're
indented here inside this else piece that in case this should be like that.
And we're just going to say if user data object start filter by e-mail.
So e-mail equals e-mail exists.
Then we're going to say that e-mail that e-mail is is being used and we're going to redirect.
OK else then we'll just say looks good.
OK so everything is passed.
So I'm going to say this I just want to test those things.
Now as far as users we have one user in the database I believe it's what's what's the user name.
Brad I believe I mean we can check when we can check in the back end here for go back home.
Will I not have my server running.
Oops.
You just check something real quick it's probably because there's nothing here so let me just do.
Let me just put a return here and save and make sure my server is still running.
It's in the other terminal.
OK good that fixed it.
All right.
So I will go back and reload.
OK so users.
And you can see we have a username of Brad in an e-mail address of Brad at gmail so I should not be
able to register with either of those.
All right so let's try that.
Let's start with.
It doesn't matter what we put in here or here.
I just want to try that Brad user name.
OK.
E-mail.
I'm not going to it doesn't matter.
Password.
Now this has to match.
We'll get an error so let's do just one one one one on one.
It's register.
There you go.
That user name is taken.
Perfect.
So let's try the e-mail now.
So remember that e-mail is Bradd at gmail dot com.
I'm sorry that you go in here username we'll just say whatever password
that e-mail is being used.
All right so all the validation is working now we want to continue to actually register the user.
So to do that and get rid of this return let's create a variable called the user.
And we're going to send it to a user Daut objects and there's a method called create user guys who want
to do that and we want to pass in all the fields so a user name equals user name we want to do password
equals password email equals email first name he called his first name last name.
He calls last name is that it.
I think that's it.
Username password email.
Yeah that should be it.
So I I just want to show you two ways of doing it.
Now if you want to log the user and once they're registered will say law you log in after register what
you could do is you could say off Daut log in and you could pass in the request and the user that we
just created here.
Now if you want to use this off object right here you actually have to bring it in and it's part of
Gengel called Treb.
So we can just add it right here and that should work but I'm not I'm actually not going to do that.
If you do do that what I would do is put a message underneath.
So I'd say messages dot success OK because you don't want to be in error.
We want it to be a success message and say request
and we'll say you are now logged in.
OK.
And then just return redirect
to slash or index you could do index.
OK so that would do that.
I'm not.
I'm not going to do that but I'm going to comment it out just in case you guys want what I want to do
is register the user and then give them a message and redirect them to the logon page so that they can
manually log in after they register.
So to do that we take the user and we just call save.
OK so we say use your dot save let's do a success.
I'll just grab this and let's say you are now logged in or you are now registered
and can log in.
Whoops I put a semi-colon.
I mean like javascript mode today.
And then we're going to return a redirect and we do want to redirect to the logon page.
OK so hopefully hopefully this works.
Let's try it out.
So I'm going to reload the register page and I'm actually going to try and register so let's say it
was say Kathy last name Smith username which is to Cathy g mail and let's match these passwords.
It's going to do one through six and register.
OK success you are registered and can log in.
Awesome.
So if we go to our admin area into the user section if I reload there was Kathy OK and if you look at
Staff Status there's an app excuse me there's an X mark because she's just a regular front end user.
OK.
And notice the password is hashed automatically so you don't have to worry about any of that.
You don't have to worry about hashing your passwords It just happens automatically.
So awesome we can now register for we can now register on the front end.
So what I want to do next is handle the log in.
But before I do that I just want to add in a couple of play.
Actually I think only the home page.
I want to add the ability to have messages or alerts because you know how I put if you wanted to log
in after you register it puts out a message and then redirects you to the index.
But the index page doesn't have the alerts.
I don't believe the alerts partial included.
So let's go down to templates and then go to see where we go and pages indexed on each team.
And we want to put the alerts somewhere in here.
So let's see I think
a good place to put this.
Let's go under the whole Showcase area.
And I actually don't know where to put this.
I mean I guess
let's just take a look at the front end here.
We could put it right above the latest listings like right here know let's do that sort of latest listings
I believe the alerts if we look at the partial history here we have Dave idea message it has a class
of containers so it will be it'll be put in the middle so that should be fine.
So for that
I'll put it right here.
So let's do our include
Parshall's slash underscore alerts studies.
OK so just in case you redirect to the home page and you want to and you want to show a message you
want to show an alert.
All right guys.
In the next video we're going to make it so that we can take the use of that we just created and we
can log in with that user.
OK so we're going to do authentication then we're going to work on the nav bar because obviously this
should be different if we're logged in.
We should also have a way to log out.
So we need to work on all that stuff.
So I will see you in the next video.