All right in the last video we took care of the registrations so we were able to go to register fill
out the form we have some validation going on.
And once we pass it it registers the user as you can see we registered a user called Kathy.
Now we want to be able to log in with that account.
So let's go to vs code and inside our views up PI that's in the accounts folder we're going to go down
to the log and method.
OK so that's the method that we want to use here.
So we are already checking to make sure that it's a post request meaning the form is submitted.
We're going to get rid of this return here and replace it.
And we want to get the variables just like we did above except there's only two that we want and that's
the user name and password that comes in from the form so let's say request dot post and we want the
user name.
OK we also want the password
OK.
So we have those two now to be able to log in or authenticate.
We want to create a variable called user I'm going to set it to off which I already brought in in the
last video could be coming from Django Contra.
And then there's an authenticate method case we want to see authenticate.
We want to do username equals the username variable it's above which is whatever is submitted in the
form and then password which is equal to the password that's submitted in the form.
OK then we want to I just do want to be in here.
We want to check to see if user is not None.
OK.
So if user is not None.
That means that we want to off does that means that the users found OK so that means it's found in the
database by this username and password.
So these are matched in the database.
Then we want to log in.
So we say Auth. dot log in and this takes in the requests and it also takes in the user OK.
So that's that's pretty much it to log in.
So we're going to do a message a success message so let's say message dot success and we'll say request
request and we'll say you are now logged in and then we'll redirect.
So it's do a return redirect.
Now we're going to redirect to the dashboard and I know that we haven't I don't think we created that
template yet or we'd like or we didn't.
It's just like an H1 but that's ultimately what we're going to want to do.
So I'm just going to put that will probably work on that next.
But we want to do an else here.
So if the user is not found then what do we want.
Do we want to output an error.
So will say messages this actually should be messages not just message so messages dot our past in our
request and then the error that we want to give is invalid credentials.
OK.
And then we're going to redirect.
So we want to return redirect and let's redirect to log in.
All right so we'll save that and sorry load
just refresh and then I'll just put in whatever say Invalid credentials.
Good.
So let's try to log in as Cathy.
So if I say Cathy put in or correct password and log in we get redirected to the dashboard.
And this is the front and this is the front end dashboard This has nothing to do with the admin.
Now if I go back to my admin and I reload we're going to be logged out because remember these are these
users are all on the same table.
So if you're logged in as Kathy then we're logged in as Cathy there's no being logged in as Brad in
the in the admin area.
And Cathy doesn't have access to the admin area so we're gonna be booted out.
So just know that that's how our our workflow is going to kind of go from now on.
But yeah so we're logged in now.
So we need a way to log out.
We also need to create the dashboard.
OK we don't even have a nav bar to add a out.
So I think in the next video what we'll do is is add the markup for the dashboard and then we can work
on the go right so we'll see in the next video.