All right to the last video we completed the log in the authentication we were able to log in successfully
we were redirected to the dashboard but the dashboard is nothing more than an H-1 in the template.
So we need to.
We need to fix that.
So let's go back to.
I'm going to go to my Sublime Text because that's where I actually have my bootstrap theme and I'm going
to go to dashboard aged Yamal.
We want to go below all the nav bar stuff.
So right here to the section and we're going to go all the way down to right above the footer.
OK dashboards not that big of a page.
And then let's go back to vs code and go to templates accounts dashboard aged hemol.
OK we're going to want to paste to sin.
But of course we need to extend our base template.
So let's do
extends base died aged him now and we need to wrap this all in a Coke and a code block
so block content.
I should say a content block code block use me we need to end that down here.
OK so let's save that.
And if we now look at the dashboard we reload.
Now this is all just static data.
Obviously we've done nothing to do with contacts yet or inquiries we haven't even created the application
yet.
So this is all static.
But we do have the nav bar showing OK and that's what I want to focus on because I mean we're logged
in and we don't want register and log in to show we want this to be different.
So let's go back to the dashboard and I just want to change one thing here before we get into that.
And that's the breadcrumb we don't want this to go to index aged him now.
We want to put in our tags and we want you Arel and we want to go index.
OK so now what I want to do is head on over to our NAV bar partials so templates Parshall's underscore
now Barcott HD IMAO.
And I want to go right inside of the UL right here with the nav bar nav and Eldo right above this ally
and I'm going to put a conditional I'm going to say if user Daut is underscore authenticated OK so basically
if the user is logged in and then we're going to do in else.
OK.
And I want everything that's here which is the the register in the log in Ally tags to be within the
rules.
OK so I'm just going to go down to the last.
This ending ally and just tab that over and then right underneath it I'm going to tab back and I'm going
to put the end if here.
And just to test this so let's just say whatever.
Hello.
Just to see if this works.
I want to save and let's go back and reload
and you can see how low and the reason you can't really see it until I highlighted it is just because
it's not a link and just it's just the way the CSSA is but we know that that conditional is working.
All right so now we want to do is construct a log log out to link.
We actually want to log outlaying and dashboard link.
But the trick here is the logo.
It can't just be like an 8 in a tag with an 8 traffic can't be a link it can't be just a standard get
request it has to be a post.
So what we'll do is we'll create a form that will be that will look like a link.
OK hopefully that makes sense because the form is what we use to make a post request.
We could use javascript and make a you know use the fetch API or Ajax or something like that but I'm
just going to construct a simple form to log out.
But let's first put the dashboard to link so let's see how we want to do this let's grab
Let's actually grab one of these allies right here.
So this whole register ally.
And I'm going to paste that in here.
And let's see if
dashboard in request path we're going to have this stuff.
And then down here let's change this to dashboard
and the URL is going to go to dashboard
OK.
Let me just let's see we don't want an icon here right.
So we'll just get rid of this tag and I'm just going to save this and just see if this shows up correctly
and works so there we go dashboard good if click on that.
All right so now we have a way to get to our dashboard.
Now in addition to just dashboard I want to say like how welcome and then whatever the username.
So remember we have access to this user object within the within the template.
OK so within all templates.
So I'm actually going to say welcome.
I'll say welcome notes to our double curly braces and will say user and we can access any field of the
user and I'm going to access user name and then I'm just going to put dashboard in parentheses like
that.
So now if I say can we go back and reload says Welcome Caffey and dashboard just to let you know that
if you click on it it will take you to the dashboard and I spelt dashboard wrong.
If you don't want to have the dashboard there and just say welcome or you don't even want the welcome
that's fine whatever you want to do is that's your preference but let me just fix this.
I always I type like too fast when I write dashboard I always put the a before the show.
So hello we have that let's take care of the logo.
So right underneath.
Let's see I'm trying to figure out where where this is going to go.
We have our Atallah have ending ally.
So let's put another
yeah let's put it another ally
and let's give it class.
We don't need the active so we don't need to do the if statement so to say now have item and let's do
Marjan right.
Three OK so we're going to do that.
And then let's put in a tag with the class of NAV dash Lanc and you'll see what I'm doing in a minute
here.
I'm actually going to put in here javascript and then some curly braces and what this will allows us
to do is actually write some javascript in here.
So I'm going to say document get element by id and the ID is going to be logo.
And then I just want to call Daut submit.
OK that's all I want there.
Now let's wait a minute.
Yeah.
So we have the the Tref we have the class of NAV link.
So inside here inside the tag I'm going to put an icon like a log out icons so we're going to do F.A.
ass and let's do a dash sign dash out dash Alt.
That will give us a little logo link and then I'm going to say logo right next to it like that.
All right.
Now when we click this it's going to run this little piece of javascript.
It's going to look for the idea of log out and it's going to submit the form.
So we want to create that form.
So we're going to put that right on right underneath this a tag.
So we'll see a form with an ID of Logo at OK.
Now the action is going to go to the URL of Logo.
OK remember we have that route.
So the action will go to log out we want to make sure that we add a method of post here.
We have post request.
And let's see inside the form.
We're not going to do much we do want to put our CSR token just like we did with the other post form
so which one of you see as are half underscore token and then we're just going to put an input with
the type of hidden
OK just like that.
So all this is all this should do is make a post request to log out.
So let's save this and then let's go back to the used up high inside accounts and you can see we have
our logo here and we want to check to see if it's a post request just like we did up here with like
the log in in the Register saying to copy that line and let's put that here.
So we're going to say if there's a post request we want a logo.
So off dot log it's as simple as that.
We just want to pass in the request that should Laaga.
So we want to send the message a success message.
Pass the request and the message will just say you are now logged out and let's redirect to index just
want to Tab this over and over and that should do it.
If we did it right so let's save it and let's see if things work out.
So a reload and easy now we have a logo link if I click that message is not defined so it should be
messages but we still should have logged out because it should have ran this.
They happened here.
So if we go back we should be logged out.
When I reload OK so up here now notice it says register and log in again and we got that little message
here.
It was like stuck to the top.
So I think what I'm going to do
I mean there might be a better place to put that in the index.
That the Parshall's alerts.
I mean we could do like we could put some CSSA we could do a line break or something like that.
What if we did that.
I mean that pushes it down a little but I think that's right.
So let's try again let's log in.
So I'd say Cathy
K. so we're logged in and we went to the dashboard.
Now if you want a message to say like you're now logged in which I think if we look at views up high
we look at our log in.
Yeah you get that message.
But the dashboard doesn't have the alerts partially.
So we have to put that in there.
So it's called a dashboard and let's figure out where we want to put this.
Let's put it right right below the breadcrumb
so alerts
clewed
Parshall's alerts on he urged him now.
All right so now when we log in it'll show right here welcome.
I mean it'll say you're now logged in.
OK.
And we can navigate around that log out.
And now success you're logged out and register and log in links are back in OK and the success matches
disappears after three seconds because of that piece of javascript that we put in.
All right.
So that's going to be it for this video guys.
Before we jump into contacts or inquiries in the next video I just want to do something that is very
simple but I think is necessary and that is to add to be able to change the titles up here for each
page because right now all the different pages OK whether it's a page or a listing they they all have
just beat real estate.
So I want to give you the option to change this.
And I think it's really important for listing pages.
I want to actually have the title of the listing in up here because if this comes up in a Google search
result then we want that in the title we don't want just BT real estate for everything.
All right.
So in the next video I'll show you how we can do that and then we'll move on to adding our contact model
or our contacts app with the model and database database table and we'll work on making inquiries or
making contacts.
When I say contacts and inquiries.
I mean the same thing I'm saying and I'm using them synonymously.
All right so that's it.
I will see you in the next video.