All right guys so before we move on here I just want to be able to have custom titles for each page
and this is something I could have done early on but I wanted to get all of our templates all set before
I did that.
OK and now I think we have every single template every page every HTL page is now incorporated into
our application.
So I think that it's a good time to implement that and it's very easy.
All we have to do is disclose all this stuff up.
All we have to do is go into our base each team out and we just simply need to add another block and
we're going to put that up in the title.
Now I do want and it's up to you how you want to do this but I do want to have Beati real estate in
every page title but then have the rest of the title after it.
So like a subtitle.
All right.
And you can do this how you want.
Usually you have like a pipe character or a hyphen or something like that.
You could put the hyphen in the template like this.
But then again if you if you forget or you don't have a custom title on a page it's just going to look
like this with nothing after it.
Or you can choose to put the hyphen or the pipe character within the template OK and I'll show you what
I mean.
So I'm just going to leave it.
I'm going to put the character inside the template just in case we don't have a title to a page but
we just want to add a block here.
So we're going to say block and I'm going to call this title and we want to of course and the block.
So it's a hand block save that and then let's go let's start off with our home page will go to pages
and then index each team out.
And for the title here I mean you guys can you can do whatever you want.
I'm just going to put the word home or welcome.
And where we want to put this is I'm going to put it right after we load the load humanize.
So read here so we want to say block title and let's just do welcome.
And what I was talking about is we would put pipe like that
in then and block.
All right.
So let's see that see if it works.
So go to the home page and reload and now we get Beati real estate with pite character and welcome.
So it's up to you where you want to put the character.
So let's add some other ones I'm just going to go ahead and copy this because as you can see now if
we went to about life we forgot to put a title over we didn't want to put a title it still just is BT
real estate.
If we did it the other way we would have just a pipe character which looks kind of silly.
So I mean I don't know it's up to you on how you want to do it.
So for a boat to go up here we're going to go right under load static.
I always want to put the title like right above the content and we'll just say about BT hiree or let's
say just you about us.
OK I'll save that.
Let's go to see what other pages we have here.
Let's go to listings and we'll go to listings for each team.
And let's say Well say Brough's or browse property listings
K. let's go to search dot each team I'll go right here and we'll say search results
save that.
Now let's go to listing each team and this is really important because I actually want to put the title
of the listing in the in the page title.
So it's actually going to be dynamic.
I'm going to grab this right here listing title and put that in here.
That way it shows the title so let's save and we'll check that out in a minute.
But let's finish here so let's go to register accounts.
Slash register.
Whoops.
Me and I get a copy of that again.
Right.
So register
count go to log in accounts log in
log in account log in
and then we just have our dashboard
and let's just say dashboard
hopes
say user dashboard.
OK.
I think that's all of our templates.
I think that's all of our age html files.
So let's go in and check them out.
Now on the front end web site.
So this is the about going to reload.
And we get about us feature listings we get browse properties register register account account log
in we go to see let's go to a single listing and notice that in the title now we can see 33 six circles
so we have the actual listing.
You could also put like the city and state whatever whatever you want it's absolutely fine whatever
you want to put.
If we log in and go to the dashboard
we get use or dashboard.
All right so all of our titles are good.
So now we're going to do in the next section is we're going to start to work with contacts OK or inquiries.
Basically we want to be able to submit this form right here.
OK so this should get submitted to a view method and it should.
This stuff should get added to the database.
And we're also going to make it so that if you're logged in then your name in your e-mail is automatically
put in the form.
Also it should get put in the database your user ID should get put in the in the in the row as well.
All right.
That way we can track logged in users inquiries and we can put that in their dashboards.
OK so we're going to get into that in the next section.